<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet href="http://www.newsx.com/components/com_obrss/assets/xsl/atom-to-html.xsl" type="text/xsl"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
	<channel>
		<title>rss</title>
		<description><![CDATA[RSS Feed]]></description>
		<link>http://www.newsx.com/</link>
		<lastBuildDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2014 12:13:53 -0600</lastBuildDate>
		<generator>FeedCreator 1.8.3 (obRSS 1.9)</generator>
		<atom:link href="http://www.newsx.com/component/obrss/rss?format=" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
		<image>
			<url>http://www.newsx.com/images/</url>
			<title>rss</title>
			<link>http://www.newsx.com/</link>
			<description>RSS Feed</description>
		</image>
		<item>
			<title>BJP neither disappointed nor dejected: Kalraj Mishra on By-election results</title>
			<link>http://www.newsx.com/national/nation/item/26828-bjp-neither-disappointed-nor-dejected-kalraj-mishra-on-by-election-results</link>
			<description><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/bb2a2efe286eaf70d7a2d97252fa3648_Generic.jpg"><img align="right" border="0" src="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/bb2a2efe286eaf70d7a2d97252fa3648_S.jpg" alt="bjp-neither-disappointed-nor-dejected-kalraj-mishra-on-by-election-results" /></a><font color="#ff3300"><b>Featured</b></font><p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Lucknow: Union Minister for Medium, Small and Micro Enterprises (MSME) Kalraj Mishra Thursday said though the by-election results were not as per BJP's expectation, the party was "neither disappointed nor dejected".</span></p>

<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"The results of by-elections were not as per our expectations, but it is wrong to say that the party is disappointed or dejected. This time we have lost, but will win in future," Mishra told reporters here.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">He said there had been something or the other shortcomings that the party's defeat. A three-member campaign committee was constituted by the party for by-elections, of which Kalraj, MP Adityanath and state president Laxmi Kant Bajpai were star campaigners.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Of the 11 Assembly seats for which by-polls were held in Uttar Pradesh, BJP won only three seats. The party had won all the 11 seats in last assembly elections.</span></p>]]></description>
			<dc:creator>Edited by Kirti Dwivedi | Updated: 5:05 IST</dc:creator>
			<pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2014 11:50:52 -0600</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.newsx.com/national/nation/item/26828-bjp-neither-disappointed-nor-dejected-kalraj-mishra-on-by-election-results</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Japan, China want land to be reserved for them, Medha Patkar says</title>
			<link>http://www.newsx.com/national/nation/item/26827-japan-china-want-land-to-be-reserved-for-them-medha-patkar-says</link>
			<description><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/6ebe405db2dee87605885438003dc7f5_Generic.jpg"><img align="right" border="0" src="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/6ebe405db2dee87605885438003dc7f5_S.jpg" alt="japan-china-want-land-to-be-reserved-for-them-medha-patkar-says" /></a><font color="#ff3300"><b>Featured</b></font><p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Jaipur: Activist Medha Patkar on Thursday alleged that leaders and officials from Japan and China were visiting India as they want land to be reserved for them in the country.</span></p>

<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"Why Japanese officials and Chinese President are visiting India? Only because, they want the land in the country to be reserved for them. That is what Modi government is doing," she told reporters during a protest march by activists against the Rajasthan Land Acquisition Bill, 2014.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">She claimed that the Bill, which was introduced in the Assembly by the Vasundhara Raje-led BJP government yesterday and taken up for discussion today, would lead to "hurried, hasty and undemocratic grabbing of land" and the situation would be worst than that of British era.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Patkar alleged that it was against the interests of farmers, labourers, urban poor and common people and it would bypass the central act that was passed last year.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">She urged former Chief Minister and Opposition leader Ashok Gehlot to oppose the Bill.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">PUCL general secretary Kavita Srivastava, who was also protesting against the Bill, termed introduction of Bill as a move of the state government to undermine democratic and Constitutional principles and traditions.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">She said the bill has provisions which will make the law draconian.</span></p>]]></description>
			<dc:creator>Edited by Kirti Dwivedi | Updated: 4:15 IST</dc:creator>
			<pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2014 11:42:59 -0600</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.newsx.com/national/nation/item/26827-japan-china-want-land-to-be-reserved-for-them-medha-patkar-says</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Actor-politician Hema Malini defends her remarks on widows in Vrindavan</title>
			<link>http://www.newsx.com/national/nation/item/26826-actor-politician-hema-malini-defends-her-remarks-on-widows-in-vrindavan</link>
			<description><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/2970ff71131f4a43006f14f2424000b7_Generic.jpg"><img align="right" border="0" src="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/2970ff71131f4a43006f14f2424000b7_S.jpg" alt="actor-politician-hema-malini-defends-her-remarks-on-widows-in-vrindavan" /></a><font color="#ff3300"><b>Featured</b></font><p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Mumbai: Actor-politician Hema Malini Thursday sought to defend her remarks that widows from West Bengal and Bihar should not crowd Vrindavan in Uttar Pradesh, saying she said this in the context of how they were being ignored in their home states and government not doing enough for them.</span></p>

<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The 65-year-old BJP Lok Sabha MP also said she had not mentioned anything that she should be "ashamed of".</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Hema Malini, during a visit to her parliamentary constituency Mathura, had stoked a potential controversy when she said that Vrindavan, a holy town which is home to thousands of destitute women, should not be crowded by widows from other states like West Bengal and Bihar.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">She had said that there are already 40,000 widows in Vrindavan, which is part of her constituency, and there was no room to accommodate more.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The actress today defended her previous statement in a series of tweets, saying no one listened to her "actual interview" to the media.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"I haven't said anything that I should be ashamed of. I stand by my statement that they should be allowed to live with dignity. Sad state for a country once known for the respect shown to women. This is what I was trying to point out," she tweeted.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"It is traumatic to see these poor widows begging on the streets even for their daily existence. Have all of you ever witnessed their plight? Of course I intend doing what I can to improve their condition but Vrindavan has a space limitation too. State government too should contribute," she added.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The actress said she had done nothing wrong by saying that "sons &amp; daughters cannot discard their duty &amp; cannot bundle them onto a train &amp; forget about them".</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"For no fault of theirs, they are thrown on the streets &amp; are compelled to beg to survive. Is this fair? Do you think these old women deserve this fate? Also most are from West Bengal, Bihar &amp; Orissa. My request was to these people to have a more humane approach &amp; look after these poor widows properly.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">She said that awareness should be created in states from where the widows belonged to.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Pointing out that most of these women were "abandoned by family and put on trains to Vrindavan without any moneny", Hema Malini said most of them find jobs as maids or turn to begging.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"Younger ones are also exploited &amp; then abandoned to their fate. Out of the 5000, only 1500 have a proper roof over their heads. The rest are on the streets, destitute &amp; desperate. Of course, we are all Indians first, &amp; have a duty towards the old &amp; infirm in our country."</span></p>]]></description>
			<dc:creator>Edited by Kirti Dwivedi | Updated: 4:15 IST</dc:creator>
			<pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2014 11:32:48 -0600</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.newsx.com/national/nation/item/26826-actor-politician-hema-malini-defends-her-remarks-on-widows-in-vrindavan</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>CM Omar Abdullah appeals for donations to CM flood relief fund</title>
			<link>http://www.newsx.com/regional/j-k/item/26825-cm-omar-abdullah-appeals-for-donations-to-cm-flood-relief-fund</link>
			<description><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/dea979afca05978001c6e2b30a19e769_Generic.jpg"><img align="right" border="0" src="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/dea979afca05978001c6e2b30a19e769_S.jpg" alt="cm-omar-abdullah-appeals-for-donations-to-cm-flood-relief-fund" /></a><font color="#ff3300"><b>Featured</b></font><p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Srinagar/Jammu: Jammu and Kashmir Chief Minister Omar Abdullah Thursday urged all, especially MPs, legislators and employees of the state to donate as much as they can for those affected by the floods to the J&amp;K Chief Minister's Flood Relief Fund.</span></p>

<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">At a high level meeting here to review the latest situation, Omar expressed gratitude to Governor N N Vohra for donating his one month's salary in the Fund and urged all to donate as much as they can.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Omar also announced Rs 1 lakh donation out of his salary to the Flood Relief Fund.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">He said MPs and legislators can also earmark funds out of their MPLAD funds and CDF for the restoration of flood hit infrastructure and other works.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The Chief Minister in his appeal to government employees, business community and well-off people, asked them to donate wholeheartedly into the account: J&amp;K Chief Minister's Flood Relief Fund Account No. 0110040100001275 (IFSC - JAKAO) of Jammu and Kashmir Bank Limited.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">At the meeting, the Chief Minister was apprised about the status of supply of essential commodities including ration, functioning of health institutions, supply of medicines, removal of garbage from roads and streets.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">He laid thrust on intensifying dewatering of submerged areas in Srinagar city. He also approved procurement of high density and heavy discharging dewatering pumps for the purpose. Each pump of this make is capable of dewatering 18,000 to 20,000 liters of water per minute.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The meeting was attended by members of Council of Ministers, Chief Secretary, Director General of Police, Principal Secretaries, Commissioner Secretaries and various Administrative Secretaries and senior officers.</span></p>]]></description>
			<dc:creator>Edited by Kirti Dwivedi | Updated: 3:45 IST</dc:creator>
			<pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2014 11:18:13 -0600</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.newsx.com/regional/j-k/item/26825-cm-omar-abdullah-appeals-for-donations-to-cm-flood-relief-fund</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>India and China need to resolve border issue soon</title>
			<link>http://www.newsx.com/national/nation/item/26824-india-and-china-need-to-resolve-border-issue-soon</link>
			<description><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/d7caaea57b3eba1f634f1eade6e94f61_Generic.jpg"><img align="right" border="0" src="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/d7caaea57b3eba1f634f1eade6e94f61_S.jpg" alt="india-and-china-need-to-resolve-border-issue-soon" /></a><font color="#ff3300"><b>Featured</b></font><p><span style="font-size: 10pt;">NEW DELHI: Prime Minister Narendra Modi candidly said on Thursday that solving the boundary issue between India and China is needed for growing economic cooperation between two countries.</span></p>

<p><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"We need to resolve our boundary issue soon," Modi said on Thursday, addressing a joint press conference with visiting Chinese President Xi Jinping after official talks at Hyderabad House here.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"A clarification on the LAC (Line of Actual Control) is very important. It has been pending for years, it is time to start it again," he said.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The Prime Minister said he raised the issue of Chinese incursions in the border with India.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 10pt;"><img style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;" src="http://www.newsx.com/images/Auto/National/Xi_Modi_Mou.jpg" alt="Xi Modi Mou" width="630" height="352" /></span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"The incidents that took place at the border, I expressed my concern over them. Peace and stability at the border is the foundation of economic possibilities," he said.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Modi said mutual trust and respect for each other's sensitivities and concerns, and peace and stability in our relations and along our borders are essential.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"If there is peace and stability, friendship and cooperation on the border, we can utilise the possibilities and contribute in each other's growth, and give a new direction to the world economy," he added.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Describing China as India's biggest neighbour and that it has a role in nation-building and foreign policy, Modi said he attched "importance and priority to relations with China".</span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 10pt;"><strong>China, India are capable of resolving border row: Xi</strong></span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Chinese President Xi Jinping Thursday said that both countries are capable of effectively managing the border situation.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"Both sides are capable of effectively managing the border situation and to settle the border disputes at the earliest," Xi said after holding talks with Prime Minister Narendra Modi here.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Xi said that we have the sincerity to work with India on the border issue.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 10pt;">He added that this issue should be dealt in a manner that it does not have an impact on ties.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 10pt;"><strong>China to open Nathu La route to Kailash Mansarovar</strong></span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 10pt;">China will be opening an additional route to Kailash Mansarovar via Nathu La, Prime Minister Narendra Modi said on Thursday.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"I would like to thank (Chinese president) Xi Jinping on behalf of all Indians for a new route to Kailash Mansarovar. This new route, which will be opened through Nathu La, will be in addition to the existing route via Uttarakhand," Modi said during a joint press interaction with Xi at Hyderabad House here.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Modi said this decision will help more and more Indians reach Kailash Mansarovar, in particular the old, as transportation on motorcycles would be available on the new route.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"The pilgrims will be benefitted in a big way. Besides that, this road will remain safe during the rainy season, too," Modi added.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 10pt;"><strong>China assures market access to Indian goods</strong></span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Prime Minister Narendra Modi said he has been assured of greater access to Indian goods and investments by Chinese President Xi Jinping in a bid to bridge the yawning trade deficit between the two countries.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"I raised the issue of trade imbalance between the two countries. I urged President Xi to give our companies better market access and investment opportunities in China," Modi said.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"The Chinese president assured that he will take concrete steps in this regard."</span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 10pt;">India-China bilateral merchandise trade stood at $65.88 billion in 2013. While India's exports to China was valued at $14.50 billion, its imports were much larger at $51.37 billion, resulting in a large trade deficit.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Modi, while delivering his statement before the media after the talks at Hyderabad House here, India and China have much scope to increase economic cooperation, as it was way below the potential.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The Prime Minister said he was pleased with the inking of agreements between the two sides for two Chinese industrial parks in India and Beijing's commitment to invest around $20 billion in India over the next five years.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"I invited Chinese investments in infrastructure and manufacturing sectors. I am glad that two Chinese industrial parks will be built in India."</span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 10pt;">&nbsp;<strong style="line-height: 1.5;">List of Documents signed during the State Visit of Chinese President Xi Jinping to India</strong></span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 10pt;"><iframe src="//www.youtube.com/embed/QDuvUt863lM" frameborder="0" width="684" height="415" allowfullscreen="true" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"></iframe></span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 10pt;"><strong>1)</strong> Memorandum of Understanding between the Ministry of External Affairs of the Republic of India and the Ministry of Foreign Affairs of the People's Republic of China on Opening a New Route for Indian Pilgrimage (Kailash Mansarovar Yatra) to the Tibet Autonomous Region of the People's Republic of China</span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 10pt;"><strong>2)</strong> Memorandum of Understanding between Ministry of Railways of the Government of Republic of India and the Government of People's Republic of China on strengthening cooperation in Railways</span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 10pt;"><strong>3)</strong> Action Plan between Ministry of Railways of the Government of Republic of India and the National Railway Administration of the Government of People's Republic of China on strengthening cooperation in Railways</span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 10pt;"><strong>4</strong>) Five year Trade and Economic Development Plan between Ministry of Commerce and Industry of the Government of the Republic of India and the Ministry of Commerce of the Government of the People's Republic of China</span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 10pt;"><strong>5)</strong> Agreed Minutes of the Tenth Session of India-China Joint Economic Group</span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 10pt;"><strong>6)</strong> Agreement on Audio-Visual Co-production between The Ministry of Information and Broadcasting of the Republic of India and the State Administration of Press, Publication, Radio, Film and Television of The People's Republic of China</span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 10pt;"><strong>7)</strong> Agreement between the Government of the Republic of India and the Government of the People's Republic of China On mutual administrative assistance and co-operation in Customs matters</span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 10pt;"><strong>8)</strong> Memorandum of Understanding between Indian Space Research Organisation and China National Space Administration on Cooperation in the Peaceful use of Space</span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 10pt;"><strong>9)</strong> Memorandum of Understanding between the Ministry of Culture of the Republic of India and the Ministry of Culture of the People's Republic of China on Strengthening the Exchange and Cooperation between Cultural Institutions</span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 10pt;"><strong>10)</strong> Memorandum of Understanding on Cooperation between National Book Trust of the Republic of India and the State Administration of Press, Publication, Radio, Film and Television of The People's Republic of China</span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 10pt;"><strong>11)</strong> Work Plan on Drug Administration and Cooperation Between China Food and Drug Administration of the People's Republic of China And Ministry of Health &amp; Family Welfare of the Republic of India</span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 10pt;"><strong>12)</strong> Agreement on establishing Sister City relationship between Mumbai and Shanghai</span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 10pt;"><strong>13)</strong> Agreement on establishing Sister City relationship between Ahmedabad and Guangzhou (Signed in Gujarat)</span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 10pt;"><strong>14)</strong> Agreement on establishing Sister Province/State relationship between Gujarat and Guangdong (Signed in Gujarat)</span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 10pt;"><strong>15)</strong> Memorandum of Understanding between China Development Bank Corporation and on supporting the setting up of industrial parks in Gujarat (Signed in Gujarat)</span></p>]]></description>
			<dc:creator>Edited by Kirti Dwivedi | Updated: 3:45 IST</dc:creator>
			<pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2014 10:35:14 -0600</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.newsx.com/national/nation/item/26824-india-and-china-need-to-resolve-border-issue-soon</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>India signs 15 deal with China, strengthens ties</title>
			<link>http://www.newsx.com/national/nation/item/26823-india-signs-15-deal-with-china-strengthens-ties</link>
			<description><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/9f4a7b6db36e3f31a23ef1f405bf0c89_Generic.jpg"><img align="right" border="0" src="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/9f4a7b6db36e3f31a23ef1f405bf0c89_S.jpg" alt="india-signs-15-deal-with-china-strengthens-ties" /></a><font color="#ff3300"><b>Featured</b></font><p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">New Delhi: Chinese President Xi Jinping on Thursday signed a series of documents with India at the Hyderabad House in New Delhi, strengthening ties between the two countries. This is Xi's first visit to India as head of the state.</span></p>

<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Among the 15 MoUs signed between India and China is the agreement over a new route for the Kailash Mansarovar Yatra. According to the MoU signed between the Ministry of External Affairs and the Ministry of Foreign Affairs of China, a new route will be opened for all Indian pilgrimages to the Tibet autonomous region of the People's Republic of China.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The Ministry of Railways has also signed an MoU with the government of China to take action on strengthening cooperation in the railways. According to the memorandum, an action plan will be set up between the Ministry of Railways and the National Railway Administration of the government of People's Republic of China on strengthening cooperation in railways.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">A five-year trade and economic development plan has been signed between the Ministries of Commerce and Industry of India and China. Agreed minutes of the tenth session of the India-China Joint Economic group will be followed.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Another agreement has been signed on audio-visual co-production between the Ministry of Information and Broadcasting and the State Administration of Press, Publication, Radio, Film and Television of The People's Republic of China.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Both the sides havealso struck a deal on mutual administrative assistance and co-operation in custom matters between the Government of India and the Government of China.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Both the nations have also agreed to sign an MoU between Indian Space Research organisation and China National Space Administration on cooperating with each other and making peaceful use of Space. According to the agreement signed, there is now an understanding between the Ministries of Culture of India and China on strengthening the exchange and cooperation between cultural institutions.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Another MoU has been signed assuring cooperation between the National Book Trust of India and the State Administration of Press, Publication, Radio, Film and Television of China. The nations plan to cooperate and work on Drug Administration and cooperation between China Food and Drug Administration of the People's Republic of China and the Ministry of Health and Family Welfare of the Republic of India.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Agreements have also been signed on establishing sister city relationship between Mumbai and Shanghai. A similar agreement was signed in Gujarat with cities Ahmedabad and Guangzhou. Gujarat and Guangdong will also establish sister city relationship with one another.</span></p>]]></description>
			<dc:creator>Edited by Kirti Dwivedi | Updated: 3:35 IST</dc:creator>
			<pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2014 10:23:20 -0600</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.newsx.com/national/nation/item/26823-india-signs-15-deal-with-china-strengthens-ties</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>RLD chief Ajit Singh's supporters threaten to stop water supply to Delhi</title>
			<link>http://www.newsx.com/national/nation/item/26822-rld-chief-ajit-singhs-supporters-threaten-to-stop-water-supply-to-delhi</link>
			<description><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/761d945f89985e1e2b954033f19d4e73_Generic.jpg"><img align="right" border="0" src="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/761d945f89985e1e2b954033f19d4e73_S.jpg" alt="rld-chief-ajit-singhs-supporters-threaten-to-stop-water-supply-to-delhi" /></a><font color="#ff3300"><b>Featured</b></font><p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">New Delhi: In a show of muscle power by RLD chief and former union minister Ajit Singh, his supporters on Thursday threatened to stop water supply to Delhi.</span></p>

<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Following this, a protest led by Ajit Singh and his supporters turned violent at Gang Nahar near Ghaziabad in Uttar Pradesh.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Protestors pelted stones at the police, after which there was a lathicharge. Ajit Singh had called the agitation after the New Delhi Municipal Council had ordered that water and power supply be cut to the government-owned house allotted to him for overstaying.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Earlier, haryana Chief Minister Bhupinder Singh Hooda had described the eviction order and snapping of power and water supply to official residence of Ajit Singh by the Centre as "discourteous act". Hooda had written to the NDA government demanding the bungalow be declared as a memorial.</span></p>]]></description>
			<dc:creator>Edited by Kirti Dwivedi | Updated: 3:15 IST</dc:creator>
			<pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2014 09:51:27 -0600</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.newsx.com/national/nation/item/26822-rld-chief-ajit-singhs-supporters-threaten-to-stop-water-supply-to-delhi</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Over 2 mn displaced in India due to natural disasters in 2013</title>
			<link>http://www.newsx.com/national/nation/item/26821-over-2-mn-displaced-in-india-due-to-natural-disasters-in-2013</link>
			<description><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/5e13cd6cf19180bd26ca07421337402d_Generic.jpg"><img align="right" border="0" src="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/5e13cd6cf19180bd26ca07421337402d_S.jpg" alt="over-2-mn-displaced-in-india-due-to-natural-disasters-in-2013" /></a><font color="#ff3300"><b>Featured</b></font><p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">United Nations: About 2.14 million people were displaced in India last year due to natural disasters, according to a United Nations-backed report which said the country was third after the Philippines and China to record the highest levels of displacement in 2013.</span></p>

<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The report 'Global Estimates 2014: people displaced by disasters' said 22 million people worldwide were displaced in 2013 by disasters sparked largely by earthquakes or climate, almost three times more than by conflict in the same year.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">In India, a total of 26.13 million people were displaced between 2008-2013, second only to China which had 54.25 million displacements.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Last year alone,?2.14 million people were displaced in India due to natural hazard-related events while conflict and violence displaced 64,000 people.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"Between 2008 and 2013, 80.9 per cent of displacement took place in Asia. The region accounted for the 14 largest displacements of 2013 and the five countries?with the highest displacement levels: the Philippines, China, India, Bangladesh and Vietnam," the report said.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">In south Asia, cyclone Mahasen forced the evacuation of around 1.1 million people in Bangladesh in May, and in October widespread monsoon season floods displaced over a million in several Indian states.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">In the same month, cyclone Phailin, the strongest to hit India in 14 years, brought widespread devastation to eastern coastal areas and forced the evacuation of another million people.</span><br /> <br /><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The report noted that improved preparadeness including evacuations was credited with limiting the death toll to fewer than 50 people in the country.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">China, India, the Philippines, Pakistan, Bangladesh, Nigeria and the US had the highest numbers of people displaced by rapid onset disasters between 2008-2013.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The report by the Norwegian Refugee Council?s Internal Displacement Monitoring Centre (IDMC) shows that the risk of displacement due to disasters has more than doubled over the last four decades largely due to the growth and concentration of urban populations, particularly in vulnerable countries.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"This increasing trend will continue as more and more people live and work in hazard-prone areas. It is expected to be aggravated in the future by the impacts of climate change," Secretary-General of the Norwegian Refugee Council Jan Egeland said here yesterday.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">UN Deputy Secretary-General Jan Eliasson said the report was "extremely timely" as it highlights the need for early warning systems and emergency evacuations in today?s world of increasing and intensifying disasters.</span></p>]]></description>
			<dc:creator>Edited by Priyanka Kukreja || Updated:13:20 IST</dc:creator>
			<pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2014 07:39:18 -0600</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.newsx.com/national/nation/item/26821-over-2-mn-displaced-in-india-due-to-natural-disasters-in-2013</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Tibetans protest outside Hyderabad House</title>
			<link>http://www.newsx.com/national/nation/item/26820-tibetans-protest-outside-hyderabad-house</link>
			<description><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/e449e823a71a7e33d2502e035a92ee48_Generic.jpg"><img align="right" border="0" src="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/e449e823a71a7e33d2502e035a92ee48_S.jpg" alt="tibetans-protest-outside-hyderabad-house" /></a><font color="#ff3300"><b>Featured</b></font><p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Scores of Tibetans today staged a vociferous protest and clashed with police outside Hyderabad House, the venue for the bilateral talks between Chinese President Xi Jinping and Prime Minister Narendra Modi.</span></p>

<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The protesters reached Gate No 3 of the building around 11:45 AM and started shouting anti-China slogans.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The police tried to pacify them but they did not relent and eventually clashed with the police as they were stopped from approaching the gate. Some of the protesters were also detained by the police.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">A group of Tibetans also held a protest at Dhaula Kuan and were forcefully removed from the spot.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Yesterday, ten Tibetans were detained after they staged a protest outside Chinese Embassy here against the visit of the Chinese President.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Xi is on a three-day visit to India.</span></p>]]></description>
			<dc:creator>Edited by Priyanka Kukreja || Updated: 12:50 IST</dc:creator>
			<pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2014 07:16:57 -0600</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.newsx.com/national/nation/item/26820-tibetans-protest-outside-hyderabad-house</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Sensex recovers from initial losses, up 186 pts</title>
			<link>http://www.newsx.com/national/business/item/26819-sensex-recovers-from-initial-losses-up-186-pts</link>
			<description><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/5af124701363bc46263646f9fa9b8924_Generic.jpg"><img align="right" border="0" src="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/5af124701363bc46263646f9fa9b8924_S.jpg" alt="sensex-recovers-from-initial-losses-up-186-pts" /></a><font color="#ff3300"><b>Featured</b></font><p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Mumbai: The benchmark BSE Sensex recovered from its initial losses and was quoted higher by 186 points in the morning trade on fresh buying mainly in healthcare, consumer durables, capital goods, refinery and realty counters on the back of higher global cues.</span></p>

<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Renewed capital inflows from foreign funds also boosted the market sentiment.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The Sensex resumed lower at 26,573.89 and dropped further to 26,503.08 on initial selling pressure. However, it recovered immediately to 26,880.50 before quoting at 26,817.</span></p>]]></description>
			<dc:creator>Edited by Priyanka Kukreja || Updated: 12:40 IST</dc:creator>
			<pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2014 07:06:21 -0600</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.newsx.com/national/business/item/26819-sensex-recovers-from-initial-losses-up-186-pts</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>#MinisterOfMyth: Minister of myth or water resources?</title>
			<link>http://www.newsx.com/component/k2/item/26818-#ministerofmyth-minister-of-myth-or-water-resources?&amp;Itemid=736</link>
			<description><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/c29b5b5b0141a2080ceb646f3089eb2c_Generic.jpg"><img align="right" border="0" src="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/c29b5b5b0141a2080ceb646f3089eb2c_S.jpg" alt="#ministerofmyth-minister-of-myth-or-water-resources?" /></a><p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Union Minister for Water Resources Uma Bharti has reportedly said that the Uttarakhand flood was caused due to defecation near the Kedarnath shrine.</span></p>
<p><iframe src="//www.youtube.com/embed/sDEx0hfF_cg" frameborder="0" width="684" height="415" allowfullscreen="true" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"></iframe></p>]]></description>
			<dc:creator>NewsX Bureau</dc:creator>
			<pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2014 04:41:26 -0600</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.newsx.com/component/k2/item/26818-#ministerofmyth-minister-of-myth-or-water-resources?&amp;Itemid=736</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Live: Chinese President Xi Jinping in Delhi, talks today with Modi on bilateral trade, border</title>
			<link>http://www.newsx.com/national/top-stories/item/26817-live-chinese-president-xi-jinping-in-delhi-talks-today-with-modi-on-bilateral-trade-border</link>
			<description><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/a8c78797f7faafbbaa575fd46f6b4b81_Generic.jpg"><img align="right" border="0" src="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/a8c78797f7faafbbaa575fd46f6b4b81_S.jpg" alt="live-chinese-president-xi-jinping-in-delhi-talks-today-with-modi-on-bilateral-trade-border" /></a><font color="#ff3300"><b>Featured</b></font><p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Chinese President Xi Jinping arrived in the national capital on Wednesday night after a grand welcome in Ahmedabad in Gujarat.</span></p>

<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The aircraft carrying Xi and his wife Peng Liyuan touched down at the Air Force Station in Palam after 10 pm.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">China's first couple were received by Human Resource Development Minister Smriti Irani.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Prime Minister Narendra Modi also arrived here at 10.35 p.m.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Earlier, Xi and his wife reached Ahmedabad Wednesday afternoon to begin a three-day India sojourn. He spent around six hours in Ahmedabad.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">In Ahmedabad, three agreements were inked in the presence of Modi and Xi.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">During the Ahmedabad leg of the tour, Xi and Modi also visited the Sabarmati Ashram, where the Chinese president took a stroll on the picturesque Sabarmati riverfront, sat on a swing and watched traditional folk dances of Gujarat.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">On Thursday, Modi and Xi would hold talks at Hyderabad House, which would be followed by the inking of several agreements, including on infrastructure and railways.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;"><strong>Here are the live updates :</strong></span></p>
<ul>
<li style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">India and China exchange bilateral agreements in presence of President Xi Jinping and PM Narendra Modi.</span></li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Narendra Modi, Xi Jinping meet ends, both the leaders will address media shortly.</span></li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Samajwadi Party leader Naresh Agarwal says, "There should be a compromise that both will be at their limit on the border. What's the meaning of this, that at one side Chinese president has come here and on the other Chinese are doing incursions at the border."</span></li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Tibetan spiritual guru leader Dalai Lama says Xi Jinping's thinking is more realistic and more open minded so he can learn more from India.</span></li>
<li><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Delhi Police detains Tibetan protestors, who were agitating against Xi's three-day visit to India.</span></li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Tibetan demonstrators raise anti-China slogans outside Hyderabad House.</span></li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Tibetan protesters stage demonstrators outside Hyderabad House where PM Narendra Modi is meeting Chinese President Xi Jinping.</span></li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The Chinese Army pushed in more troops into Chumar village along the Line of Actual Control in the wee hours today. According to sources, the Chinese side pushed in more troops before the break of dawn with more banners asking the Indian Army to leave the area.</span></li>
<li><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Chinese President's wife Peng Liyuan visits Tagore International School in Delhi.</span></li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Chinese President Xi Jinping meets PM Narendra Modi at Hyderabad House. Both leaders are expected to ink several agreements, including on infrastructure and railways.</span></li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Ge xia, wo hen huanying nin dao yindu lai - I extend a very warm welcome to you in India," Sushma Swaraj greets the Chinese President.</span></li>
</ul>
<ul style="text-align: justify;">
<li style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Chinese President Xi Jinping meets External Affairs Minister Sushma Swaraj.</span></li>
</ul>
<ul style="text-align: justify;">
<li style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Union Minister Smrii Irani Jinping presents a model of 'charkha' to Chinese President.</span></li>
</ul>
<ul style="text-align: justify;">
<li style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">I&amp;B Minister Prakash Javadekar to meet Chinese delegation at 4:30 PM at Shastri Bhawan today.</span></li>
</ul>
<ul style="text-align: justify;">
<li style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Tibetan activist protests in Delhi's Dhaula Kuan area against Xi Jinping's visit.</span></li>
</ul>
<ul style="text-align: justify;">
<li style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Chinese President accompanied by HRD Minister Smriti Irani reaches Rajghat, pays homage to Mahatma Gandhi.</span></li>
</ul>
<p><span style="font-size: 10pt;"><iframe src="//www.youtube.com/embed/TTAvAYVL5yc" frameborder="0" width="684" height="415" allowfullscreen="true" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"></iframe></span></p>
<ul style="text-align: justify;">
<li style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The summit meetings are occasion for leaders to raise all substantive issues having bearing on bilateral ties, The Prime Minister took the opportunity to raise the issue last night with the visiting dignitary, Akbaruddin says.</span></li>
</ul>
<ul style="text-align: justify;">
<li style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The MEA spokesperson says all issues of substance will be raised today with Chinese President.</span></li>
</ul>
<ul style="text-align: justify;">
<li style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">MEA spokesperson Syed Akbaruddin says Prime Minister Narendra Modi raised the issue of Chinese incursions with the visiting Chinese President during their meeting Wednesday night.</span></li>
</ul>
<ul style="text-align: justify;">
<li style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Chinese President heads to Rajghat to pay homage to Mahatma Gandhi.</span></li>
</ul>
<ul style="text-align: justify;">
<li style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">India and China need to take strategic partnership to higher levels, Jinping says.</span></li>
</ul>
<ul style="text-align: justify;">
<li style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Beijing and New Delhi can create opportunities for the world, Jinping says.</span></li>
</ul>
<ul style="text-align: justify;">
<li style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Stressing on friendship between India and China, Jinping says he hopes to talk to the Indian leadership to take this "strategic relationship" forward.</span></li>
</ul>
<ul style="text-align: justify;">
<li style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">We have common development goals, it is important we deepen the alignment of our development strategies, Chinese President says.</span></li>
</ul>
<ul style="text-align: justify;">
<li style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">China admires and respects each other’s civilisation and it is important that New Delhi and Beijing deepen mutual respect, says Jinping.</span></li>
</ul>
<ul style="text-align: justify;">
<li style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">My main goal to deepen cooperatio between India, China, Jinping says.</span></li>
</ul>
<ul style="text-align: justify;">
<li style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Xi speaks of mutual understanding and friendship between the two countries and hopes to achieve a lot during his first visit to India.</span></li>
</ul>
<ul style="text-align: justify;">
<li style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Chinese President Xi Jinping stresses on friendship between India and China.</span></li>
</ul>
<ul style="text-align: justify;">
<li style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The Chinese President addresses media.</span></li>
</ul>
<ul style="text-align: justify;">
<li style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Chinese President Xi Jinping receives a guard of honor at the President House.</span></li>
</ul>
<ul style="text-align: justify;">
<li style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">President Pranab Mukherjee receives Xi Pinging at Rashtrapati Bhawan.</span></li>
</ul>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">&nbsp;</span></p>]]></description>
			<dc:creator>Edited by Priyanka Kukreja || Updated: Sep 18, 10:05 IST</dc:creator>
			<pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2014 04:31:15 -0600</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.newsx.com/national/top-stories/item/26817-live-chinese-president-xi-jinping-in-delhi-talks-today-with-modi-on-bilateral-trade-border</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>#FloodOfTreachery: What does Yasin Malik have to say?</title>
			<link>http://www.newsx.com/component/k2/item/26816-#floodoftreachery-what-does-yasin-malik-have-to-say?&amp;Itemid=736</link>
			<description><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/9ca9801871e48989c68a37edbd918115_Generic.jpg"><img align="right" border="0" src="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/9ca9801871e48989c68a37edbd918115_S.jpg" alt="#floodoftreachery-what-does-yasin-malik-have-to-say?" /></a><p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Leaders of various political parties on Wednesday condemned the move of a group of separatist leaders, led by Jammu and Kashmir Liberation Front (JKLF) leader Yasin Malik, to hijack a boat meant for relief work in flood-ravaged Jammu and Kashmir.</span></p>

<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Bharatiya Janata Party (BJP) leader Shahnawaz Hussain said separatist leaders, such as Yasin Malik are jealous of the fact that the Indian Army is gaining popularity in Kashmir for devotedly helping the flood victims, and are therefore trying to disrupt rescue operations.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">“Just because the army is getting favoritism in Kashmir, separatists don’t need to get jealous and disrupt rescue operations. The people of Kashmir have realized that army has done a lot for them, but the news regarding Yasin Malik is very unfortunate,” he said.</span></p>
<p><iframe src="//www.youtube.com/embed/LGyb0i-Dz2Y" frameborder="0" width="684" height="415" allowfullscreen="true" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"></iframe></p>]]></description>
			<dc:creator>NewsX Bureau</dc:creator>
			<pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2014 04:23:30 -0600</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.newsx.com/component/k2/item/26816-#floodoftreachery-what-does-yasin-malik-have-to-say?&amp;Itemid=736</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>23-year-old girl gang-raped by friends in moving car</title>
			<link>http://www.newsx.com/regional/delhi/item/26815-23-year-old-girl-gang-raped-by-friends-in-moving-car</link>
			<description><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/809429901faba31682db3affb4f12093_Generic.jpg"><img align="right" border="0" src="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/809429901faba31682db3affb4f12093_S.jpg" alt="23-year-old-girl-gang-raped-by-friends-in-moving-car" /></a><font color="#ff3300"><b>Featured</b></font><p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">A 23-year-old girl was allegedly gang-raped by her male friend and two of his friends in a moving car before being dumped by the roadside near Nehru Place area of South Delhi.</span></p>

<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Police said the incident took place late Tuesday night when the victim, a daughter of Delhi Police woman constable, was offered soft drinks laced with sedatives by the accused.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"(The) girl along with her male friend and his friend came out for a ride. On the way, they offered her soft drinks laced with sedatives. After drinking it, the girl fell unconscious," said a senior police officer.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">According to the officer the girl alleged in her complaint that she was then gang-raped and dumped near Nehru Place flyover.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"Seeing a girl lying in an unconscious condition, an auto driver, who was passing through the area, immediately called up the police. Police took victim to a nearby hospital," officer also said.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Medical examination has confirmed the rape and a case has been registered in this regard.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Police said that they have detained two persons in the connection.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"A case has been registered in this regard and further investigation is on," the officer added.</span></p>]]></description>
			<dc:creator>Edited by Priyanka Kukreja || Updated: Sep 18, 9:50 IST</dc:creator>
			<pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2014 04:19:38 -0600</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.newsx.com/regional/delhi/item/26815-23-year-old-girl-gang-raped-by-friends-in-moving-car</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>#VVIPShame: MLAs tour europe, Karnataka battles floods </title>
			<link>http://www.newsx.com/national/top-stories/item/26812-vvipshame-mlas-tour-europe-karnataka-battles-floods</link>
			<description><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/031e5d161c55299847006df669677e93_Generic.jpg"><img align="right" border="0" src="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/031e5d161c55299847006df669677e93_S.jpg" alt="vvipshame-mlas-tour-europe-karnataka-battles-floods" /></a><font color="#ff3300"><b>Featured</b></font><p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Bangalore: A trip to European countries by a group of ruling Congress legislators in Karnataka, when some parts of the state were hit by floods, has triggered a controversy.</span></p>

<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">As about 15 MLAs were enjoying their tour, Chief Minister Siddaramaiah told reporters that he was not aware of the trip and no way connected with it.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"I am not aware of their visit to the European countries and I am no way connected to the issue," he said, adding "None of them have intimated me about their trip to European countries."</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Asked if they would be called back, he replied in the negative.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Siddaramaiah said the government was tackling the situation caused by floods.</span></p>
<p><iframe src="//www.youtube.com/embed/7RBzYh7KKrc" frameborder="0" width="684" height="415" allowfullscreen="true" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"></iframe></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">A similar planned junket of 100 MLAs in batches to Australia and New Zealand, had triggered a major controversy in December last year, especially when large parts of the state were reeling under drought.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">After the public outcry against the foreign jaunts, Karnataka Speaker Kagodu Thimappa had put on hold the trips while some parts of the state were reeling under severe drought.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">This prompted the government to set up a committee which recommended doing away with the present system in which MLAs who are members of many Legislature Committees are entitled to go on tours abroad on an ad hoc basis.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Thimappa had said it would not be fair for the government to ban junkets, but send the legislators on subject-specific tours on rotation basis.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">However, Cooperation Minister Mahadev Prasad came to the defence of the legislators now on tour saying that they are visiting the foreign locale, paying out of their pockets.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"They (legislators) have gone on their own. They are paying out of their pockets, not by spending public money," he said.</span></p>]]></description>
			<dc:creator>Edited by Priyanka Kukreja || Updated: 9:20 IST</dc:creator>
			<pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2014 03:46:08 -0600</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.newsx.com/national/top-stories/item/26812-vvipshame-mlas-tour-europe-karnataka-battles-floods</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Delhi University up by 20 ranks in QS World University Rankings</title>
			<link>http://www.newsx.com/cities/item/26811-delhi-university-up-by-20-ranks-in-qs-world-university-rankings</link>
			<description><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/45669fcec80747c305c2beefbf09374a_Generic.jpg"><img align="right" border="0" src="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/45669fcec80747c305c2beefbf09374a_S.jpg" alt="delhi-university-up-by-20-ranks-in-qs-world-university-rankings" /></a><font color="#ff3300"><b>Featured</b></font><p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">New Delhi: Delhi University has moved up by 20 ranks in the QS World University Rankings compared to previous year's rank and has been placed on top amongst the Indian universities other than five IITs.</span></p>

<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">While last year, the overall world ranking of DU was between 441-451. This year it has been ranked between 421-430.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Even as the university has been facing flak from the Delhi University's Teachers' Association (DUTA) for its recent decisions on pension and promotions issue, DU has been ranked first in India for 'Employer Reputation' while its world ranking is 122 in the category.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The University of Mumbai has been ranked second in India on the scale of employer reputation.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">According to the QS ranking, on basis of the Academic Reputation, DU has been ranked 196 which is the highest rank awarded to an Indian University other than some IITs.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">With a worldwide rank of 166, in the field of Social Science and Management, DU remains at top among the Indian universities. In Arts and Humanities and Natural Science, DU has been ranked second with world ranking of 194 and 220 respectively.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The QS World University Rankings for 2014-15 which were released yesterday take into account research quality,graduate employment, student-staff ratios, teaching standards and the number of international students while rating nearly 800 universities from all over the world.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">However, the biggest single factor in the QS rankings is academic reputation. This is calculated by surveying more than 60,000 academics around the world about their opinion on the merits of institutions other than their own.</span></p>]]></description>
			<dc:creator>Edited by Priyanka Kukreja || Updated: Sep 18, 8:55 IST</dc:creator>
			<pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2014 03:29:39 -0600</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.newsx.com/cities/item/26811-delhi-university-up-by-20-ranks-in-qs-world-university-rankings</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>I waited three years for Hrithik Roshan: Ashutosh Gowariker on ‘Mohenjo Daro’ </title>
			<link>http://www.newsx.com/showbiz/bollywood/item/26810-i-waited-three-years-for-hrithik-roshan-ashutosh-gowariker-on-mohenjo-daro</link>
			<description><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/ba8020c8d2fcb00e8370aa5350cda100_Generic.jpg"><img align="right" border="0" src="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/ba8020c8d2fcb00e8370aa5350cda100_S.jpg" alt="i-waited-three-years-for-hrithik-roshan-ashutosh-gowariker-on-mohenjo-daro" /></a><font color="#ff3300"><b>Featured</b></font><p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Mumbai: Noted filmmaker Asutosh Gowariker, who is all set to team up with Hrithik Roshan again in next project 'Mohenjo Daro', says the superstar took three years to say yes for the period drama.</span></p>

<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">'Mohenjo Daro', a love story set during the Indus Valley civilisation, is jointly produced by Disney and Gowariker, who is also directing the film.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"It's an individual choice, interest and ability to stay interested and keep pursuing. For me 'Lagaan' would have never happened without Aamir, similarly without Hrithik I could have never made 'Jodha Akbar'.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"And also Mohan Bhargav ('Swades') would have never been possible without Shah Rukh Khan. The same was true for Abhishek as Surya Sen (Khelein Hum Jee Jaan Sey). So, for me it was natural that I waited three years for Hrithik to find time," Gowariker said in a group interview here.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">With the film, Gowariker is launching a new face, Pooja Hegde, as the female lead.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The 50-year-old director, who launched actresses like Gracy Singh and Gayatri Joshi through his films, said, "The character needed a new fresh face and that's why Pooja came in."</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">'Mohenjo Daro' is scheduled to go on floor in November this year. Currently the director is scouting the locations for the film.</span></p>]]></description>
			<dc:creator>Edited by Priyanka Kukreja || Updated: 8:40 IST</dc:creator>
			<pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2014 03:06:48 -0600</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.newsx.com/showbiz/bollywood/item/26810-i-waited-three-years-for-hrithik-roshan-ashutosh-gowariker-on-mohenjo-daro</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Gene variant that reduces 'bad' lipids identified</title>
			<link>http://www.newsx.com/life-style/health/item/26809-gene-variant-that-reduces-bad-lipids-identified</link>
			<description><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/23d7a632e10421b14aa13521ee01018a_Generic.jpg"><img align="right" border="0" src="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/23d7a632e10421b14aa13521ee01018a_S.jpg" alt="gene-variant-that-reduces-bad-lipids-identified" /></a><font color="#ff3300"><b>Featured</b></font><p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">London: Scientists have identified a rare genetic variant that dramatically reduces levels of certain types of lipids in the blood which is associated with reduced risk of cardiovascular disease.</span></p>

<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Researchers looked at whole genome sequences from 4,000 people in the UK and compared this with data about their lipid levels.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">They spotted an association between levels of lipids called triglycerides and the presence of the APOC3 gene variant.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The research suggests that people with the rare change (approximately 0.2 per cent of the population carry this) typically have lower levels of triglycerides.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Previous research has shown that lower levels of triglycerides are associated with reduced risk of cardiovascular disease.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"Once we can understand the mechanism of the protective function of this variant, we can try to use this information to develop novel therapies to help those at risk of cardiovascular disease," said Professor Steve Humphries, senior author from University College London.</span></p>]]></description>
			<dc:creator>Edited by Priyanka Kukreja || Updated: Sep 18, 8:20 IST</dc:creator>
			<pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2014 02:50:22 -0600</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.newsx.com/life-style/health/item/26809-gene-variant-that-reduces-bad-lipids-identified</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Imran calls for ‘Day of Deliverance’ on Friday, Sharif defiant</title>
			<link>http://www.newsx.com/world/pakistan/item/26808-imran-calls-for-day-of-deliverance-on-friday-sharif-defiant</link>
			<description><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/64d3368c4f3ee25452c15c37839a6ee3_Generic.jpg"><img align="right" border="0" src="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/64d3368c4f3ee25452c15c37839a6ee3_S.jpg" alt="imran-calls-for-day-of-deliverance-on-friday-sharif-defiant" /></a><font color="#ff3300"><b>Featured</b></font><p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Pakistan government and protesters were once again headed on collision course with Imran Khan declaring Friday as a ‘Day of Deliverance’ and a defiant Prime Minister Nawaz Sharif on Thursday saying he will not resign on the wishes of a few thousand.</span></p>

<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The country’s political crisis deepened with a murder case registered against Prime Minister Sharif, his ministers and other top officials last night for their alleged involvement in the killing of anti-government protesters.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">At least three people were killed and over 500 injured in clashes with police on August 30 after Pakistan Tehreek-i- Insaf Chairman Khan and cleric Tahir-ul-Qadri of the Pakistan Awami Tehreek asked their supporters to march towards Sharif’s official residence. PAT had approached the court for registering of the case.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Khan announced late last night that Friday would be marked as ‘Go Nawaz Go’ Day and a ‘Day of Deliverance’. The cricketer-turned-politician, while addressing supporters in front of the Parliament, said he would continue the protest movement till Sharif resigns.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">With Imran stepping up pressure on the government, Qadri also reiterated PAT’s demand for Sharif’s resignation. The PAT chief said Sharif and his close aides, booked for murder charges, should be arrested immediately. “If not today, then tomorrow they will be hanged,” Qadri said.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Prime Minister Sharif, while speaking at a public event in the Punjab province, said the entire nation had a unanimous view of pursuing a democratic path with only a few people pursuing negative politics that posed a serious threat to national development.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">“Why should Nawaz Sharif and Shahbaz Sharif resign on the demand of five thousand people,” the Prime Minister said, adding that he was sure the nation would stand by them. “The entire Parliament is on one side and a single party stands alone on the other (demanding resignation),” he said. Sharif highlighted that the government had shown a lot of patience in dealing with the Islamabad sit-ins.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">“It is not hard to clear the containers and protesters, but we have shown patience in this regard,” Sharif said. Meanwhile, Jamaat-e-Islami (JI) chief Sirajul Haq said negotiations with protesting parties — PTI and PAT — and the government will begin on Thursday.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">“I have been in contact with members of various other political parties, and we have decided that negotiations with the rulers and the protesting parties will begin again tomorrow,” Haq said while addressing the media. Khan wants Sharif’s ouster over alleged rigging in last year’s poll which his party lost, while Qadri wants to bring a revolution in the country. They are agitating since August 14, demanding Sharif’s ouster.</span></p>]]></description>
			<dc:creator>Edited by Priyanka Kukreja || Updated: 8:10 IST</dc:creator>
			<pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2014 02:34:41 -0600</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.newsx.com/world/pakistan/item/26808-imran-calls-for-day-of-deliverance-on-friday-sharif-defiant</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Father sentenced to death for murder of teenage girl</title>
			<link>http://www.newsx.com/regional/other-states/item/26807-father-sentenced-to-death-for-murder-of-teenage-girl</link>
			<description><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/b773154a412aa9d0a1a730fff5c97934_Generic.jpg"><img align="right" border="0" src="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/b773154a412aa9d0a1a730fff5c97934_S.jpg" alt="father-sentenced-to-death-for-murder-of-teenage-girl" /></a><font color="#ff3300"><b>Featured</b></font><p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Chandigarh: A court in Panchkula today handed the death sentence to the father and uncle of a teenage girl for her murder in October last year.</span></p>

<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The court of District and Sessions Judge RK Sondhi awarded the death sentence to the 15-year-old girl's father Shaukeen and uncle Salim, prosecution said. The court ruled that duo had killed the girl over an affair she was said to be having with the fiance of her elder sister.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The court had convicted the duo last week.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The girl's body was found near an orchard in a Panchkula village on the night of October 23, 2013. She was a native of Muzaffarnagar in Uttar Pradesh.</span></p>]]></description>
			<dc:creator>Edited by Priyanka Kukreja || Updated: Sep 18, 7:55 IST</dc:creator>
			<pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2014 02:24:21 -0600</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.newsx.com/regional/other-states/item/26807-father-sentenced-to-death-for-murder-of-teenage-girl</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Modi gifts copy of Gita in Chinese to Xi at Sabarmati Ashram</title>
			<link>http://www.newsx.com/national/nation/item/26814-modi-gifts-copy-of-gita-in-chinese-to-xi-at-sabarmati-ashram</link>
			<description><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/722471f5679cbaeeb8772510f33680be_Generic.jpg"><img align="right" border="0" src="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/722471f5679cbaeeb8772510f33680be_S.jpg" alt="modi-gifts-copy-of-gita-in-chinese-to-xi-at-sabarmati-ashram" /></a><font color="#ff3300"><b>Featured</b></font><p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Chinese President Xi Jinping, who kicked off his India visit from Gujarat, visited the Sabarmati ashram of Mahatma Gandhi in Ahmedabad where Prime Minister Narendra Modi gifted him a copy of the Gita written in Chinese language.</span></p>

<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Xi Jinping was received by PM Modi and Gujarat Chief Minister Anandi Patel on the gates of tranquil Sabarmati Ashram, located in the Sabarmati suburb adjoining the Ashram Road, on the banks of river Sabarmati.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">PM Modi and Patel offered cotton garlands to Xi Jinping and accompanied him to different rooms in the ashram which was home of the Mahatma for about 12 years and his wife Kasturba Gandhi.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Later, the Chinese President paid homage to an idol of Gandhi there. PM Modi also explained Gandhi's writings in Hindi and English, to the Chinese President on the occasion. According to the trustees of Sabarmati Ashram, Mr Jinping wrote in Chinese in the visitors' book.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Xi Jinping also visited Gandhi's personal room 'Hridayakunj' and offered a cotton garland to Gandhi's picture.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">PM Modi also presented mementos, including books and a painting on Gandhi, to Xi on the occasion.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"The Sabarmati Ashram Trust presented a replica of the charkha, originally used by Gandhi during his stay in Yervada jail near Pune, to the Chinese President. Xi Jinping was also given a copy of the original certificate, given to Gandhi by the people of Chinese origin in South Africa in 1915," said trustee of the Ashram Kartikeya Sarabhai</span></p>]]></description>
			<dc:creator>Edited by Priyanka Kukreja || Updated: 7:50 IST</dc:creator>
			<pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2014 02:18:34 -0600</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.newsx.com/national/nation/item/26814-modi-gifts-copy-of-gita-in-chinese-to-xi-at-sabarmati-ashram</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>100 more Chinese soldiers enter Ladakh’s Chumar area</title>
			<link>http://www.newsx.com/national/nation/item/26813-100-more-chinese-soldiers-enter-ladakhs-chumar-area</link>
			<description><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/ae2a27ce0ce249cbe8a889220cba7f04_Generic.jpg"><img align="right" border="0" src="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/ae2a27ce0ce249cbe8a889220cba7f04_S.jpg" alt="100-more-chinese-soldiers-enter-ladakhs-chumar-area" /></a><font color="#ff3300"><b>Featured</b></font><p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">On a day Chinese President Xi Jinping kicked off his three-day visit to the country, the Chinese army reportedly made a fresh incursion in Chumar area and refused to return even as a flag-meeting between the two sides is believed to have made no headway in breaking the deadlock.</span></p>

<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Official sources told PTI that some of the Chinese troops had returned on Tuesday and it was generally expected that the others would also retreat to their side of the perceived LAC.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">However, as many as 100 more soldiers of Chinese People’s Liberation Army (PLA) arrived from a hillock of Chumar area and strengthened its numbers to nearly 350, sources said.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Surprisingly, the move came barely few hours ahead of Chinese President Xi Jinping’s arrival in India on a state visit.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">India also rushed some more troops in the area and both sides were indulging in repeated banner drill, the sources said.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">A Brigadier-level flag meeting, second within a week, was held in Chushul, where the issue of intrusion of Chinese troops in Chumar and civilian intrusion in the Demchok area was discussed, the sources said.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">According to home ministry sources an intrusion was reported from the same area on Wednesday also but they are not reading into it much as such incidents happen along the LAC almost daily.</span></p>]]></description>
			<dc:creator>Edited by Priyanka Kukreja || Updated: 7:40 IST</dc:creator>
			<pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2014 02:09:47 -0600</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.newsx.com/national/nation/item/26813-100-more-chinese-soldiers-enter-ladakhs-chumar-area</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Sardar Patel 'would not have let J&amp;K split,' claims Amit Shah </title>
			<link>http://www.newsx.com/national/nation/item/26806-sardar-patel-would-not-have-let-jk-split-claims-amit-shah</link>
			<description><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/8c53cc4ccc037d843e339c8f2fe05e5e_Generic.jpg"><img align="right" border="0" src="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/8c53cc4ccc037d843e339c8f2fe05e5e_S.jpg" alt="sardar-patel-would-not-have-let-jk-split-claims-amit-shah" /></a><font color="#ff3300"><b>Featured</b></font><p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Bidar: BJP President Amit Shah on Wednesday said Pakistan would not have been holding a part of Kashmir and Article 370 would not have existed had Sardar Vallabhai Patel, instead of Jawharlal Nehru, handled the Kashmir issue.</span></p>

<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"....Even today a big part of Kashmir is under Pakistan. I don't have any hesitation in telling you that if Kashmir issue was also given to Sardar Patel instead of Jawaharlal Nehru....The part of Kashmir would not have gone under Pakistan; Article 370 also wouldn?t have been there and it would have remained as any other territory of India," he said.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Shah said "it is because of Sardar Patel, his firm determination and his ability to understand people we are all together, we have to always remember this.'</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">He was speaking at a function after laying foundation stone for the statue of Patel and a martyrs' memorial at Gorta village in Bidar district in north Karnataka.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Gorta is called Jalianwala Bagh of South India after the militia of the Nizam of Hyderabad massacred some 200 people of the village for hoisting the Indian flag on May 9, 1948. Gorta was under the Nizam rule. Nizam's were reluctant to be a part of Indian Union but under the "Operation Polo" in 1948, the state of Hyderabad became part of it.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Shah said "If today this old Nizam state is part of united India, the credit has to go to Sardar Patel."</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Stating that Patel's life is an inspiration to many, he said "no one from his family is into politics; in spite of him being in public life for long no one knows about his family, this is what differentiates Patel."</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"Despite being a known barrister in Gujarat, when he died his bank balance was only Rs 150. He lived a very simple life. I on this day of liberation day from the old Nizam state, pay my rich tributes to him on behalf of all countrymen.?</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Shah also remembered the martyrs of Gorata massacre.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">BJP has plans to unveil the martyrs memorial and statue of Sardar Patel on September 17, 2015 by Prime Minister Narendra Modi.</span></p>]]></description>
			<dc:creator>Edited by Devendra Singh || Updated 07:35 IST</dc:creator>
			<pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2014 02:06:19 -0600</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.newsx.com/national/nation/item/26806-sardar-patel-would-not-have-let-jk-split-claims-amit-shah</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Congress releases booklet on 100 days of BJP &quot;misrule&quot; </title>
			<link>http://www.newsx.com/national/nation/item/26805-congress-releases-booklet-on-100-days-of-bjp-misrule</link>
			<description><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/165ac8fe39fd5a137e505ba8ddbedf44_Generic.jpg"><img align="right" border="0" src="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/165ac8fe39fd5a137e505ba8ddbedf44_S.jpg" alt="congress-releases-booklet-on-100-days-of-bjp-misrule" /></a><font color="#ff3300"><b>Featured</b></font><p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">New Delhi: Congress on Wednesday brought out a booklet on BJP's "100 days of misrule" insisting that results of all the bypolls after the Lok Sabha election reflect "people's anger" over "hollow promises of a useless government".</span></p>

<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The slide of the ruling party was a "significant trend" that will gather momentum with the "unmasking" of BJP, the party claimed in the booklet titled "Modi government-The truth of BJP government: 100 days of misrule".</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"The story till now is only of slogans and more slogans. The nation is worried at what lies in store for India for the remaining tenure of this government", the AICC said in the booklet released by party spokesman Anand Sharma.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Suggesting that the landslide for BJP has turned into a slide, it said, "The results of all the bye-elections held after 2014 Lok Sabha reflect people's anger and rejection of BJP's politics of hatred and hoodwinking."</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The party noted that in the 54 Assembly constituencies where bye-elections were held, BJP had led in 42 constituencies in May 2014 which has now been reduced to only 21".</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Dubbing the Modi rule and its assurances as "hollow promises of a useless government" (khokhle vaade nikammi sarkar), it said that the 100-day rule of Prime Minister Narendra Modi showed that he has assumed the role of a dream merchant in the poll campaign and "sold false dreams".</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Demanding an apology from the government for "fooling the people" during the election campaign, it said NDA owed an explanation over its "failure" to control prices after coming to power.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Listing out the "failures" of the government on several fronts, the party alleged that the BJP-led dispensation was "still in election mode". "It continues to make wild and baseless allegations on its political opponents on the one hand and continues to make false promises on the other."</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Assuring people that "mistakes and wrong doings" of Modi government will not go uncontested, the party said that it will ensure that the remaining tenure of this government is "bereft of pain" for people of the country.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Noting that BJP has lost most of the bypolls in all regions to Congress and other opposition parties, it said, "This is a significant trend that cannot be ignored, and will surely gain momentum with the unmasking of BJP."</span></p>]]></description>
			<dc:creator>Edited by Devendra Singh || Updated 07:15 IST</dc:creator>
			<pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2014 01:50:12 -0600</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.newsx.com/national/nation/item/26805-congress-releases-booklet-on-100-days-of-bjp-misrule</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Madras: HC seeks details on number of cases registered against teachers</title>
			<link>http://www.newsx.com/regional/tamil-nadu/item/26803-madras-hc-seeks-details-on-number-of-cases-registered-against-teachers</link>
			<description><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/ba29c0f176c2cf66185b85bc1c062db1_Generic.jpg"><img align="right" border="0" src="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/ba29c0f176c2cf66185b85bc1c062db1_S.jpg" alt="madras-hc-seeks-details-on-number-of-cases-registered-against-teachers" /></a><font color="#ff3300"><b>Featured</b></font><p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Madurai: The Madras High Court bench on Wednesday sought details from police on the number of cases registered against teachers on complaints of students committing suicide after being reprimanded/punished by teachers.</span></p>

<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Justice N Kirubakaran gave the direction while hearing a petition filed by John Kennedy, Principal of St Thomas Higher Secondary School, Nadukaveri, Thanjavur district, seeking to quash a case proceedings against him in Judicial Magistrate Court at Tiruvaiyaru regarding the suicide of one of his students for scolding him.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The petitioner allegedly scolded him for scoring poor marks in examinations. The student committed suicide on March seven, 2012 for allegedly being scolded for securing low marks in the examinations. The case was registered on a complaint given by the father of the student.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The petitioner said police registered a case against him under IPC Sec 306 (abetment of suicide) and later a charge-sheet under Sec IPc 305 (abetting suicide by person below 18 years committing suicide).</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The petitioner submitted that there was no motive for the alleged occurrence. He contended that every teacher and headmaster is a well wisher of his/her students. The teachers were strict towards their students for welfare of their future. If this type of cases are allowed, it will create fear in the minds of the teacher community.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">He also sought to stay the proceeding of the case in the Judicial Magistrate Court and also dispense his personal appearance in the court.</span></p>]]></description>
			<dc:creator>Edited by Kirti Dwivedi | Updated: 9:45 IST</dc:creator>
			<pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2014 16:55:00 -0600</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.newsx.com/regional/tamil-nadu/item/26803-madras-hc-seeks-details-on-number-of-cases-registered-against-teachers</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>India Debates: #ModiFyingChina – Face – off in Ladakh, Bhai –Bhai in Gujarat </title>
			<link>http://www.newsx.com/component/k2/item/26804-india-debates-#modifyingchina-–-face-–-off-in-ladakh-bhai-–bhai-in-gujarat&amp;Itemid=919</link>
			<description><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/5377f2bf546f4759203f7d295c2df1e2_Generic.jpg"><img align="right" border="0" src="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/5377f2bf546f4759203f7d295c2df1e2_S.jpg" alt="india-debates-#modifyingchina-–-face-–-off-in-ladakh-bhai-–bhai-in-gujarat" /></a><font color="#ff3300"><b>Featured</b></font><p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Chinese President Xi Jinping reached Ahmedabad on Wednesday for his three-day visit to India that will focus on building closer relations with the world's second-largest economy.</span></p>

<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The Chinese president was received by Gujarat Chief Minister Anandiben Patel at the Sardar Vallabhbhai Patel Airport in Ahmedabad.</span></p>
<p><iframe src="//www.youtube.com/embed/aybCIpzeW7A" frameborder="0" width="684" height="415" allowfullscreen="true" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"></iframe></p>]]></description>
			<dc:creator>NewsX Bureau</dc:creator>
			<pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2014 16:44:52 -0600</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.newsx.com/component/k2/item/26804-india-debates-#modifyingchina-–-face-–-off-in-ladakh-bhai-–bhai-in-gujarat&amp;Itemid=919</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Delhi: Gymnast and coach booked for 'harassing' woman player</title>
			<link>http://www.newsx.com/cities/item/26802-delhi-gymnast-and-coach-booked-for-harassing-woman-player</link>
			<description><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/5bcc6c4bcfdf566b0bf57fffc7ec9677_Generic.jpg"><img align="right" border="0" src="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/5bcc6c4bcfdf566b0bf57fffc7ec9677_S.jpg" alt="delhi-gymnast-and-coach-booked-for-harassing-woman-player" /></a><font color="#ff3300"><b>Featured</b></font><p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">New Delhi: Delhi Police has intensified investigation in the alleged sexual harassment of a woman player by an international-level gymnast and a gymnastics coach.</span></p>

<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The two accused, who are part of the squad which left for the Incheon Asian Games yesterday, have been booked for allegedly passing obscene comments and making vulgar gestures at the woman player, police said on Wednesday.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"An investigation has been launched in the case and police are recording statements of several persons, including stadium staff and other persons. Police are also scanning the footage of CCTV to get some leads in the case," a senior police officer said.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Asked if the accused will be asked to return to India, the officer said that will be done if needed. "Investigating team is doing its job. If needed, police will ask both accused to return to India. However, both are scheduled to come back in the first week of October and police can also then record their statements," he said.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">In a complaint lodged with the Delhi Police on Tuesday night, the trainee-level woman gymnast has alleged that the coach and the player passed vulgar remarks about her clothes and made indecent gestures towards her on September 2 evening during a practice session at Indira Gandhi Indoor Stadium.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">A case has been registered under Section 509 (word, gesture or act intended to insult the modesty of a woman) and 506 (punishment for criminal intimidation) of the Indian Penal Code (IPC) at IP Estate police station in central Delhi.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The victim had also alleged that police initially refused to take her complaint, but when a senior official intervened, an FIR was then registered. Speaking on these allegations, a top police official said, "We will investigate if there was a delay on the part of police officials to register gymnast's complaint. If anyone is found guilty, we will take action. Police are also investigating the allegations of gymnast and justice will be done."</span></p>]]></description>
			<dc:creator>Edited by Kirti Dwivedi | Updated:  9:25 IST</dc:creator>
			<pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2014 16:20:44 -0600</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.newsx.com/cities/item/26802-delhi-gymnast-and-coach-booked-for-harassing-woman-player</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Nation at 9: #FloodofTreachery – No one to arrest a ‘traitor’? </title>
			<link>http://www.newsx.com/component/k2/item/26801-nation-at-9-#floodoftreachery-–-no-one-to-arrest-a-‘traitor’?&amp;Itemid=736</link>
			<description><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/9ec9eeff31bc07bedd96db52a0419943_Generic.jpg"><img align="right" border="0" src="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/9ec9eeff31bc07bedd96db52a0419943_S.jpg" alt="nation-at-9-#floodoftreachery-–-no-one-to-arrest-a-‘traitor’?" /></a><font color="#ff3300"><b>Featured</b></font><p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Leaders of various political parties on Wednesday condemned the move of a group of separatist leaders, led by Jammu and Kashmir Liberation Front (JKLF) leader Yasin Malik, to hijack a boat meant for relief work in flood-ravaged Jammu and Kashmir.</span></p>

<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Bharatiya Janata Party (BJP) leader Shahnawaz Hussain said separatist leaders, such as Yasin Malik are jealous of the fact that the Indian Army is gaining popularity in Kashmir for devotedly helping the flood victims, and are therefore trying to disrupt rescue operations.</span><br /><br /><span style="font-size: 10pt;">“Just because the army is getting favoritism in Kashmir, separatists don’t need to get jealous and disrupt rescue operations. The people of Kashmir have realized that army has done a lot for them, but the news regarding Yasin Malik is very unfortunate,” he said.</span></p>
<p><iframe src="//www.youtube.com/embed/ekHpTIYr9bU" frameborder="0" width="684" height="415" allowfullscreen="true" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"></iframe></p>]]></description>
			<dc:creator>NewsX Bureau</dc:creator>
			<pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2014 16:10:20 -0600</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.newsx.com/component/k2/item/26801-nation-at-9-#floodoftreachery-–-no-one-to-arrest-a-‘traitor’?&amp;Itemid=736</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Nitin Gadkari meets Rajnath Singh on visa, citizenship issues</title>
			<link>http://www.newsx.com/national/nation/item/26800-nitin-gadkari-meets-rajnath-singh-on-visa-citizenship-issues</link>
			<description><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/7f948e93fb6709176cd12f1c6df80a3a_Generic.jpg"><img align="right" border="0" src="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/7f948e93fb6709176cd12f1c6df80a3a_S.jpg" alt="nitin-gadkari-meets-rajnath-singh-on-visa-citizenship-issues" /></a><font color="#ff3300"><b>Featured</b></font><p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">New Delhi: A delegation of Sindhi and Bengali communities accompanied by Union Minister Nitin Gadkari on Wednesday met Home Minister Rajnath Singh here and submitted a memorandum to highlight their plight on visa and citizenship related issues.</span></p>

<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Singh assured the delegation that the Home Ministry is committed to address issues faced by them and it had already constituted a Task Force headed by Joint Secretary (Foreigners) to look into such issues.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The Task Force will monitor and expedite processing of citizenship and Long Term Visa (LTV) applications from these minorities from neighbouring countries, an official release said.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The Home Minister informed Gadkari that the cases having complete documents will be processed within two months by the Task Force constituted on September 5.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The MHA Task Force will be soon visiting Lucknow, Nagpur and other cities where such migrants live in large numbers.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The Task Force will camp in those cities and resolve the issues pertaining to visa and citizenship.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">This decision is expected to facilitate the minorities from neighbouring countries who want to stay back in India for fear of religious persecution back home.</span></p>]]></description>
			<dc:creator>Edited by Kirti Dwivedi | Updated: 9:05 IST</dc:creator>
			<pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2014 16:06:46 -0600</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.newsx.com/national/nation/item/26800-nitin-gadkari-meets-rajnath-singh-on-visa-citizenship-issues</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Construction plan for new Kedarpuri to be unveiled soon: CM Harish Rawat</title>
			<link>http://www.newsx.com/national/nation/item/26799-construction-plan-for-new-kedarpuri-to-be-unveiled-soon-cm-harish-rawat</link>
			<description><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/528f1a2c7af187cedd8ad6119b68544d_Generic.jpg"><img align="right" border="0" src="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/528f1a2c7af187cedd8ad6119b68544d_S.jpg" alt="construction-plan-for-new-kedarpuri-to-be-unveiled-soon-cm-harish-rawat" /></a><font color="#ff3300"><b>Featured</b></font><p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Dehradun: An elaborate construction plan for a new township near Kedarnath will be rolled out soon keeping in mind safety of the famed Himalayan shrine as suggested by experts, Uttarakhand Chief Minister Harish Rawat said on Wednesday.</span></p>

<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"We are working on an elaborate plan to construct a new Kedarpuri striking a balance between safety of the shrine and interests of teertha purohits which will soon be rolled out," he told reporters here.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The plan will give due consideration not only to safety measures recommended by the Geological Survey of India but also to commercial interests of teertha purohits whose economy heavily depends on the annual pilgrimage to the Himalayan temple, Rawat said.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The GSI which conducted a study on the reconstruction of Kedarpuri and submitted its recommendations to the state government does not want any construction within five km radius around the shrine for safety reasons.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">However, the teertha purohits whose livelihood is connected to the pilgrimage do not want their business establishments to be located far from the shrine.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"Our effort is to thrash out a middle-of-the-road solution in the construction plan without compromising either safety aspects of the temple and pilgrims or the interests of teertha purohits who will have their business establishments in Kedarpuri among other things," Rawat said.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"We will take care of the interests of teertha purohits, but they should also show sensitivity to our safety concerns and abide by the recommendations made by experts in this regard," he said.</span></p>]]></description>
			<dc:creator>Edited by Kirti Dwivedi | Updated: 8:45 IST</dc:creator>
			<pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2014 15:51:29 -0600</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.newsx.com/national/nation/item/26799-construction-plan-for-new-kedarpuri-to-be-unveiled-soon-cm-harish-rawat</guid>
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
