<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet href="http://www.newsx.com/components/com_obrss/assets/xsl/atom-to-html.xsl" type="text/xsl"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
	<channel>
		<title>rss</title>
		<description><![CDATA[RSS Feed]]></description>
		<link>http://www.newsx.com/</link>
		<lastBuildDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2014 12:50:38 -0600</lastBuildDate>
		<generator>FeedCreator 1.8.3 (obRSS 1.9)</generator>
		<atom:link href="http://www.newsx.com/component/obrss/rss?format=" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
		<image>
			<url>http://www.newsx.com/images/</url>
			<title>rss</title>
			<link>http://www.newsx.com/</link>
			<description>RSS Feed</description>
		</image>
		<item>
			<title>'Make in India' campaign: Govt lacks political honesty, says Congress</title>
			<link>http://www.newsx.com/national/nation/item/27127-make-in-india-campaign-govt-lacks-political-honesty-says-congress</link>
			<description><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/9a0ba6bebd4a360a3bc6bf51b05461ec_Generic.jpg"><img align="right" border="0" src="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/9a0ba6bebd4a360a3bc6bf51b05461ec_S.jpg" alt="make-in-india-campaign-govt-lacks-political-honesty-says-congress" /></a><font color="#ff3300"><b>Featured</b></font><p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">New Delhi: Terming the government's "Make in India" campaign as "mere repackaging and rebranding" of the earlier initiatives taken during the UPA rule, Congress on Thursday accused the Centre of "lacking political honesty".</span></p>

<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"It is surprising that there is nothing new in it. It is just repackaging and rebranding the initiatives that were taken up during the UPA government."</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"This staged event conveys lack of political honesty in correctly informing the nation that these steps were taken by the UPA government," party spokesperson and former commerce minister Anand Sharma said.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">His reaction came after Prime Minister Narendra Modi launched the campaign, saying his government's focus will be on physical infrastructure creation as well as creating a digital network for making India a hub for global manufacturing of goods ranging from cars to softwares, satellites to submarines and paper to power.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Holding that in the last two-three years "companies were looking to move out of country", Modi said the three months of the NDA government has reversed the mood with its focus on easing the process of doing business in the country.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Congress leader Sharma, however, reminded that the Union Cabinet had in October 2011 itself approved the National Manufacturing Policy when the UPA government was in power.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Regarding the Prime Minister's remarks that his government's focus will be on physical infrastructure creation as also on a digital network for making India a hub for global manufacturing of goods, Sharma said that there were already portals of Invest India, which cover every continent and they have already signed 12 MoUs.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"There is a dedicated portal, which was launched at the Africa-India Forum Summit in Addis Ababa in May 2011," the former commerce minister said.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">He said that the government is talking of things like manufacturing and others as if they are new and did not exist in the past, which is "far away from the truth".</span></p>]]></description>
			<dc:creator>Edited by Kirti Dwivedi | Updated: 5:45 IST</dc:creator>
			<pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2014 12:30:20 -0600</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.newsx.com/national/nation/item/27127-make-in-india-campaign-govt-lacks-political-honesty-says-congress</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>#PervertPeepers: Man caught red-handed while videographing college girl bathing at Kancheepuram hostel arrested</title>
			<link>http://www.newsx.com/component/k2/item/27126-#pervertpeepers-man-caught-red-handed-while-videographing-college-girl-bathing-at-kancheepuram-hostel-arrested&amp;Itemid=694</link>
			<description><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/4221dc7e4e685cc137d5948edba54456_Generic.jpg"><img align="right" border="0" src="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/4221dc7e4e685cc137d5948edba54456_S.jpg" alt="#pervertpeepers-man-caught-red-handed-while-videographing-college-girl-bathing-at-kancheepuram-hostel-arrested" /></a><font color="#ff3300"><b>Featured</b></font><p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">TAMIL NADU: Agitated students of Sri Chandrasekharendra Viswa Maha Vidyalaya (SCSVMV) University who caught an electrician red-handed while he was filming a woman taking bath in her hostel washroom on Wednesday morning are extremely disappointed by ‘no action’ taken by the management against him.</span></p>

<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">37-year-old Ravi was at the hostel washroom to fix a geyser when he filmed the girl taking shower. According to the police reports, one of the roommates of the girl being filmed noticed the electrician capturing the video and screamed at him.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">As the students caught hold him, they found obscene videos in his mobile phone and in the mean time, one of the hostel wardens, broke the memory card of the cellphone of Ravi to avoid footage being passed on to other people.</span></p>
<p><iframe src="//www.youtube.com/embed/phtqxTDPDNw" frameborder="0" width="684" height="415" allowfullscreen="true" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"></iframe></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">&nbsp;</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The accused was then handed over to Kanchipuram Taluk Police, however, the police after arresting Ravi and charging him under several sections, including Information Technology Act claimed that they do not have complete evidence that he had videographed the student.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">On the other hand, the authorities from the University remained unavailable for the comment. The university management remains closed until October 6.</span></p>]]></description>
			<dc:creator>Written by Charnamrit Sachdeva</dc:creator>
			<pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2014 12:17:39 -0600</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.newsx.com/component/k2/item/27126-#pervertpeepers-man-caught-red-handed-while-videographing-college-girl-bathing-at-kancheepuram-hostel-arrested&amp;Itemid=694</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>My definition of FDI is 'First Develop India', PM Modi says at 'Make in India' campaign launch</title>
			<link>http://www.newsx.com/national/nation/item/27125-my-definition-of-fdi-is-first-develop-india-pm-modi-says-at-make-in-india-campaign-launch</link>
			<description><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/cbef3c138eb3e03f7d426c0570adfea2_Generic.jpg"><img align="right" border="0" src="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/cbef3c138eb3e03f7d426c0570adfea2_S.jpg" alt="my-definition-of-fdi-is-first-develop-india-pm-modi-says-at-make-in-india-campaign-launch" /></a><font color="#ff3300"><b>Featured</b></font><p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">NEW DELHI: Launching his government's ambitious project to make India a manufacturing hub, Prime Minister Narendra Modi on Thursday promised effective and easy governance to help achieve high growth and creation of jobs.</span></p>

<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Kicking off the "Make in India" campaign, Modi said his government's focus will be on physical infrastructure creation as well as creating a digital network for making India a hub for global manufacturing of goods ranging from cars to softwares, satellites to submarines and paper to power.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"I do not only talk about good governance. I talk about effective governance and easy governance," he said launching the 'Make in India' campaign that was attended by a galaxy of industrialists and business leaders, including Cyrus Mistry, Mukesh Ambani, Azim Premji, Kumar Mangalam Birla, Chanda Kocchar and YC Deveshwar.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Calling upon domestic and international companies to invest in India, the Prime Minister said his government's focus was not only to 'Look East' but also to 'Link West'.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"We want highways. We also want i-ways — information ways for a digital India," Modi said, adding "Make in India is not a slogan, not an invitation".</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Recalling the scenario of last two-three years where "companies were looking to move out of country", he said three months of the NDA government has reversed the mood with its focus on easing the process of doing business in the country.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"Government is committed to development. This is not a political agenda, but an article of faith," he said while stressing on public-private partnership as well as skill development for increasing share of manufacturing in GDP.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Modi said the world is ready to come to Asia and India offers best destination as it is a vibrant democracy with demographic dividend and huge demand.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Modi said the 'Make in India' campaign is a Lion's step towards making the country a destination for global manufacturing.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"We don't have to tell the world our address, there will be a Vasco da Gama in every nook and corner," he said.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Commerce and industry minister Nirmala Sitharaman said series of measures have been taken on ease of doing business and that the government was fully committed to delicensing, deregulating and taking India to high growth trajectory.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Speaking on the occasion, Tata Group chairman Cyrus Mistry stressed the need to reform labour laws. He said the Group was fully committed to investing in India.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Reliance Industries chairman Mukesh Ambani said implementation of GST will make India one market and strengthen overall the 'Make in India' programme.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">He also said that Reliance Industries would be creating 1.25 lakh jobs in next 12-15 month period.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Wipro chief Azim Premji opined that true success of manufacturing lies in ability to service global market.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Stressing on the need to focus on ease of doing business, ICICI Bank CEO &amp; MD Chanda Kochhar said strong manufacturing will enhance country's macro-economic stability besides creating jobs.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Phil Shaw, CEO Lockheed Martin, termed India as "epicentre of innovation" and said his company would be delighted to work with government of India.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">In his address, ITC chairman YC Deveshwar said that problems of inflation and unemployment can be resolved through domestic manufacturing. He said ITC's next investment destination is Madhya Pradesh.</span></p>]]></description>
			<dc:creator>Edited by Kirti Dwivedi | Updated: 5:15 IST</dc:creator>
			<pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2014 11:57:05 -0600</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.newsx.com/national/nation/item/27125-my-definition-of-fdi-is-first-develop-india-pm-modi-says-at-make-in-india-campaign-launch</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Need to break back of inflation, Raghuram Rajan says</title>
			<link>http://www.newsx.com/national/business/item/27124-need-to-break-back-of-inflation-raghuram-rajan-says</link>
			<description><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/79d66f3da25ea16433faf8891d6cedcf_Generic.jpg"><img align="right" border="0" src="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/79d66f3da25ea16433faf8891d6cedcf_S.jpg" alt="need-to-break-back-of-inflation-raghuram-rajan-says" /></a><font color="#ff3300"><b>Featured</b></font><p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Mumbai: Reserve Bank Governor Raghuram Rajan said there was a need to "break the back" of inflation which remains high and controlling it would make the apex bank's position more comfortable.</span></p>

<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"The real problem is inflation that is persistent. We have been emphasising again and again in order to break the back of inflation, we got to break this persistence," Rajan said at the 8th Statistics Day Conference.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">He said once inflation is contained, the RBI will be in a much more comfortable position.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">In August, consumer price index (CPI) or retail inflation eased to 7.8 per cent from 7.96 per cent in July, while the wholesale price index (WPI) moderated to 3.74 per cent from 5.19 per cent in July.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Noting that various economic data available in the country is not very comprehensive, Rajan pressed for an urgent need to improve them.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"We need to improve the quality and quantity and scope of our data, and we are working at it," Rajan said.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">He said India's employment data, which forms the basis for number of decision on monetary policies in many countries, comes with a lag and is not comparable.</span><br /><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"We need to work on getting a timely and comprehensive employment data base, perhaps on the monthly level," Rajan said.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">He said the RBI is working with a National Sample Survey Organisation (NSSO) to create a strong and reliable data base on employment.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">He also said the country does not have a proper producer price index and the RBI would soon create a series.</span></p>]]></description>
			<dc:creator>Edited by Kirti Dwivedi | Updated:  5:05 IST</dc:creator>
			<pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2014 11:48:05 -0600</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.newsx.com/national/business/item/27124-need-to-break-back-of-inflation-raghuram-rajan-says</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Post Delhi incident, Kerala zoo to tighten safety and precautionary measures</title>
			<link>http://www.newsx.com/regional/other-states/item/27123-post-delhi-incident-kerala-zoo-to-tighten-safety-and-precautionary-measures</link>
			<description><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/bd599bcfa77ea7d3a48c98b97a6dfb18_Generic.jpg"><img align="right" border="0" src="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/bd599bcfa77ea7d3a48c98b97a6dfb18_S.jpg" alt="post-delhi-incident-kerala-zoo-to-tighten-safety-and-precautionary-measures" /></a><font color="#ff3300"><b>Featured</b></font><p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Thiruvananthapuram: The century-old zoological park has tightened safety and precautionary measures, days after a youth was mauled to death by a white tiger when he fell into its enclosure at the Delhi Zoo.</span></p>

<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Additional metal sticks would be put in place in between the grills of the cages and steps would be taken to increase height of the walls of enclosures of big cats to prevent onlookers from falling inside, a top zoo official said.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"Taking cue from the Delhi incident, steps have been taken to fix metal sticks in between the grills of the cages to prevent onlookers from going near the animals. With this, visitors will be discouraged to put their hands inside the cages," zoo director B Joseph said.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"There is a tendency among visitors to put their hands inside cages to attract the attention of animals which may lead to tragic incidents. We are also mulling to introduce some modifications in the structure of open enclosures to avoid visitors jumping upon walls to take photos," he said.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The zoo, located in the heart of the city and one of the tourist destinations, would soon have new enclosures for blue bull, barking deer, hyena, jackal and giant malabar squirrel, he said.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Discussions to bring a white tiger from the Delhi zoo are in progress, he added.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Post the arrival of seven anacondas from Sri Lanka, the visitor footfall in the zoo has increased manifold, he said.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"The zoo registered a total earning of Rs 35 lakh this month and this is a record," Joseph said.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The zoo, spread over 55 acres, has a large number of animals such as tiger, leopard, rhinoceros, Asiatic lions and elephants besides a separate avian enclosure with Indian peafowl, white spoonbill and cassowary.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The zoo complex also houses an art museum and gallery, aquarium, 3D theatre and natural history museum.</span></p>]]></description>
			<dc:creator>Edited by Kirti Dwivedi | Updated: 4:55 IST</dc:creator>
			<pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2014 11:43:44 -0600</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.newsx.com/regional/other-states/item/27123-post-delhi-incident-kerala-zoo-to-tighten-safety-and-precautionary-measures</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>25-year-old BJP-Shiv Sena alliance over in Maharashtra?</title>
			<link>http://www.newsx.com/national/top-stories/item/27122-25-year-old-bjp-shiv-sena-alliance-over-in-maharashtra</link>
			<description><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/34c1066b91d061a58635f8249fdf5c21_Generic.jpg"><img align="right" border="0" src="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/34c1066b91d061a58635f8249fdf5c21_S.jpg" alt="25-year-old-bjp-shiv-sena-alliance-over-in-maharashtra" /></a><font color="#ff3300"><b>Featured</b></font><p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">NEW DELHI: While one of the most important alliances of the country; BJP-Shiv Sena in Maharashtra is going topsy-turvy, Shiv Sena on Thursday made strong remarks against the Bharaitya Janata Party (BJP) stating that the saffron party is in a hurry to end the long associated alliance.</span></p>

<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Coming from a meeting with the BJP leaders in Mumbai, the Sena leaders have accused the saffron brigade of abruptly stepping out of the meeting without informing them.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">In the mean time, BJP expressed its disappointment with the proposals shared by Shiv Sena over seat sharing in Maharashtra Assembly Elections and is awaiting the new proposal from its ally.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">However, Shiv Sena continued to claim that it has offered its final proposal to BJP and it was now the national party’s choice to either accept or reject the same.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">On the other hand, as some sources suggest, the BJP-Shiv Sena’s over 25-year-old poll alliance has come to an end but an official announcement is expected by evening today.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Interestingly, BJP President Amit Shah has called off his Mumbai visit extending the speculations of BJP-Sena alliance coming to a split.</span></p>]]></description>
			<dc:creator>Written by Charnamrit Sachdeva</dc:creator>
			<pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2014 11:09:25 -0600</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.newsx.com/national/top-stories/item/27122-25-year-old-bjp-shiv-sena-alliance-over-in-maharashtra</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>J&amp;K govt asks state govt employees to contribute one day's salary to CMRF</title>
			<link>http://www.newsx.com/regional/j-k/item/27121-jk-govt-asks-state-govt-employees-to-contribute-one-days-salary-to-cmrf</link>
			<description><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/86671ad2082f006c95869682d4037842_Generic.jpg"><img align="right" border="0" src="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/86671ad2082f006c95869682d4037842_S.jpg" alt="jk-govt-asks-state-govt-employees-to-contribute-one-days-salary-to-cmrf" /></a><font color="#ff3300"><b>Featured</b></font><p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Jammu: Jammu and and Kashmir government has requested all state government to contribute one day's salary to the Chief Minister's Flood Relief Fund.</span></p>

<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"In order to express solidarity with the flood affected people and to provide succor to them, all the employees of the state government, including the members of the All India Services, are requested to contribute one day's salary to the CM's Flood Relief Fund", an official spokesman said.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The Drawing and Disbursing officers will collect the contributions and deposit them in the said Account, he said.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The contributions are voluntary and it is expected that all the employees will rise to the occasion and contribute to the flood relief sund, spokesman said.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"For this purpose, an account has been opened with the Jammu and Kashmir Bank, with the following details Chief Minister's Flood Relief Fund, J&amp;K Bank, Branch (Moving) Secretariat, Srinagar, Account No. 0110040100001275 IFSC Code: JAKA0MOVING," the spokesman said.</span></p>]]></description>
			<dc:creator>Edited by Kirti Dwivedi | Updated: 4:25 IST</dc:creator>
			<pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2014 11:00:30 -0600</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.newsx.com/regional/j-k/item/27121-jk-govt-asks-state-govt-employees-to-contribute-one-days-salary-to-cmrf</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>PM Modi hopes visit to US will mark a new chapter in the strategic ties</title>
			<link>http://www.newsx.com/national/nation/item/27120-pm-modi-hopes-visit-to-us-will-mark-a-new-chapter-in-the-strategic-ties</link>
			<description><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/97d888d2ea6b753e8aab1f8a49633fc7_Generic.jpg"><img align="right" border="0" src="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/97d888d2ea6b753e8aab1f8a49633fc7_S.jpg" alt="pm-modi-hopes-visit-to-us-will-mark-a-new-chapter-in-the-strategic-ties" /></a><font color="#ff3300"><b>Featured</b></font><p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">New Delhi: Embarking on a high-profile visit, Prime Minister Narendra Modi on Thursday described the US as India's "vital partner" and said that he was confident that his trip will bridge "many divisions" and mark a "new chapter" in the strategic ties.</span></p>

<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">In a pre-deparature statement, Modi said he will discuss with President Barack Obama how the ties can be taken to a "new level" in the interest of the two countries as well as of the world.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Showering praise on Obama, Modi described his life's journey as "a remarkable testimony" to the rights and opportunities that democracies provide, and an "inspiration" for people around the world.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"I see the United States as a vital partner for our national development, drawing especially on the rich possibilities of partnership in education, skills, research, technology and innovation - and, above all, a shared commitment to human values," the Prime Minister said.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">In his address at the 69th session of the UN General Assembly on Saturday, Modi said he will call for a stronger global commitment and more concerted multilateral action in addressing challenges of fragile global economy, turbulence and tension in many parts of the world, growth and spread of terrorism, the Ebola health crisis in Africa, climate change and eradication of poverty.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The Prime Minister said he will call for early adoption of the Post-2015 Development Agenda with a focus on growth, development and elimination of poverty.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"I will also stress the urgency of early reforms in the United Nations, to ensure that it remains relevant and effective in dealing with the challenges of the 21st century," he said.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Noting that India has been showing unwavering commitment to multilateral processes to advance peace and security and promote inclusive economic growth, he said India's contribution to UN peacekeeping operations over decades was a strong testimony of its efforts in helping the world body realise its objectives.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Modi will have a stopover in Frankfurt tonight and will reach New York tomorrow.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Talking about ties with the US, the Prime Minister exuded confidence that his visit will further boost cooperation while noting that the shared values, convergent interests and complementary strengths provide the foundation for natural partnership between the "world's oldest and largest democracies".</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"I will discuss with President Obama how we can use the strength of all that we share and all that we have built so far to take our relationship to a new level in the interest of our two countries and the cause of this world. I am confident that the visit will mark the start of a new chapter in our strategic partnership," he said.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Modi would be meeting as many as 11 top corporate honchos over breakfast on September 29 apart from one-on-one meetings with six more business captains the same day in New York. He will also be participating in a business meet, to be organised by USIBC, that is expected to be attended by 300-400 businessmen in Washington on September 30.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"I look forward to meeting business leaders to invite them to participate more actively in India's economic growth and transformation. This is message that I will also convey to the US business community in Washington DC."</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"My participation in a public event in Central Park in New York on poverty is to focus international attention on this great challenge for humanity and affirm my support for global civic action, especially involving the youth, to address it," said Modi.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Referring to his scheduled address at the Madison Square Garden in New York on September 28, the Prime Minister said he was keenly awaiting the opportunity to meet the Indian- American Community there.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"Their success in diverse fields, their contribution to the United States, their abiding bonds with India and their role as a vibrant bridge between the two largest democracies is a source of pride for us. They serve as a window to our heritage, progress and potential," he said.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Modi would also be meeting the top American political leadership ranging from former president Bill Clinton and former secretary of state Hillary Clinton to Indian-American South Carolina Governor Nikki Haley.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">In Washington, there is a very high level of expectation from Modi's meeting with President Obama.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Obama has gone out of his way to host a rare private dinner for Modi at the White House on September 29, so as to establish a personal relationship with the Indian leader.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Ahead of his main summit at the White House on September 30, Modi would visit the Martin Luther King Memorial and Lincoln Memorial in Washington and pay floral tribute to Mahatma Gandhi's statue in front of the Indian Embassy.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">This would be for the first time that an Indian Prime Minister would have so many public and private engagements during a US visit.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">New York City Mayor Bill de Blasio would make a courtesy call on the Prime Minister shortly after he arrives.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Modi would also meet Nobel laureate Harold Eliot Varmus, who is the current Director of the National Cancer Institute.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">He will pay a visit to the 9/11 memorial in New York on Saturday following which he is expected to drive down to the United Nations headquarters to address the 69th annual session of UN General Assembly.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">He would also meet UN General Secretary Ban Ki-moon.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">On Saturday, Modi would meet former New York Mayor Michael Bloomberg. Modi is interested in seeking Bloomberg's views on the ambitious 100 smart cities project that his government has undertaken after coming to power in May this year.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The same day, the Prime Minister will drive down to the historic Central Park to address the annual Global Citizens Initiative, which aims at building a sustainable world community for all.</span></p>]]></description>
			<dc:creator>Edited by Kirti Dwivedi | Updated: 4:25 IST</dc:creator>
			<pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2014 10:41:04 -0600</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.newsx.com/national/nation/item/27120-pm-modi-hopes-visit-to-us-will-mark-a-new-chapter-in-the-strategic-ties</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Committed to women's reservation in Parliament: Venkiah Naidu </title>
			<link>http://www.newsx.com/national/nation/item/27119-committed-to-womens-reservation-in-parliament-venkiah-naidu</link>
			<description><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/145a7c7a51e115185af2f75513a8a32f_Generic.jpg"><img align="right" border="0" src="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/145a7c7a51e115185af2f75513a8a32f_S.jpg" alt="committed-to-womens-reservation-in-parliament-venkiah-naidu" /></a><font color="#ff3300"><b>Featured</b></font><p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">New Delhi: Parliamentary Affairs Minister M Venkiah Naidu Thursday said the National Democratic Alliance government is committed to raise the representation of women in Parliament.</span></p>

<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"We must get more women in the parliament as soon as possible and the government is committed towards women's reservation," Naidu said while addressing the Assocham Ladies League(ALL) here.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">He hoped the Women's Reservation Bill would be passed in the Lok Sabha soon.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Speaking at the ALL "grassroots women of the decade achievers" awards function, Naidu said: "Today, women are not only making a mark for themselves but helping many others, especially the marginalised and vulnerable sections of society. We must be conscious towards women reservation and get more and more women in parliament."</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Thirty six women leaders from over 16 states were awarded for their work towards society, women empowerment and protection of environment.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"Proactive efforts like this one are needed to highlight women's leadership across the country so that many more women are inspired to engage in society at multiple levels," said Harbeen Arora, ALL global chairperson.</span></p>]]></description>
			<dc:creator>Edited by Kirti Dwivedi | Updated: 3:55 IST</dc:creator>
			<pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2014 10:33:36 -0600</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.newsx.com/national/nation/item/27119-committed-to-womens-reservation-in-parliament-venkiah-naidu</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Ensure justice for dead Afghan civilians, PM Narendra Modi urged</title>
			<link>http://www.newsx.com/national/nation/item/27118-ensure-justice-for-dead-afghan-civilians-pm-narendra-modi-urged</link>
			<description><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/8dab0272153257b0a66964aa6375bdf8_Generic.jpg"><img align="right" border="0" src="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/8dab0272153257b0a66964aa6375bdf8_S.jpg" alt="ensure-justice-for-dead-afghan-civilians-pm-narendra-modi-urged" /></a><font color="#ff3300"><b>Featured</b></font><p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">New Delhi: Around 20,000 Indians have urged Prime Minister Narendra Modi to ask the US to investigate cases of civilian deaths in Afghanistan caused by the country's military operations, a statement said on Thursday.</span></p>

<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">As part of an Amnesty International India campaign, the group wants US President Barack Obama to ensure accountability for human rights violations and apparent war crimes in Afghanistan by US forces.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Modi is scheduled to meet Obama for summit-level talks in Washington September 29-30.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"The families of thousands of Afghan civilians killed by US and NATO forces are still waiting for justice. Modi must call on the US government to investigate cases where Afghan civilians have been killed in US military operations," said Shailesh Rai, programmes director, Amnesty International India.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Documenting the lack of accountability for civilian casualties caused by the US and NATO forces in Afghanistan between 2009 and 2013, a report by Amnesty titled "Left in the Dark" found that even apparent war crimes have gone uninvestigated and unpunished mainly because of the flawed US military justice system.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"The US government must address the unlawful killings of civilians by its forces," said Rai.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"As a key ally of both Afghanistan and the US, India must urge the US to ensure justice and remedy for Afghan civilians," he said.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Amnesty International India also urged Modi to raise other crucial human rights issues with the US authorities during his visit, including the Dow Chemical Company and Union Carbide's disregard for the Indian court summons over the 1984 Bhopal gas tragedy.</span></p>]]></description>
			<dc:creator>Edited by Kirti Dwivedi | Updated: 3:45 IST</dc:creator>
			<pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2014 10:27:04 -0600</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.newsx.com/national/nation/item/27118-ensure-justice-for-dead-afghan-civilians-pm-narendra-modi-urged</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Nixing of coal block allocations will end 'policy paralysis': Goa CM</title>
			<link>http://www.newsx.com/national/nation/item/27117-nixing-of-coal-block-allocations-will-end-policy-paralysis-goa-cm</link>
			<description><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/e108d7e7ed1804e008c368cf81064842_Generic.jpg"><img align="right" border="0" src="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/e108d7e7ed1804e008c368cf81064842_S.jpg" alt="nixing-of-coal-block-allocations-will-end-policy-paralysis-goa-cm" /></a><font color="#ff3300"><b>Featured</b></font><p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Panaji: Goa Chief Minister Manohar Parrikar has said that the cancellation of coal block allocations by the Supreme Court will set aside the 'policy paralysis' which had affected the Centre for a decade.</span></p>

<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"The policy paralysis faced by the Central government for the last eight to 10 years has been set aside by the SC judgement on the coal blocks."</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"(It is the) first time that the Central government has approached the SC asking it to bring finality to the issue," Parrikar said during the 'Make In India' programme organised by Confederation of Indian Industries (CII) here.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"The decision-making process always requires finality to any pending issue. Now it is up to the Union government how to revive the leases and what is the amount to be fixed (for the same)," he said.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The SC order, which has cancelled 214 of the 218 leases given out since 1993, also includes a lease belonging to the Goa government in Chhattisgarh, which was supposed to supply coal for power generation.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Parrikar said that the Centre can have a different view as far as leases owned by the state governments are concerned.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"As far as some leases owned by states like Goa, the Union government may enact a law which might say that leases do not require to follow the procedure. This could be a small amendment to the law," he said, adding that leases owned by three state governments have been affected by the SC order.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The Chief Minister rejected talk that the scrapping of leases would be a setback for power generation for the state.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"The power generating unit has been already set up in Chhattisgarh and is supplying electricity to Goa. If you give indigenous coal (mined from the leased block) to it (the power plant), then you can get it cheaper, and if you don't give indigenous coal then the rate can increase by 70 paise," he said.</span></p>]]></description>
			<dc:creator>Edited by Priyanka Kukreja || Updated: 14:50 IST</dc:creator>
			<pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2014 09:13:25 -0600</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.newsx.com/national/nation/item/27117-nixing-of-coal-block-allocations-will-end-policy-paralysis-goa-cm</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Monitoring Chinese activity in Indian Ocean: Navy Chief</title>
			<link>http://www.newsx.com/national/defence/item/27116-monitoring-chinese-activity-in-indian-ocean-navy-chief</link>
			<description><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/e5fd9c777d72c44418dd910474e7683c_Generic.jpg"><img align="right" border="0" src="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/e5fd9c777d72c44418dd910474e7683c_S.jpg" alt="monitoring-chinese-activity-in-indian-ocean-navy-chief" /></a><font color="#ff3300"><b>Featured</b></font><p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">New Delhi: Against the backdrop of incursions in Ladakh, Navy Thursday said it was continuously monitoring the activity of the Chinese Navy in the Indian Ocean Region (IOR).</span></p>

<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"Chinese warships are deployed in the Indian Ocean Region and we are continuously monitoring them and see what is their deployment. Along with it, our aircraft, submarines and warships are always deployed to face any challenge.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"....IOR is our area of operations and we see what is Chinese deployment in IOR and how it can create challenges for us and how we can face them....We are always ready," Navy Chief Admiral Robin Dhowan told reporters here.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">He was asked to comment on the situation in Chumar in Ladakh where Chinese troops intruded more than two weeks back and are engaged in stand-off with Indian soldiers on the sidelines of the golden jubilee of the Navy Warship Design Bureau.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The Navy Chief said only the Army was competent to comment on the particular incident in the Ladakh region of Jammu and Kashmir.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">He said it was the Navy's responsibility to look after Indian maritime interests in IOR. "We are always ready to face them. Our economic interests are there in the maritime region and their protection is also our responsibility."</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">In the recent times, the Chinese Navy has been deploying its warships and submarines in IOR.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Asked about the proposed maritime dialogue between India and China this year, he said the two sides have been cooperating in terms of port visits and anti-piracy operations in the Gulf of Aden. Asked if the Indian Navy would be required to protect country's economic interests in the oil exploration activity planned with Vietnam, Dhowan said the Navy will show its presence wherever it is required.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">He said the Navy's eastern fleet had recently gone to Vladivostok in Russia and then sailed to the Pacific Ocean to hold exercises with the US and Japanese Navy under the Malabar series of war games.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">On the future of the deal to buy 16 multirole helicopters for warships, the Navy Chief said the case was in the final stages and expressed the hope that it would be finalised soon.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">On the final inquiry report about INS Sindhurakshak submarine which sank in August last year killing 18 personnel, he said it happened "perhaps because certain Standard Operating Procedures were not followed which could have led to the accident".</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The Navy has submitted the Board of Inquiry (BoI) report on the accident to the Defence Ministry and it will be studied before any final decision is taken by the force.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">To a query on the proposed second Indigenous Aircraft Carrier, he said the force is preparing the Detailed Project Report for it and it will be submitted to the Defence Ministry very soon for the required sanctions.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">He termed as "speculative" the suggestion that the proposed warship would be propelled by nuclear power.</span></p>]]></description>
			<dc:creator>Edited by Priyanka Kukreja || Updated: 14:20 IST</dc:creator>
			<pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2014 09:05:06 -0600</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.newsx.com/national/defence/item/27116-monitoring-chinese-activity-in-indian-ocean-navy-chief</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Sushma Swaraj begins US visit, meets counterparts from 7 nations</title>
			<link>http://www.newsx.com/national/nation/item/27115-sushma-swaraj-begins-us-visit-meets-counterparts-from-7-nations</link>
			<description><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/b2fd12edbd26263a328a8109d031e26f_Generic.jpg"><img align="right" border="0" src="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/b2fd12edbd26263a328a8109d031e26f_S.jpg" alt="sushma-swaraj-begins-us-visit-meets-counterparts-from-7-nations" /></a><font color="#ff3300"><b>Featured</b></font><p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">New York: External Affairs Minister Sushma Swaraj has begun her 10-day trip to the US with back-to-back meetings here with her counterparts from seven nations, including the UK and the Maldives.</span></p>

<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Swaraj met the leaders at the United Nations headquarters yesterday.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">She met UK Secretary of State Philip Hammond, Sudanese Minister of Foreign Affairs Ali Ahmed Karti, Maldives Foreign Affairs Minister Dunya Maumoon, Norwegian Foreign Affairs Minister Borge Brende, Kyrgyz Foreign Affairs Minister Abdyldaev Erlan Bekeshovich, Greece Deputy Prime Minister Evangelos Venizelos and Nigerian Foreign Affairs Minister Aminu Wali.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Swaraj, however, did not speak to the media after the meetings.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The External Affairs Minister is scheduled to meet nearly 100 foreign ministers during her visit to the US and will also join the delegation of Prime Minister Narendra Modi, who will reach New York on September 26.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Ahead of Prime Minister Modi's arrival, Swaraj will participate in the meetings with the Foreign Ministers of the G4, IBSA, BRICS, Commonwealth and SAARC.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Her bilateral meetings will be with Brazilian Foreign Affairs Minister Luis Alberto Figueiredo Machado, Bangladeshi Foreign Affairs Minister Abul Hassan Mahmud Ali and Chinese Foreign Affairs Minister Wang Yi.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">In the Commonwealth and SAARC meetings, Swaraj could meet Pakistan's National Security and Foreign Affairs Adviser Sartaj Aziz.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">On September 26, before Modi reaches New York, Swaraj will participate in a bilateral meeting with Egyptian Foreign Affairs Minister Sameh Hassan Shoukry besides participating in a ministerial level meeting of the Committee on Palestine.</span></p>]]></description>
			<dc:creator>Edited by Priyanka Kukreja || Updated: 14:20 IST</dc:creator>
			<pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2014 08:40:03 -0600</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.newsx.com/national/nation/item/27115-sushma-swaraj-begins-us-visit-meets-counterparts-from-7-nations</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>New technique to diagnose autism in babies</title>
			<link>http://www.newsx.com/life-style/health/item/27114-new-technique-to-diagnose-autism-in-babies</link>
			<description><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/ffdc31a6c3c53d160cdab0ec2c8eaca6_Generic.jpg"><img align="right" border="0" src="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/ffdc31a6c3c53d160cdab0ec2c8eaca6_S.jpg" alt="new-technique-to-diagnose-autism-in-babies" /></a><font color="#ff3300"><b>Featured</b></font><p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Scientists have developed a new technique to diagnose autism in babies as young as 12 months.</span></p>

<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Dr Josephine Barbaro from Australia’s La Trobe University has developed an accurate set of “red flag” markers of the condition,which include a failure by babies to make consistent eye contact,to smile,show their toys to others,to play social games,point and respond when their name is called.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Barbaro is training medical experts around the globe in the use of her diagnostic method on children under two years of age.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">“All typically developing babies are pre-wired to be social,look at other people’s faces,learn from them and copy what they’re doing. Children with autism are not doing this -and we can now accurately identify this at a much younger age and take action,” Barbaro said.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Barbaro and her team are training doctors in Tianjin in China,as part of an Australia-China Science and Research Fund Group Mission.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">They have helped to train 300 doctors monitor children’s development using the early autism identification programme.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Based on these preliminary findings,the Tianjin government has agreed to conduct autism surveillance using Barbaro’s programme for every child born in the city for the next seven years.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The team is also training healthcare workers in Poland,Korea,Japan and Bangladesh.</span></p>]]></description>
			<dc:creator>Edited by Priyanka Kukreja || Updated: 14:10 IST</dc:creator>
			<pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2014 08:29:44 -0600</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.newsx.com/life-style/health/item/27114-new-technique-to-diagnose-autism-in-babies</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>New iPhones run into software, bending complaints</title>
			<link>http://www.newsx.com/gadgets/mobiles/item/27113-new-iphones-run-into-software-bending-complaints</link>
			<description><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/5659e168f947dc55ba86e6f83a872eb9_Generic.jpg"><img align="right" border="0" src="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/5659e168f947dc55ba86e6f83a872eb9_S.jpg" alt="new-iphones-run-into-software-bending-complaints" /></a><font color="#ff3300"><b>Featured</b></font><p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">San Francisco: Apple's newest iPhones have ran into some glitches after users complained that a new software update blocked their calls, and a video circulated to suggest that the larger of the two new models is vulnerable to bending.</span></p>

<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Apple said it would stop providing the software update, which it began distributing yesterday morning to fix several issues in last week's iOS 8 operating system for iPhones and iPads.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The decision to pull the update came after some people complained on Twitter and in Apple user chatrooms that the update, dubbed iOS 8.0.1, rendered their phones unable to make calls and caused problems with a feature that lets people unlock their phones with their fingerprint.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">By midday yesterday, Apple announced that it was investigating the reports and would issue advice to users "as quickly as we can." Users are still able to the upgrade older phones to last week's version of iOS 8, which Apple said has already been downloaded to nearly half of all iOS devices.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Some tech blogs reported the update only seemed to cause problems for the latest phone models -- the new iPhone 6 and 6 Plus. It's not uncommon for new software to contain bugs that have to be fixed with subsequent releases.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Meanwhile, social media sites were buzzing yesterday with reports that the aluminum shell of the iPhone 6 Plus is vulnerable to bending.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Some Twitter users claimed their phones showed a slight curving at one end after several hours in a pants pocket. With a 5.5-inch screen, the iPhone 6 Plus is slightly longer and thinner than other iPhone models.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">It's not clear how widespread the complaints are. One YouTube video showed someone bending an iPhone 6 Plus by applying extended pressure with his hands -- not from normal sitting.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Both the iPhone 6 and the 6 Plus were given high ratings in a recent "breakability" test sponsored by SquareTrade, a San Francisco firm that sells protection plans to consumers for their electronic devices. That test did not include bending, and SquareTrade plans further tests.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Apple did not comment on the reports of bending.</span></p>]]></description>
			<dc:creator>Edited by Priyanka Kukreja || Updated: 13:40 IST</dc:creator>
			<pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2014 08:10:30 -0600</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.newsx.com/gadgets/mobiles/item/27113-new-iphones-run-into-software-bending-complaints</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Tremendous demand for tickets for PM Modi's address at Madison Square Garden</title>
			<link>http://www.newsx.com/world/us/item/27112-tremendous-demand-for-tickets-for-pm-modis-address-at-madison-square-garden</link>
			<description><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/353d74dd793d453975e460cff5630226_Generic.jpg"><img align="right" border="0" src="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/353d74dd793d453975e460cff5630226_S.jpg" alt="tremendous-demand-for-tickets-for-pm-modis-address-at-madison-square-garden" /></a><font color="#ff3300"><b>Featured</b></font><p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">New York: Indian Americans have been queuing up to buy the tickets for Prime Minister Narendra Modi's address at Madison Square Garden on September 28, which will be one of the highlights of his five-day bilateral visit to US.</span></p>

<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Organizers say that due to the tremendous demand for tickets they had to restrict almost 450 associations that became 'welcoming partners'.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"We had tremendous demands for the tickets, we knew this will be overwhelming and it is still continuing. We have to restrict almost 450 associations from the country that became welcoming partners. Almost 15,000 free tickets have been distributed through the associations as well as individuals by lottery," said Bharat Barai, president of the Indian-American Community Foundation and chief organiser of the Madison Square Garden event</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Barai added that almost 200 community members and almost 800-1,000 volunteers have worked hard for the event's success.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"On 28th September in the morning, people will start arriving here at 8.30 or so because we have to move around 18,000 people through security and it will be airport grade security, because there are also going to be 40-50 Congressmen and senators," said Barai.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"There will be a cultural program which will start at 10 in the morning. There will be a different programme starting at around 11 in the morning. The Congressmen and Senators will arrive here and will have a private meeting in a separate area with the PM," he added.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Asked about the unprecedented level of enthusiasm for the Prime Minister's visit, Barai said, "Most Indian Americans perceive this Prime Minister to be a very progressive one, who has put people first. He has vision, he has mission and he wants to deliver for the benefit of the people."</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"In a country where there has been lot of corruption, lot of nepotism and lot of permit quota control; this is breath of fresh air," he added.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Barai also described the Madison Square Garden as a very technologically advanced venue.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"The seats are beautiful, the arena arrangement inside is very beautiful and it accommodates almost 20,000 people," he added.</span></p>]]></description>
			<dc:creator>Edited by Priyanka Kukreja || Updated: 12:30 IST</dc:creator>
			<pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2014 06:53:51 -0600</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.newsx.com/world/us/item/27112-tremendous-demand-for-tickets-for-pm-modis-address-at-madison-square-garden</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>PM Narendra Modi wishes people on Navratri</title>
			<link>http://www.newsx.com/national/nation/item/27111-pm-narendra-modi-wishes-people-on-navratri</link>
			<description><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/5655a6feae500803d4637df8e844dad5_Generic.jpg"><img align="right" border="0" src="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/5655a6feae500803d4637df8e844dad5_S.jpg" alt="pm-narendra-modi-wishes-people-on-navratri" /></a><font color="#ff3300"><b>Featured</b></font><p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">New Delhi: Prime Minister Narendra Modi on Thursday greeted people on the occasion of the holy period of Navratri, saying may Maa Jagdamba keep inspiring us to serve the poorest of the poor.</span></p>

<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"As the auspicious festival of Navratri begins, I convey my warm greetings to everyone. We bow to Maa Jagdamba and seek her blessings. May Maa Jagdamba enrich our lives with strength, well-being, good health and may she keep inspiring us to serve the poorest of the poor," the Prime Minister said in his message.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The holy period of Navratri commences today and will conclude on Oct. 2.</span></p>]]></description>
			<dc:creator>Edited by Priyanka Kukreja || Updated:12:10 IST</dc:creator>
			<pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2014 06:33:18 -0600</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.newsx.com/national/nation/item/27111-pm-narendra-modi-wishes-people-on-navratri</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Sensex recovers 69 points in early trade</title>
			<link>http://www.newsx.com/national/business/item/27110-sensex-recovers-69-points-in-early-trade</link>
			<description><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/b2f7647314734b78f2e8d0635e896890_Generic.jpg"><img align="right" border="0" src="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/b2f7647314734b78f2e8d0635e896890_S.jpg" alt="sensex-recovers-69-points-in-early-trade" /></a><font color="#ff3300"><b>Featured</b></font><p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Mumbai: The benchmark BSE Sensex recovered by over 69 points in early trade today on selective buying by investors and covering-up of short positions by speculators in view of monthly expiry in the derivatives segment amidst positive global cues.</span></p>

<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The 30-share barometer, which had lost over 462 points in the previous two sessions, recovered by 69.51 points, or 0.25 per cent, to 26,814.20.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Also, the National Stock Exchange index Nifty gained 16.90 points, or 0.21 per cent, to 8,019.30.</span></p>]]></description>
			<dc:creator>Edited by Priyanka Kukreja || Updated: 11:50 IST</dc:creator>
			<pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2014 06:09:17 -0600</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.newsx.com/national/business/item/27110-sensex-recovers-69-points-in-early-trade</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>PM Modi to open Pravasi Bharatiya Divas, Vibrant Summit in January</title>
			<link>http://www.newsx.com/national/nation/item/27109-pm-modi-to-open-pravasi-bharatiya-divas-vibrant-summit-in-january</link>
			<description><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/ac6c10d6b7a28f9ab991a5fcc9290b2b_Generic.jpg"><img align="right" border="0" src="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/ac6c10d6b7a28f9ab991a5fcc9290b2b_S.jpg" alt="pm-modi-to-open-pravasi-bharatiya-divas-vibrant-summit-in-january" /></a><font color="#ff3300"><b>Featured</b></font><p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Gandhinagar: Prime Minister Narendra Modi will be in Gujarat on January 8 and 11 next year to inaugurate the Pravasi Bhartiya Divas as well as the Vibrant Gujarat Global Investor Summit-2015 respectively.</span></p>

<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"On January 8, the Prime Minister will be in Gujarat to inaugurate Pravasi Bhartiya Diwas, which will conclude the next day. On January 11, Modi will also open the Vibrant Gujarat Summit," Gujarat Finance Minister Saurabh Patel told reporters here today.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The 7th edition of the Vibrant Summit will be held between January 11 and 13 at the Mahatma Mandir here.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The state government has also organised a parallel exhibition called 'Global Trade Show' at Helipad Ground here between January 7 and 13, he said.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Patel said that after inaugurating the Summit, Modi will have lunch with the global business leaders, which will be followed by seminars.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"This time seven countries are participating as partner countries in the Vibrant Summit. These countries are Japan, Australia, Singapore, the UK, Netherlands, Canada and South Africa. Delegates from the USA and China are also scheduled to take part in the seminars.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"We have invited CEOs of Fortune-500 companies, chief ministers of different states, union ministers, heads of academic institutions, economists and other important dignitaries from world over for the Summit," Patel said.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">In order to promote the event in Gujarat as well as in other states, road shows will be organised in the coming months.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">According to Patel, the road shows will be held in Surat, Bharuch, Rajkot, Gandhidham, Vapi, Vadodara, Bhavnagar and Jamnagar. "We have also planned a road show in Mumbai to promote the summit," he said.</span></p>]]></description>
			<dc:creator>Edited by Priyanka Kukreja || Update: 9:50 IST</dc:creator>
			<pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2014 05:55:05 -0600</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.newsx.com/national/nation/item/27109-pm-modi-to-open-pravasi-bharatiya-divas-vibrant-summit-in-january</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>India siding with US against China can be disastrous: Natwar</title>
			<link>http://www.newsx.com/national/nation/item/27108-india-siding-with-us-against-china-can-be-disastrous-natwar</link>
			<description><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/de4b7a79ea9953397b35c0464a4e1ffe_Generic.jpg"><img align="right" border="0" src="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/de4b7a79ea9953397b35c0464a4e1ffe_S.jpg" alt="india-siding-with-us-against-china-can-be-disastrous-natwar" /></a><font color="#ff3300"><b>Featured</b></font><p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Jaipur: A day before Prime Minister Narendra Modi embarks on his maiden visit to the United States, former external affairs minister Natwar Singh on Wednesday said that India should not unite with the US against China as it could be "disastrous".</span></p>

<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"The era of superpower has gone. America is not the only superpower and its influence has come down. America would like India to come together against China but it could be disastrous," he said during an event here.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Lauding Modi for taking "good steps" in the area of foreign policy, Singh exuded confidence that the Prime Minister's visit to the United Nations and Washington will be successful.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Singh said that India will play an extremely important global role in the coming years and the present NDA government is faced with several challenges.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"Modi has taken good steps in the area of foreign policy and relations after he became Prime Minister that includes inviting heads of neighboring nations to his oath taking ceremony, attending the BRICS summit and now he will have the opportunity to meet foreign ministers and heads of several nations in the United Nations Assembly and then visit Washington," he said, adding that "the Prime Minister should visit Russia and further strengthen relations."</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Modi will embark on a five-day high profile visit from tomorrow to the US during which he will have a power-packed schedule of meetings - official, business and public - apart from addressing the UN General Assembly on September 27 and bilateral talks with US President Barack Obama.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Singh, a former diplomat, said that before becoming the Prime Minister, Modi met him in February and discussed foreign issues and he told him that there was a need to strengthen relations with neighboring countries.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">On relations with China, he said both India and China are mature country but the foreign relations of China are far ahead from India as it existed in traditional form.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Singh said that relations with Pakistan were "accident prone" and people of that country want good ties with India.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Criticizing former prime minister Manmohan Singh on foreign policy matters, he said, "Manmohan Singh is a gentleman, but not a leader".</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">While claiming to be an admirer of former prime minister Jawaharlal Nehru, Singh highlighted three mistakes he made in context of foreign policy. He said that taking the Kashmir dispute to UN, failure in resolving border disputes with China and not taking up the opportunity of having a permanent seat in the UN Security Council were some mistakes Nehru made.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Singh was speaking at a lecture on the present NDA government's foreign policy, organised by Prabha Khaitan Foundation in memory of novelist and poet Prabha Khaitan.</span></p>]]></description>
			<dc:creator>Edited by Priyanka Kukreja || Updated: 9:50 IST</dc:creator>
			<pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2014 05:33:37 -0600</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.newsx.com/national/nation/item/27108-india-siding-with-us-against-china-can-be-disastrous-natwar</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Live: PM Modi kickstarts #MakeInIndia campaign</title>
			<link>http://www.newsx.com/national/top-stories/item/27107-pm-narendra-modi-to-launch-make-in-india-campaign-today</link>
			<description><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/2724a70b8b943320c96d7ac0c5af02a3_Generic.jpg"><img align="right" border="0" src="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/2724a70b8b943320c96d7ac0c5af02a3_S.jpg" alt="pm-narendra-modi-to-launch-make-in-india-campaign-today" /></a><font color="#ff3300"><b>Featured</b></font><p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Prime Minister Narendra Modi on Thursday launches his next initiative, ‘Make In India’ campaign in the National Capital which is expected to offer a collective push to the manufacturing structure in India and will seek greater foreign investment in the country.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Central government creates a separate Twitter handle for 'Make in India' campaign</span></p>

<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;"><strong>Here are the Live updates</strong>:</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong><span style="font-size: 10pt;">11:50 AM: Modi launches ‘Make In India’ campaign</span></strong></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">PM launches the official website - a one-stop resource for everyone who wants to #MakeinIndia. Addressing a major gathering, Prime Minister Narendra Modi said, “We do not want any industrialist being forced to leave India and can say that we have been able to bring about a change in last few months. One of the key issues of the country is trust. Why do we not trust our fellow countrymen? I want to change this. Our government's mantra is that we want to trust each and every Indian. The atmosphere of trust can change a lot of things”</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">“I was sad to see people not willing to invest in India. Who is the Government for? It is for every Indian. It is for the poorest of the poor. My definition of FDI for the people of India is First Develop India. FDI is a responsibility for the people of India,” Modi said.</span></p>
<p><iframe src="//www.youtube.com/embed/YkcINDdzME8" frameborder="0" width="684" height="415" allowfullscreen="true" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"></iframe></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Discussing the purchasing and spending power along with manufacturing and development, Modi said, “We have to create opportunities of employment. If the poor get jobs the purchasing power of families will increase. We have to increase manufacturing and at the same time ensure that the benefits reach the youth of our nation. Industry does not come when there are too many incentive schemes. We have to create a development &amp; growth oriented environment. After the successful Mars Orbiter Mission, I am certain that nobody can question the abilities and the talent of India.”</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong><span style="font-size: 10pt;">11:00 AM: Ministers and Industrialists address the gathering</span></strong></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Nirmala Sitharaman, Commerce &amp; Industries Minister and Ravi Shankar Prasad, Law Minister are sharing the stage with him. “’Make in India’ is not a slogan but a mission to be accomplished with single minded commitment, about new processes”, said Sitharaman and added, “We are fully committed to make India a global manufacturing hub.”</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">On the other hand, Cyrus Mistry of Tata Sons while addressing the gathering, said, “India has 2 strategic advantages- our human capital and a market which affords scale and growth.” “Under leadership of PM Modi, 'Make in India' is bringing together industry and government,” he added.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">“We realized the potential of India very early and we must remove factors affecting manufacturing competitiveness,” expressed Kenichi Ayukawa of Maruti Suzuki.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">RIL Chief Mukesh Ambani while addressing the big gathering including PM Modi said, “Today is a historic day for the Indian industry. India has been blessed with a leader like PM Modi.”</span></p>
<p><iframe src="//www.youtube.com/embed/AIzAKYPlml8" frameborder="0" width="684" height="415" allowfullscreen="true" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"></iframe></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">“'Make in India' is an opportunity given to thousands of Indians and we commit ourselves to 'Make in India' movement. When the world looks at India, let nobody have a doubt that we can be competitive on global terms.”</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Wipro founder Azim Premji addressing the gathering said, “Indian products reflect low-cost innovative designs. True success of manufacturing lies in the ability to service global markets.”</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Also, ICICI CEO Chanda Kochhar addressed the gathering and said, “’Make in India’ will be next growth driver for India. We need to give the young generation proper training and need to improve ease of doing business and access to infrastructure. Manufacturing will strengthen the macro-economic stability of the country.”</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">While pledging to support the ‘Make In India’ campaign of PM Narendra Modi, Kochhar further said, “As a nation we need to focus on 4 areas- rules &amp; regulations, infrastructure, policies and skill training. #MakeinIndia can add 90 million jobs in the next decade.”</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong><span style="font-size: 10pt;">10: 30 AM: PM arrives for the launch</span></strong></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Prime Minister Narendra Modi arrived at Vigyan Bhawan in New Delhi for the launch of ‘Make In India’ campaign where he is welcomed by the top notch people of the country.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">10:30 AM: Make In India Campaign to launch today!</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Prime Minister Narendra Modi is all set to launch the much awaited ‘Make In India’ campaign which will enhance the manufacturing system of the country.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The launch event is attended by top industrialist Chanda Kochchar, Kumar Mangalam Birla, Azim Premji and Kiran Majumdar Shaw.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">At his Independence Day speech, Prime Minister Narendra Modi had pitched that he intends to improve the manufacturing in India to create jobs to revive growth and a month and half later, his government is launching the big initiative at both state and national level.</span></p>]]></description>
			<dc:creator>Written by Charnamrit Sachdeva</dc:creator>
			<pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2014 04:18:18 -0600</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.newsx.com/national/top-stories/item/27107-pm-narendra-modi-to-launch-make-in-india-campaign-today</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Committee to suggest steps for improving communication network during disasters</title>
			<link>http://www.newsx.com/national/nation/item/27106-committee-to-suggest-steps-for-improving-communication-network-during-disasters</link>
			<description><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/bb7fc077dd59b242c66537e561ffa213_Generic.jpg"><img align="right" border="0" src="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/bb7fc077dd59b242c66537e561ffa213_S.jpg" alt="committee-to-suggest-steps-for-improving-communication-network-during-disasters" /></a><font color="#ff3300"><b>Featured</b></font><p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">New Delhi: In view of total collapse of the communication system during recent floods in Jammu and Kashmir, a committee has been formed to make suggestions for providing a dedicated network to ensure uninterrupted communication during natural disasters.</span></p>

<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">This was conveyed today during a meeting chaired by Union Home Minister Rajnath Singh along with Information and Technology Minister Ravi Shankar Prasad.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The meeting was informed that a committee had been set up in the Department of Technology which will submit its report within two months for improving communication network during disasters.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The Home Minister directed to setup a robust communication system that would withstand natural disasters by a greater degree.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Singh said the existing system can be further improved based on national and international experiences in such situations.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The meeting resolved that disasters managers should be provided with satellite phones and priority calls should be given to those involved in rescue and relief operations during natural disasters.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The participants discussed the experiences of difficulties faced in the field of communication during the recent floods in Jammu and Kashmir and Uttarakhand's natural disaster last year.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The recent floods had seen failure of communication network completely in Jammu and Kashmir.</span></p>]]></description>
			<dc:creator>Edited by Priyanka Kukreja || Updated: 9:30 IST</dc:creator>
			<pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2014 03:56:24 -0600</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.newsx.com/national/nation/item/27106-committee-to-suggest-steps-for-improving-communication-network-during-disasters</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>CBI registers case against MCI officials, carries out searches</title>
			<link>http://www.newsx.com/national/nation/item/27105-cbi-registers-case-against-mci-officials-carries-out-searches</link>
			<description><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/62b6d1ee8a3c8ff30b9519b1c4aac22b_Generic.jpg"><img align="right" border="0" src="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/62b6d1ee8a3c8ff30b9519b1c4aac22b_S.jpg" alt="cbi-registers-case-against-mci-officials-carries-out-searches" /></a><font color="#ff3300"><b>Featured</b></font><p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">New Delhi: The CBI on Wednesday carried out searches at the official and residential premises of senior Medical Council of India officials and a Medical College in Thiruvananthapurm after registering a case of alleged cheating and corruption against them.</span></p>

<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The probe agency conducted searches at the residential and official premises of MCI Additional Secretary Prasanna Raj, Deputy Secretary Anshu Sethi Bajaj, ex-consultant Madhu Handa and Principal of Somervell Medical College, Samson Nessaih, CBI sources said.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"The CBI has registered a case against Additional Secretary, Deputy Secretary, then Assistant Secretary of MCI and a Principal of private Medical College at Thiruvanthapuram (Kerala)...Under section 120B (criminal conspiracy) and 420 (cheating) of IPC and 13(2) read with 13(1)(d) of Prevention of Corruption Act, 1988...," CBI spokesperson said here today.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">She said that it is alleged old and pending application of said medical college, seeking PG seats was dealt and processed unauthorisedly in MCI and Letter of Permission issued after the last date of March 31, 2012.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"It is further alleged that the deficiencies pointed out by the assessors in their inspection report in 2011 still prevailed in said medical college and machines which were to be installed before sending the compliance to MCI were actually installed after that date," the spokesperson said.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">She said the bank guarantee which was mentioned to have been submitted by the said college to MCI along with the compliance letter was not actually submitted on time.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"The said college was not granted Letter of Permission (LoP) for preceding year because of the said reasons. The undue favours were allegedly shown to said medical college on the part of the MCI officials by ignoring the relevant regulations, and necessary permissions were granted which resulted in significant pecuniary benefits to the private medical college," CBI alleged.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The spokesperson alleged the Principal of said medical college in conspiracy with MCI officials allegedly submitted false information for the purpose of getting the required permission and hence cheated the MCI.</span></p>]]></description>
			<dc:creator>Edited by Priyanka Kukreja || Updated: 9:30 IST</dc:creator>
			<pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2014 03:46:55 -0600</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.newsx.com/national/nation/item/27105-cbi-registers-case-against-mci-officials-carries-out-searches</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Sushant Singh Rajput denies walking out of Paani</title>
			<link>http://www.newsx.com/showbiz/celebrities/item/27104-sushant-singh-rajput-denies-walking-out-of-paani</link>
			<description><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/cdab93504f4b56d5a6282aec3c85075d_Generic.jpg"><img align="right" border="0" src="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/cdab93504f4b56d5a6282aec3c85075d_S.jpg" alt="sushant-singh-rajput-denies-walking-out-of-paani" /></a><font color="#ff3300"><b>Featured</b></font><p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Actor Sushant Singh Rajput has denied reports that he had dropped out of Shekhar Kapur's ambitious project.</span></p>

<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"We were very amused to read speculations that Sushant Singh Rajput is not in Paani due to a variety of absurd reasons. There is absolutely NO truth to it. Sushant keeps a low profile and let's his work speak for itself. He has recently completed 'Detective Byomkesh Bakshi' and is deep in preparations for 'Paani' given the scale of the film," said his spokesperson.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Sushant Singh Rajput started his acting journey as a TV star with 'Pavitra Rishta' before moving to Bollywood with films like 'Shuddh Desi Romance' and 'Kai Po Che'.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Shekhar Kapur's long-gestating project is set in a futuristic world where water is controlled by multinational companies.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Two lovers spark a war in their bid to bring water back to people. The film is being produced by Yash Raj Films for a 2015 release. 'Black' actress Ayesha Kapoor has reportedly been finalised as the female lead.</span></p>]]></description>
			<dc:creator>Edited by Priyanka Kukreja || Updated: 9:10 IST</dc:creator>
			<pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2014 03:35:03 -0600</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.newsx.com/showbiz/celebrities/item/27104-sushant-singh-rajput-denies-walking-out-of-paani</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>BJP leaders to monitor cleanliness drive</title>
			<link>http://www.newsx.com/cities/item/27103-bjp-leaders-to-monitor-cleanliness-drive</link>
			<description><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/e9146107ee3aa6bd68b18b0c0bc6445c_Generic.jpg"><img align="right" border="0" src="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/e9146107ee3aa6bd68b18b0c0bc6445c_S.jpg" alt="bjp-leaders-to-monitor-cleanliness-drive" /></a><font color="#ff3300"><b>Featured</b></font><p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">New Delhi: In keeping with Prime Minister Narendra Modi's vision of clean India, BJP's MPs, MLAs, Municipal Mayors and Councillors in Delhi have been given responsibility to make the sanitation campaign a success.</span></p>

<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"With an aim to make sanitation campaign a success, party's MPs, MLAs, municiple mayors and councillors have been asked to personally monitor it in their respective areas, mohallas," a senior BJP leader said.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Some BJP leaders led by Delhi BJP chief Satish Upadhyay today apprised Urban Development minister M Venkaiah Naidu of arrangements being made regarding the campaign, which will be initiated from October 2, in the national capital.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"All the safai karamcharis and inspectors will attend their work on October 2. It is being ensured by the sanitation department that the trucks and trolleys working for the disposal of garbage also provide their services," he added.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Besides, Delhi government yesterday announced that it would take action against people found littering and also impound vehicles parked illegally as part of its 'Swachchha Bharat Abhiyan', which will kick start from October 2.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"Strict action will be taken against the people littering the area by the Municipal Magistrate. Also, vehicles which are found parked illegally on roadsides and footpath will be impounded," a Delhi government official said.</span></p>]]></description>
			<dc:creator>Edited by Priyanka Kukreja || Updated: 8:40 IST</dc:creator>
			<pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2014 03:06:49 -0600</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.newsx.com/cities/item/27103-bjp-leaders-to-monitor-cleanliness-drive</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Shiv Sena says won't budge from 151 Assembly seats demand</title>
			<link>http://www.newsx.com/regional/maharashtra/item/27102-shiv-sena-says-wont-budge-from-151-assembly-seats-demand</link>
			<description><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/e953e336bef00b7d27a561f8d3236594_Generic.jpg"><img align="right" border="0" src="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/e953e336bef00b7d27a561f8d3236594_S.jpg" alt="shiv-sena-says-wont-budge-from-151-assembly-seats-demand" /></a><font color="#ff3300"><b>Featured</b></font><p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Mumbai: Amid the tussle over seat-sharing between the saffron-led alliance partners in Maharashtra, Shiv Sena on Wednesday night asserted it will not step back from its demand for 151 asssembly seats "come what may".</span></p>

<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"Shiv Sena is a very big party in Maharashtra. And that is why we will definitely fight elections on 151 assembly seats. Even (Sena chief) Uddhavji has made this very clear. We will not go back on this decision of ours come what may," party spokesman Sanjay Raut said here.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Sena is insisting on a formula under which it will get to contest 151 seats, BJP 130 and other allies seven. The state has 288-member assembly. However, the minor partners have expressed displeasure over Sena's formula and are demanding more seats for themselves.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Raut, who is also an MP, was talking to reporters on the sidelines of his meeting with Shiv Sena President Uddhav Thackeray at the latter's residence in suburban Bandra.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Rejecting suggestions of minor parties walking out of the six-member `mahayuti' (Sena-BJP-led grand Opposition bloc), he said they are intelligent enough to stick together and fight the October 15 assembly polls as one force.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"All our alliance partners, be it Raju Shetti (Swabhimani Shetkari Sangathana), Mahadev Jankar (Rashtriya Samaj Party), Vinayak Mete (Shiv Sangram) or Ramdas Athavale (RPI) are intelligent enough to know that we need to fight the elections together. And we are sincerely holding talks to sort out the issue on seat-sharing," Raut said.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The senior Sena leader said it will be unfortunate if any of the parties quits the alliance cobbled ahead of the April-May Lok Sabha polls, which it swept in Maharashtra, winning 42 of the 48 seats.</span></p>]]></description>
			<dc:creator>Edited by Priyanka Kukreja || Updated: 8:30 IST</dc:creator>
			<pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2014 02:54:04 -0600</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.newsx.com/regional/maharashtra/item/27102-shiv-sena-says-wont-budge-from-151-assembly-seats-demand</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Vaishnodevi shrine ready for Navratras amid tight security</title>
			<link>http://www.newsx.com/national/nation/item/27101-vaishnodevi-shrine-ready-for-navratras-amid-tight-security</link>
			<description><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/8910bfe0625df13c5baf52669f0be499_Generic.jpg"><img align="right" border="0" src="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/8910bfe0625df13c5baf52669f0be499_S.jpg" alt="vaishnodevi-shrine-ready-for-navratras-amid-tight-security" /></a><font color="#ff3300"><b>Featured</b></font><p>Katra: The cave shrine of Mata Vaishnodevi in Jammu and Kashmir's Trikuta Hills is decked up for the Navratras, which will begin on Thursday amid tight security.</p>
<p>The Katra base camp and the route to the shrine will have multi-pronged security with the Army patrolling the Bhawan. CCTV monitoring and heavy checking and frisking at entry and exit points will be ensured during Navratras, Chief Executive Officer, Shri Mata Vaishno Devi Shrine Board, Mandeep K Bhandari said.</p>
<p>"The Bhawan of Mata Vaishno Deviji, Atka and the areas surrounding it have been decorated with flowers. All the routes leading to the cave shrine have been fully maintained for movement of pilgrims apart from ensuring sufficient supplies of provisions, food and water on the way," he said.</p>
<p>The flowers have been brought from various parts of the country and some have also been imported from New Zealand, Australia, Canada and England.</p>
<p>The Bhawan will witness a 'Mahayagya' round-the-clock with the beginning of the Navratras and elaborate arrangements have been made for the large number of pilgrims who are likely to visit the shrine during this period.</p>
<p>However, in view of the devastating floods and the loss of lives in Jammu and Kashmir, this year's 'Navratra' festival is likely to be a low key affair sans festivities.</p>
<p>"The event shall be kept simple and on a low key," Bhandari said.</p>
<p>The CEO said the yatra, which was temporarily suspended on September 4 because of incessant heavy rains, was resumed on September 8 and since then it is proceeding smoothly.</p>
<p>In view of militant activities across the border and unprecedented floods, police officers have been asked to ensure comprehensive deployment of force, Inspector General of Police (IGP), Jammu Zone, Rajesh Kumar said, adding there will be regular patrolling by Army, CRPF and Police.</p>]]></description>
			<dc:creator>Edited by Priyanka Kukreja || Updated: 7:40 IST</dc:creator>
			<pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2014 02:12:22 -0600</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.newsx.com/national/nation/item/27101-vaishnodevi-shrine-ready-for-navratras-amid-tight-security</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Nation at 9: #ModiInUS – The 3rd mega exclusive</title>
			<link>http://www.newsx.com/component/k2/item/27100-nation-at-9-#modiinus-–-the-3rd-mega-exclusive&amp;Itemid=736</link>
			<description><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/9ceaa933b07b74e3d1e557972a68fe99_Generic.jpg"><img align="right" border="0" src="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/9ceaa933b07b74e3d1e557972a68fe99_S.jpg" alt="nation-at-9-#modiinus-–-the-3rd-mega-exclusive" /></a><font color="#ff3300"><b>Featured</b></font><p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Prime Minister Narendra Modi would be among a dozen world leaders who will attend a global festival on September 27 in the sprawling Central Park in New York that will feature music icon Jay Z and many other big stars.</span></p>

<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Apart from PM Modi, leaders such as UN Secretary General Ban Ki-moon, Bangladesh Prime Minister Sheikh Hasina, World Bank President Jim Yong Kim, Prime Minister of Norway Erna Solberg and Nepalese Prime Minister Sushil Koirala would attend the 2014 Global Citizen Festival.</span></p>
<p><iframe src="//www.youtube.com/embed/q3_0AauQHDc" frameborder="0" width="684" height="415" allowfullscreen="true" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"></iframe></p>]]></description>
			<dc:creator>NewsX Bureau</dc:creator>
			<pubDate>Wed, 24 Sep 2014 17:09:00 -0600</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.newsx.com/component/k2/item/27100-nation-at-9-#modiinus-–-the-3rd-mega-exclusive&amp;Itemid=736</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Prime Minister Narendra Modi  embarks on US visit tomorrow</title>
			<link>http://www.newsx.com/national/nation/item/27099-prime-minister-narendra-modi-embarks-on-us-visit-tomorrow</link>
			<description><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/b5853a1cf9e8c5212cf2376b687a6d9b_Generic.jpg"><img align="right" border="0" src="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/b5853a1cf9e8c5212cf2376b687a6d9b_S.jpg" alt="prime-minister-narendra-modi-embarks-on-us-visit-tomorrow" /></a><font color="#ff3300"><b>Featured</b></font><p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">NEW DELHI: Prime Minister Narendra Modi will embark on a five-day high profile visit from Thursday to the US during which he will have a power-packed schedule of meetings — official, business and public — apart from addressing the UN general assembly on September 27 and bilateral talks with President Barack Obama.</span></p>

<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Expecting a "substantive" outcome, India said, "We see Prime Minister Narendra Modi's first visit to New York and Washington as a signal of India's abiding commitment to multilateralism and of a desire to build on a growing convergences in Indo-US ties in the areas where we can work together and in areas where we can do more for each other."</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Modi would also be holding three bilateral meetings with neighbours — Sri Lankan President Mahinda Rajapaksa, Nepal Prime Minister Sushil Koirala and Bangladesh Prime Minister Sheikh Hasina. There are no plans to meet Pakistani counterpart Nawaz Sharif.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The Indian side has also indicated Modi's "dietary preferences" given that the Prime Minister would be observing the nine-day Navratri fast during his trip.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Modi will hold talks with over 15 top American corporate honchos, including top executives of Google, Boeing and General Electric, as India looks to attract more overseas investments.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Apart from meeting 11 top corporate honchos over breakfast on September 29, the Prime Minister will have one- on-one meetings with six more business captains same day in New York.</span></p>]]></description>
			<dc:creator>Edited by Kirti Dwivedi | Updated: 8:25 IST</dc:creator>
			<pubDate>Wed, 24 Sep 2014 15:24:14 -0600</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.newsx.com/national/nation/item/27099-prime-minister-narendra-modi-embarks-on-us-visit-tomorrow</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>#DateWithMars: ISRO’s Mars mission successful, India makes history, PM Modi congratulates scientists</title>
			<link>http://www.newsx.com/national/top-stories/item/27063-indias-datewithmars-today-mangalyaan-to-enter-mars-orbit</link>
			<description><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/d0025d8a73be91db35d6f0e7665f457a_Generic.jpg"><img align="right" border="0" src="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/d0025d8a73be91db35d6f0e7665f457a_S.jpg" alt="indias-datewithmars-today-mangalyaan-to-enter-mars-orbit" /></a><font color="#ff3300"><b>Featured</b></font><p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">&nbsp;BANGALORE: In its maiden attempt, India has created a history on Wednesday by becoming the first country to successfully getting a spacecraft into the Martian orbit.</span></p>

<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The Mars Orbiter Mission (MOM) of Indian Space Research Organization (ISRO) began orbiting the Red Planet at 7:47 AM but only 12 minutes later, due to the time delay in radio signals travelling the 680 million km, that that scientists at Isro Telemetry, Tracking and Command Network in Bangalore, could erupt in joy as Prime Minister Narendra Modi stood a happy witness to the mission.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Adding to the suspense, for the maximum time, the main engine was firing, 20 of the 24 crucial minutes – MOM was hiding behind the Mars.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The scientists involved in the mission have been waiting for 300 days as MOM toured on through space but the last 54 minutes were nearly intolerable. It was during this span that the orbiter first readjusted itself and then fired its engine and thrusters for approximately 24 minutes to get into the Mars orbit.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">There were not much for the scientists to do in their action at the ground station as over 10 days ago, had uplinked all the commands for the manoeuvres to the spacecraft, to which, MOM like a subservient baby followed it perfectly.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><br /><span style="font-size: 10pt;"><iframe src="//www.youtube.com/embed/1yBXkLPS3MM" frameborder="0" width="684" height="415" allowfullscreen="true" style="font-size: 13px; line-height: 20px; display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"></iframe></span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">&nbsp;</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;"><strong>PM Modi congratulates ISRO Scientists</strong></span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Over the great victory, Prime Minister Narendra Modi congratulated the ISRO scientists. In his speech in Bangalore, PM Modi applauding the scientists expressed, “MOM never disappoints.” “India is the first country to get this right in the first attempt,” he said.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">While discussing on the scientific achievement, Narendra Modi turned philosophical and said, “Jab kaam mangal hota hai, irade mangal hote hain, tho yaatra bhi mangal hota hai (When the task is holy, and so is the intention, the journey has to be a success).”</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">He further in his congratulatory speech said, “Unless you enter the waters you don't learn to swim. Risk tho lena hi padtha hai (You have to take risks.”</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Encouraging the scientist to keep up the good work and become an idol to the future generation, PM said, “Despite our many limitations, we have succeeded. It is a shining symbol of what we are capable of as a nation ... A successful space programme generates efforts across multiple domains.”</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">He stressed on the fact that the scientists in India are changing the lives of the people and speed of achievements in India.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;"><strong>MOM’s Journey!</strong></span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">MOM has had a perfect journey since November 5, 2013 when PSLV-C25 lifted off from Sriharikota with the spacecraft in its nosecone.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The first litmus test came on Monday while it was to hold out time-tagged instructions to reignite its main engine which had been still for approximately 300 days ever since it left the Earth orbit on December 1, 2013.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">MOM ensured of doing this in style, burning for the designated four seconds to show that the engine is in fine shape. On Wednesday, it confirmed its buoyancy.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">For the scientific studies, as it travels around the Mars on an elliptical orbit with the closest point around 420km and the farthest around 80,000km, MOM will employ five equipment that collectively weight 15kg.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">India is not the first country to make the experiment as several countries before India have launched their Mars mission, but only 21 out of 51 have remained successful.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">India has now joined the Martian league with USA, Russia and the European Space Agency and out of these only European Space Agency has been able to get its orbiter right in the first attempt, but at the same time India may claim a first as the agency is accumulation of several countries.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;"><strong>Twitter takes over!</strong></span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Amid the big news making headlines, it was time for a treat for the Twitter lovers to stay updated with the latest news as they witnessed a great exchange of tweets between the United States Nasa’s Curiosity Rover and India’s ISRO’s Mard Orbiter immediately after the victorious inclusion of India’s satellite into the Mars Orbit today.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">While Nasa’s latest mission on Twitter welcomed the ISRO’s Mars Orbiter by saying, “Namaste, @MarsOrbiter! Congratulations to @ISRO and India's first interplanetary mission upon achieving Mars orbit,” the ISRO’s Mars Orbiter immediately reverted, “</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Howdy @MarsCuriosity? Keep in touch. I'll be around”.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">However, @MarsCuriosity is the official account of the NASA's Mars mission; the @MarsOrbiter belongs to the ISRO.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">&nbsp;</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">&nbsp;</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;"><strong style="font-size: 10pt; line-height: 1.5;">&nbsp;</strong></span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;"><strong style="font-size: 10pt; line-height: 1.5;">&nbsp;</strong></span></p>]]></description>
			<dc:creator>Written by Charnamrit Sachdeva</dc:creator>
			<pubDate>Wed, 24 Sep 2014 14:46:57 -0600</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.newsx.com/national/top-stories/item/27063-indias-datewithmars-today-mangalyaan-to-enter-mars-orbit</guid>
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
