<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet href="http://www.newsx.com/components/com_obrss/assets/xsl/atom-to-html.xsl" type="text/xsl"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
	<channel>
		<title>rss</title>
		<description><![CDATA[RSS Feed]]></description>
		<link>http://www.newsx.com/</link>
		<lastBuildDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2014 15:06:31 -0600</lastBuildDate>
		<generator>FeedCreator 1.8.3 (obRSS 1.9)</generator>
		<atom:link href="http://www.newsx.com/component/obrss/rss?format=" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
		<image>
			<url>http://www.newsx.com/images/</url>
			<title>rss</title>
			<link>http://www.newsx.com/</link>
			<description>RSS Feed</description>
		</image>
		<item>
			<title>Eye care tips for Tech-addicts!</title>
			<link>http://www.newsx.com/life-style/health/item/26796-eye-care-tips-for-tech-addicts</link>
			<description><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/3bdbe45cabbb60647b504fcec5fd8c90_Generic.jpg"><img align="right" border="0" src="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/3bdbe45cabbb60647b504fcec5fd8c90_S.jpg" alt="eye-care-tips-for-tech-addicts" /></a><font color="#ff3300"><b>Featured</b></font><p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">In an age driven by technology and digitization, it is hard not to become slave to gadgets and machines. Our heavy dependence on digital devices like computers, smart-phones, tablets, laptops and television is today both a necessity and an addiction. Our eyes bear a heavy brunt of this tendency, they get tired, and weary; they may become itchy or red.</span></p>

<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;"><strong>But don’t you worry</strong>; you need not have to cut down on your tech habits as here are some simple ways to keep your eyes safe while you continue to enjoy your passion.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;"><strong>Routine checkups</strong>: Make it a habit to visit an ophthalmologist once a year if you live and breathe on computer and other smart devices. Get your eyes examined and seek advice, particularly if you are experiencing redness or itchiness. Keep checking if your vision needs correction.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;"><strong>Reduce glare</strong>: Opt for installing anti-glare screen on your monitor and if, possible, paint your walls with a darker color having matte finish to avoid reflections or glare on them. Glare or reflections on walls and computer screen add to the eye strain.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;"><strong>Take a break</strong>: Working on a computer continuously at a longer stretch can harm your eyes. Do not just stare on the screens for hours at a stretch. Take a few minutes break every hour, take a walk around your office, stretch your arms, body and back. It helps in avoiding vision syndrome and also prevents body ache. Stand up and go for a mini-stroll, this will help in releasing muscle tension as well as eye strain.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;"><strong>Use protective lenses in spectacles</strong>: Getting the right spectacle lenses will make it easier for you. Contact lenses lose moisture and tend to dry out during prolonged hours of computer work. It will serve you well if you opt for spectacle lenses that give you protection. Essilor’s Crizal Prevencia is the first lens to offer selective protection against harmful blue light and UV rays that computer and smartphone screens emit. This lens lets in essential light which your eyes need to function properly while filtering out the harmful light.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;"><strong>Exercise and relax your eyes</strong>: You can follow the palming method. Rub the palms against each other till they get warm and then cup your eyes with your palms for one minute to give them relief. To soothe your eyes from constantly looking at your computer screen, you can follow the “20-20-20” rule. Look away from your computer screen in every 20 minutes for 20 seconds and stare at a distant object.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;"><strong>Use proper lightening:</strong> You eyes start developing strain because of extra brightness. You can avoid working with fluorescent lights on in your computer. You can use floor lamps for appropriate visibility.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;"><strong>Water wonder</strong>: Water really can do wonders, you can splash water on your eyes to afresh them and water will help cleansing the fatigue. You are advised to drink water at regular intervals as this will towards reducing the puffiness in your eyes caused due to prolonged working hours while sitting in front of your computer.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;"><strong>Sit straight and upright</strong>: Inappropriate posture during computer work will contribute towards adding to vision deficiency. Structure your workstation and chair to the coordinating levels. Fix up ergonomic furniture to enable you to position your computer screen 20 to 24 inches from your eyes. The centre focus of the screen should be about 10 to 15 degrees below your eyes to stabilize your neck and head at a right place. You can use a desk lamp but make sure it should not be too bright for your eyes.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;"><strong>Healthy diet:</strong> Balanced diet enriched with portions of Vitamin A, C and E proves to be the most vital supplement for ensuring eye health. Eat fruits like tomatoes, spinach, green leafy vegetables, kale, citrus and dairy products. Doctors have also recommended intake of fish reach in omega-3 fatty acids, such as salmon and tuna.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong><span style="font-size: 10pt;">*This article has been authored by Shiv Kumar, CEO, Essilor India</span></strong></p>]]></description>
			<dc:creator>NewsX Bureau</dc:creator>
			<pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2014 14:44:59 -0600</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.newsx.com/life-style/health/item/26796-eye-care-tips-for-tech-addicts</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Tibet should be core issue for India, China: Tibetan PM says</title>
			<link>http://www.newsx.com/national/nation/item/26795-tibet-should-be-core-issue-for-india-china-tibetan-pm-says</link>
			<description><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/1031b4c994f8da4bcd6a2d850efc18ea_Generic.jpg"><img align="right" border="0" src="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/1031b4c994f8da4bcd6a2d850efc18ea_S.jpg" alt="tibet-should-be-core-issue-for-india-china-tibetan-pm-says" /></a><font color="#ff3300"><b>Featured</b></font><p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Dharamsala: Tibetan Prime Minister-in-exile Lobsang Sangay Wednesday said Tibet should be a core issue for India in its dealings with China.</span></p>

<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"It has always been our hope that the Indian government makes Tibet a core issue in its dealings with China and urges the Chinese government to resolve the issue of Tibet peacefully through dialogue," Sangay said in an interview to IANS.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The statement by the elected head of the Central Tibetan Administration (CTA), based in this hill town in Himachal Pradesh, came on the day Chinese President Xi Jinping arrived in India on a three-day official visit during which trade and investment are likely to top the agenda of talks with Prime Minister Narendra Modi.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">He said the CTA was not challenging the sovereignty or the territorial integrity of China but seeking "genuine autonomy" for the people in Tibet.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"Yes, we will immensely appreciate it if Prime Minister Modi raises the issue of human rights violations in Tibet," he said.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The political successor of the Dalai Lama said China has been propagating a so-called happy and prosperous Tibet while the ground reality depicts gross violations of human rights.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"The Chinese police firing on a group of Tibetan demonstrators in Shugpa village demonstrates the denial of basic human rights to Tibetans inside Tibet," he said.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Responding to the growing proximity between the two Asian giants, India and China, Sangay said: "A growing proximity of positive contacts between India and China, and for India to have good relations with all countries is welcomed by all Tibetans."</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"We don't want to be an obstruction in those relations. What Tibetans put forward is a 'win-win' solution for both India and China. Therefore, Tibet should be a core issue for India and China," he said.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">On the continuing deadlock over talks between the Dalai Lama's envoys and the Chinese authorities over granting more autonomy for Tibet, the 46-year-old Sangay said: "We remain hopeful that, as before, dialogue will continue between the envoys of the Dalai Lama and representatives of the Chinese government."</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"What we seek is an administrative mechanism to bring all the Tibetan-inhabited areas under one single administration. Bringing all the Tibetans currently living in designated Tibetan autonomous areas within a single autonomous administrative unit is entirely in accordance with article 4 of the Chinese constitution and the law on regional national autonomy."</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Asking the Tibetans in exile, who staged demonstrations in India over the visit of the Chinese president, to have legal, peaceful and dignified protests, Sangay said: "As always, a few groups have held some kinds of events whenever Chinese leaders have come to India."</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The fact is that India is a vibrant democracy and freedom of speech is a part and parcel of democracy. However, any event has to be legal, peaceful and dignified, he said.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">With the Dalai Lama stepping down from diplomacy and active politics, the elected leader of Tibetan people has acquired added stature.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The Dalai Lama has lived in India since fleeing his homeland in 1959. The Tibetan administration in exile is based in this northern Indian hill town.</span></p>]]></description>
			<dc:creator>Edited by Kirti Dwivedi | Updated: 7:25 IST</dc:creator>
			<pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2014 14:03:29 -0600</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.newsx.com/national/nation/item/26795-tibet-should-be-core-issue-for-india-china-tibetan-pm-says</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>EPFO not considering any suggestion to invest in stock markets</title>
			<link>http://www.newsx.com/national/business/item/26794-epfo-not-considering-any-suggestion-to-invest-in-stock-markets</link>
			<description><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/465ec70cdf5d8d805bddd0851949434c_Generic.jpg"><img align="right" border="0" src="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/465ec70cdf5d8d805bddd0851949434c_S.jpg" alt="epfo-not-considering-any-suggestion-to-invest-in-stock-markets" /></a><font color="#ff3300"><b>Featured</b></font><p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">New Delhi: Retirement fund manager EPFO on Wednesday said that it is not considering any proposal to invest a part of its huge corpus of around Rs 6 lakh crore in stock markets.</span></p>

<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"We are not considering any proposal to invest in stock markets or equity at present," Employees' Provident Fund Organisation's (EPFO) Central Provident Fund Commissioner KK Jalan said.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">He said this in response to media reports that EPFO has no alternative but to change its investment norms to invest in equity markets.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Jalan said, "During the recent meeting of the EPFO's trustees, proposed pattern of investment by Finance Ministry was discussed and the Board was not in favour of investing in equities and Exchange Traded Funds (ETFs)."</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">However, the EPFO's apex decision making body, the Central Board of Trustees headed by the Labour Minister, had decided to recommend making the pattern more flexible to further increase the percentage of investment in government securities.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The Finance Ministry has been pitching for EPFO funds to be invested in the equity markets to maximise their yields. However, following strong opposition from unions in view of the volatile nature of stocks, EPFO did not opt for equity investment.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The Finance Ministry had allowed the EPFO to invest up to 5 per cent of its funds in equity in 2005 and enhanced the limit to 15 per cent in 2008.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">A recent notification by the Labour Ministry allows the EPFO to invest up to 5 per cent of its funds in money market instruments, including units of mutual funds and equity-linked schemes regulated by the Securities and Exchange Board of India.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The EPFO has more than 5 crore subscribers across the country. It provided interest of 8.75 per cent on PF deposits in 2013-14. The EPFO trustees have recently decided to pay interest of 8.75 per cent in this financial year.</span></p>]]></description>
			<dc:creator>Edited by Kirti Dwivedi | Updated: 7:35 IST</dc:creator>
			<pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2014 13:39:54 -0600</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.newsx.com/national/business/item/26794-epfo-not-considering-any-suggestion-to-invest-in-stock-markets</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Bypolls defeat: BJP should consider bringing Varun back, Maneka Gandhi says</title>
			<link>http://www.newsx.com/national/nation/item/26793-bypolls-defeat-bjp-should-consider-bringing-varun-back-maneka-gandhi-says</link>
			<description><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/a0222c9e8ff1eeb653c7f2a760d09b82_Generic.jpg"><img align="right" border="0" src="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/a0222c9e8ff1eeb653c7f2a760d09b82_S.jpg" alt="bypolls-defeat-bjp-should-consider-bringing-varun-back-maneka-gandhi-says" /></a><font color="#ff3300"><b>Featured</b></font><p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">New Delhi: A day after the Bharatiya Janata Party (BJP) lost seats in bypoll elections in Uttar Pradesh, Gujarat and Rajasthan - states where it swept the Lok Sabha elections - Union Minister Maneka Gandhi has said that the party should consider bringing back her son and Sultanpur MP Varun Gandhi back to Uttar Pradesh to boost the party's position there.</span></p>

<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Out of the 11 Assembly seats in Uttar Pradesh which went to the polls, the BJP won three while the Samajwadi Party swept the rest.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Varun Gandhi was sidelined by the party's top brass last month, after he was dropped from BJP president Amit Shah's core team.</span></p>]]></description>
			<dc:creator>Edited by Kirti Dwivedi | Updated: 4:55 IST</dc:creator>
			<pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2014 12:47:01 -0600</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.newsx.com/national/nation/item/26793-bypolls-defeat-bjp-should-consider-bringing-varun-back-maneka-gandhi-says</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>BSNL to offer free 2GB deta on select Micromax devices</title>
			<link>http://www.newsx.com/national/business/item/26792-bsnl-to-offer-free-2gb-deta-on-select-micromax-devices</link>
			<description><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/bd5e7001eee927c678172715c20a052e_Generic.jpg"><img align="right" border="0" src="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/bd5e7001eee927c678172715c20a052e_S.jpg" alt="bsnl-to-offer-free-2gb-deta-on-select-micromax-devices" /></a><font color="#ff3300"><b>Featured</b></font><p><span style="font-size: 10pt;">New Delhi: Domestic handset maker Micromax said it has partnered state-run telecom firm BSNL to offer free Internet access on select devices in a bid to drive data usage in the country.</span></p>

<p><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Under the partnership, BSNL will bundle free data usage of up to 2GB per quarter for 12 months on smartphones, free voice calls (on net) on feature phones and other freebies on purchase of Micromax tablet and data cards.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The offer will be available on six Micromax devices - X070, X088 (feature phones), P410i (tablet), MMX377G (datacard), A37 and A37B (smartphones).</span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"We are delighted to partner with BSNL, as this collaboration will be an excellent unification of BSNL's offerings and Micromax's design capability thus enabling millions of Indian consumers to enjoy seamless connectivity through data usage, affordable call rates and other VAS services," Micromax CEO Vineet Taneja said.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The partnership will further provide a major boost to better connectivity and Internet adoption as BSNL's pan-India network coupled with our devices, backed by a strong channel and retail presence which will take these offerings across length and breadth of the country, he added.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"The association will create immense opportunities for customers by offering them high speed 3G data. BSNL has already provided 3G coverage in more than 2,300 cities and towns of India and is committed to provide 3G coverage to additional towns," BSNL CMD A N Rai said.</span></p>]]></description>
			<dc:creator>Edited by Kirti Dwivedi | Updated: 4:45 IST</dc:creator>
			<pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2014 12:37:41 -0600</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.newsx.com/national/business/item/26792-bsnl-to-offer-free-2gb-deta-on-select-micromax-devices</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>JKLF chief Yasin Malik denies hijacking rescue boat in flood-hit J&amp;K</title>
			<link>http://www.newsx.com/national/nation/item/26791-jklf-chief-yasin-malik-denies-hijacking-rescue-boat-in-flood-hit-jk</link>
			<description><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/24ccbfd625ab27870d4f91e406e1cca8_Generic.jpg"><img align="right" border="0" src="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/24ccbfd625ab27870d4f91e406e1cca8_S.jpg" alt="jklf-chief-yasin-malik-denies-hijacking-rescue-boat-in-flood-hit-jk" /></a><font color="#ff3300"><b>Featured</b></font><p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Srinagar: Jammu Kashmir Liberation Front(JKLF) chief Yasin Malik, who has been accused of snatching anIndian Armyboat meant for relief work in flood-hit Jammu and Kashmir, has denied all such allegations.</span></p>

<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">As per reports, Malik termed the reports on him disrupting the relief and rescue work as just a poisonous propaganda by the Indian media</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Malik reportedly said that if charges against him are proven true, he will quit Kashmiri politics.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">He, however, did not clarify from where did he get the boat and relief material, pictures of which have been circulated on social media.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The separatist leader also went on to accuse the National Disaster Response Force (NDRF) of not distributing relief material, claiming people are facing shortages.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Reports had earlier claimed that Malik was in a September 13 video seen disrupting relief and rescue operations in a flood-hit area.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">As per reports, the JKLF chief and his aides hijacked a rescue boat in order to 'personally' distribute relief items.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Malik and his supporters were seen in a video - available on social media as well as broadcast by an English news channel – asking relief workers to abandon a boat so that they could carry out the rescue operation themselves. The separatists were even seen allegedly forcing ailing lady patients to disembark from the Army relief boat.</span></p>]]></description>
			<dc:creator>Edited by Kirti Dwivedi | Updated: 4:35 IST</dc:creator>
			<pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2014 12:14:45 -0600</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.newsx.com/national/nation/item/26791-jklf-chief-yasin-malik-denies-hijacking-rescue-boat-in-flood-hit-jk</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Six BJP youth wing leaders booked for assault</title>
			<link>http://www.newsx.com/regional/up/item/26790-six-bjp-youth-wing-leaders-booked-for-assault</link>
			<description><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/c9c926ec49b1c31a8e118a8b8b27b6ab_Generic.jpg"><img align="right" border="0" src="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/c9c926ec49b1c31a8e118a8b8b27b6ab_S.jpg" alt="six-bjp-youth-wing-leaders-booked-for-assault" /></a><font color="#ff3300"><b>Featured</b></font><p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Aligarh: Six BJP Yuva Morcha leaders along with 40 party activists have been booked for allegedly assaulting a 24-year-old man, who intended to marry a girl from a different community, police said here on Wednesday.</span></p>

<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The incident took place yesterday evening, when the six persons and 40 other unnamed activists of the party's youth wing allegedly attacked the man, at Nauranganad locality in Gandhi Park area, police said.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The man, who belonged to a minority community had come to meet her woman friend and her parents apparently over marriage plan, and the party workers took it as a case of 'love jihad', after which he was allegedly assaulted and his motorcycle was also set afire, according to police.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">They (workers) were, however, informed by the girl and her family that the two "lovers" intended to get married and they that they were fully aware of the identity of youth for the past four years, police said.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">An FIR has been lodged against six leaders -- Manoj Sharma, Lalitesh Lodhi, Rajat Thakur, Aman Gupta, Yatin Dixit, K K Goswami and 40 unnamed activists, police said.</span></p>]]></description>
			<dc:creator>Edited by Kirti Dwivedi | Updated: 4:15 IST</dc:creator>
			<pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2014 12:02:23 -0600</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.newsx.com/regional/up/item/26790-six-bjp-youth-wing-leaders-booked-for-assault</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>UAE to send urgent humanitarian assistance to J&amp;K flood victims</title>
			<link>http://www.newsx.com/national/nation/item/26789-uae-to-send-urgent-humanitarian-assistance-to-jk-flood-victims</link>
			<description><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/dd307e79925da9448a4c8abb89d50adf_Generic.jpg"><img align="right" border="0" src="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/dd307e79925da9448a4c8abb89d50adf_S.jpg" alt="uae-to-send-urgent-humanitarian-assistance-to-jk-flood-victims" /></a><font color="#ff3300"><b>Featured</b></font><p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Dubai: The UAE will send urgent humanitarian assistance to the flood victims in Jammu and Kashmir, where millions of people have been impacted by the worst floods in over a century.</span></p>

<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Sheikh Hamdan bin Zayed Al Nahyan, Ruler's Representative in the Western Region and Chairman of Emirates Red Crescent (ERC), has ordered authorities to send urgent humanitarian assistance to the victims of the disaster.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Official news agency WAM reported that Sheikh Hamdan has ordered immediate help to meet the basic needs of the people affected by floods in Jammu and Kashmir, where more than 200 people have died and tens of thousands affected by the floods.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Mohammed Ateeq Al Falahi, Secretary-General of the ERC, said that Sheikh Hamdan's directives come in the light of his keenness to alleviate the suffering of the victims and improve living conditions there, indicating that he is closely following the repercussions of floods in India.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">He said that ERC would work to ensure delivery of humanitarian aid to the victims from the local market.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Floods triggered by incessant rain in Jammu and Kashmir in the first week of September has caused widespread damage to property and infrastructure in the state.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Jammu and Kashmir Chief Minister Omar Abdullah has described the current floods in the state as the worst in 109 years.</span></p>]]></description>
			<dc:creator>Edited by Kirti Dwivedi | Updated: 3:55 IST</dc:creator>
			<pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2014 11:46:48 -0600</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.newsx.com/national/nation/item/26789-uae-to-send-urgent-humanitarian-assistance-to-jk-flood-victims</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>CPI condemns separatists for hindering Kashmir flood relief operations</title>
			<link>http://www.newsx.com/national/nation/item/26788-cpi-condemns-separatists-for-hindering-kashmir-flood-relief-operations</link>
			<description><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/bb44f5c49aa030fd1c46c694a7fd08af_Generic.jpg"><img align="right" border="0" src="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/bb44f5c49aa030fd1c46c694a7fd08af_S.jpg" alt="cpi-condemns-separatists-for-hindering-kashmir-flood-relief-operations" /></a><font color="#ff3300"><b>Featured</b></font><p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">New Delhi: Communist Party of India (CPI) leader D Raja on Wednesday deplored separatists for allegedly creating roadblocks in army rescue efforts in flood-hit Jammu and Kashmir.</span></p>

<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Raja remarks came after reports said that Jammu Kashmir Liberation Front (JKLF) chief Yasin Malik and his supporters had allegedly tried to disrupt an army rescue operation in flood-hit Srinagar.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"This is highly deplorable. They should not disrupt relief and rescue work. In fact, the army and all other security forces are doing a commendable job in rescuing the people and providing relief, the Army and other security forces must be congratulated," Raja told ANI.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"If people want to help they all should associate with the Army to deliver relief materials on time that is what one should do. This is a moment of a challenge and all sections and all political parties, all democratic movements, people's organizations must come together, stand united, work together and help people, this is what people need," he added.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">He also asked such groups to desist from doing any politicking on such issues.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"It is not a moment for doing politics. Politicking should not take place at this point of time. People need help, people need rescue and people should help the army," he further added.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">A video of Jammu and Kashmir Liberation Front (JKLF) leader Yasin Malik surfaced on Monday in which he allegedly asked voluntary relief workers not to distribute food items, as only JKLF can operate in that particular area.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Malik and his team later allegedly looted the relief materials and boats of aid workers and started distributing the items among the victims.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The JKLF chief, however, has reportedly denied all such allegations.</span></p>]]></description>
			<dc:creator>Edited by Kirti Dwivedi | Updated: 3:45 IST</dc:creator>
			<pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2014 11:32:58 -0600</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.newsx.com/national/nation/item/26788-cpi-condemns-separatists-for-hindering-kashmir-flood-relief-operations</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>J&amp;K flash floods: Activists say time to act against encroachments</title>
			<link>http://www.newsx.com/regional/j-k/item/26787-jk-flash-floods-activists-say-time-to-act-against-encroachments</link>
			<description><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/da7775022d6a0723e089ba0923ecda65_Generic.jpg"><img align="right" border="0" src="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/da7775022d6a0723e089ba0923ecda65_S.jpg" alt="jk-flash-floods-activists-say-time-to-act-against-encroachments" /></a><font color="#ff3300"><b>Featured</b></font><p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Srinagar: Chaos has hit relief distribution in flood-ravaged Kashmir as some survivors of the natural calamity from the summer capital of the state are running from pillar to post to get food grains but to no avail.</span></p>

<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Officials at various relief camps refer the flood-victims to the nearest police stations to get the food grains mostly rice is in demand but the police officials say they do not have stocks to distribute.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Ghulam Rasool, a resident of Padshahi Bagh in Srinagar, approached the Saddar police station with an application for release of food grains for his locality. The application was addressed to the Relief Officer incharge of the concerned area who had marked it to Saddar police station.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"The police officers are telling us now to go to Sheikhpura in Budgam district for getting rice bags. We have been going around for two days now but to no avail," Rasool told PTI as he was coming out of police station.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Rasool claimed that while several truck-loads of relief have been coming to neighbouring areas but nothing reached Padshahi Bagh locality.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">A senior police officer said there was no relief material stored in the police stations in his area. "What shall we distribute when we have nothing here?" he asked.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">He said the relief material coming from various areas arrives at the police station concerned but police does not distribute it and hands it over to local committees.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"Police has its plate full already. We are recovering bodies from flooded areas and there are reports of more bodies being sighted by locals in collapsed houses.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"In such a scenario, we cannot take the additional responsibility of relief distribution," the officer said.</span></p>]]></description>
			<dc:creator>Edited by Kirti Dwivedi | Updated: 3:45 IST</dc:creator>
			<pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2014 11:20:27 -0600</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.newsx.com/regional/j-k/item/26787-jk-flash-floods-activists-say-time-to-act-against-encroachments</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Maharashtra Assembly election: Chavan hopeful of resolving seat-sharing tussle with NCP</title>
			<link>http://www.newsx.com/regional/maharashtra/item/26786-maharashtra-assembly-election-chavan-hopeful-of-resolving-seat-sharing-tussle-with-ncp</link>
			<description><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/50b15dcdcbd6ffa92728b8058098d9b8_Generic.jpg"><img align="right" border="0" src="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/50b15dcdcbd6ffa92728b8058098d9b8_S.jpg" alt="maharashtra-assembly-election-chavan-hopeful-of-resolving-seat-sharing-tussle-with-ncp" /></a><font color="#ff3300"><b>Featured</b></font><p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Aurangabad: Maharashtra Chief Minister Prithviraj Chavan on Wednesday said the seat-sharing agreement between the Congress Party and the Nationalist Congress Party (NCP) for the upcoming Assembly polls will be resolved in the next three days.</span></p>

<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"We will take a decision within two to three days. My priority is that we must fight with all our might in all 288 seats whosoever is the aspirant. In the entire state of Maharashtra, we will fight with our strength and keep our secular ideals strongly before the people," Chavan told a news agency here.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"We believe that our government will be re-elected for the fourth term and they will never side with the communal forces," he added.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Meanwhile, Chavan took a jibe at the Bharatiya Janata Party (BJP) over the verdict of the bypolls results.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"The bypolls results have shown that the people are not satisfied with 100 days of governance of the BJP-led NDA. People have realised their mistakes and these results are a reflection of it," he said.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">According to reports, the stalemate between the Congress and NCP over seat sharing is brewing with the latter not willing to contest in less than 136 seats. The Congress has reportedly offered only 125 seats to its ally keeping the rest of the seats with itself to contest in the upcoming state Assembly polls.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">During the 2009 Maharashtra Assembly Elections, the Congress had contested in 174 seats while the NCP had fought in 114 seats.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The polling for 288 Assembly seats in Maharashtra is scheduled to be held on October 15. The counting of votes will take place on October 19.</span></p>]]></description>
			<dc:creator>Edited by Kirti Dwivedi | Updated: 3:35 IST</dc:creator>
			<pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2014 10:50:55 -0600</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.newsx.com/regional/maharashtra/item/26786-maharashtra-assembly-election-chavan-hopeful-of-resolving-seat-sharing-tussle-with-ncp</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Live: PM Modi gets rid of protocol, receives Chinese President XI Jinping in Ahmedabad</title>
			<link>http://www.newsx.com/national/top-stories/item/26785-live-pm-modi-gets-rid-of-protocol-receives-chinese-president-xi-jinping-in-ahmedabad</link>
			<description><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/a1d5de6b58b75d4e6eef4c7c409e47e2_Generic.jpg"><img align="right" border="0" src="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/a1d5de6b58b75d4e6eef4c7c409e47e2_S.jpg" alt="live-pm-modi-gets-rid-of-protocol-receives-chinese-president-xi-jinping-in-ahmedabad" /></a><font color="#ff3300"><b>Featured</b></font><p><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Chinese President Xi Jingping today meets Prime Minister Narendra Modi in India to understand and enhance the Indo-Chinese relations. The three day visit of Chinese President Xi Jingping is likely to draft a new chapter in bilateral ties between India and China.</span></p>

<p><strong><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Here are the live updates of the meeting</span></strong></p>
<p><strong><span style="font-size: 10pt;">5:30 PM: Xi Jingping arrives at Sabarmati ashram</span></strong></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 10pt;">As the Chinese leader arrived Sabarmati ashram, PM Modi tells Chinese President Xi Jinping that the two nations should work in an atmosphere of cooperation and give-and-take</span></p>
<p><strong><span style="font-size: 10pt;">4:30 PM: Agreement signed between India and China</span></strong></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 10pt;">India and China have signed a sister city agreement between Ahmedabad and Guangzhou and the two countries have sign pact to set up an industrial park in Gujarat in the presence of the leaders of the two countries.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 10pt;">After the meeting, the Chinese premier will visit Mahatama Gandhi’s Sabarmati ashram shortly and the Indian PM will host a private dinner for the Xi Jingping at the Sabarmati Riverfront Park where the ‘incursion’ talks are likely to be held.</span></p>
<p><strong><span style="font-size: 10pt;">4:00 PM: Two top heads begin talks</span></strong></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Prime Minister Narendra Modi begins talks with Chinese President Xi Jingping and the two top leaders will shortly sign the several key agreements between the two countries.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The agreements that are expected to be signed are most likely related to the trade, infrastructure and resoling bilateral issues.</span></p>
<p><strong><span style="font-size: 10pt;">3:40 PM: PM Modi meets Xi Jingping</span></strong></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Prime Minister Narendra Modi travelled to the Hyatt Hotel to meet the Chinese leader in Ahmedabad and the PM was spotted outside the hotel waiting for the President.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 10pt;">As Xi Jingping arrived at the hotel, Prime Minister Narendra Modi received him and offered a bunch of bouquet to him and his wife after which the group posed for the cameras.</span></p>
<p><strong><span style="font-size: 10pt;">3:00 PM: Gujarat Chief Minister welcomes Chinese leader</span></strong></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 10pt;"><iframe src="//www.youtube.com/embed/oxWjGHqB8x4" frameborder="0" width="684" height="415" allowfullscreen="true" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"></iframe></span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Gujarat Chief Minister Anandiben Patel and state Governor OP Kohli offered a warm welcome to the Chinese President Xi Jingping along with his wife Peng Liyuan, 51 who is a well accomplished folk-singer and a household name in China.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 10pt;">On being received, a guard of honour was presented to Xi Jingping.</span></p>
<p><strong><span style="font-size: 10pt;">2:45 PM: Chinese President Xi Jingping visit in India</span></strong></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The much awaited three day tour of Chinese President Xi Jingping begins now as the aircraft the President is travelling ahs landed at the Indian soil. While his plane was delayed by 20 minutes as per the scheduled time, it safely landed in Ahmedabad.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Waving off to the protocol, Prime Minister Modi personally received the Chinese President and this is the first time that a foreign dignitary is starting his visit from outside the National Capital.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Ahead of the Chinese President’s visit, a red carpet welcome and Gujarati culture and cuisine was awaiting the Chinese guest.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The commercial capital of Gujarat, Ahmedabad was decked up to welcome the Chinese leader who after signing the defence and maritime security cooperation deal with Colombo, is likely to sign a number of agreements with the Indian PM at the time of his three-day visit.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Ahead of the visit, the city came to a standstill because of traffic block and countless people gathered to have a glimpse of the Indian PM and Chinese President.</span></p>]]></description>
			<dc:creator>Written by Charnamrit Sachdeva</dc:creator>
			<pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2014 10:07:54 -0600</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.newsx.com/national/top-stories/item/26785-live-pm-modi-gets-rid-of-protocol-receives-chinese-president-xi-jinping-in-ahmedabad</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>#SaradhaScam: Former Assam DGP, under scanner in Saradha scam commits suicide</title>
			<link>http://www.newsx.com/component/k2/item/26784-#saradhascam-former-assam-dgp-under-scanner-in-saradha-scam-commits-suicide&amp;Itemid=665</link>
			<description><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/70c821e90ddcfb0a1816b7d39393141a_Generic.jpg"><img align="right" border="0" src="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/70c821e90ddcfb0a1816b7d39393141a_S.jpg" alt="#saradhascam-former-assam-dgp-under-scanner-in-saradha-scam-commits-suicide" /></a><font color="#ff3300"><b>Featured</b></font><p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">NEW DELHI: With shocking details being revealed in Saradha scam, another incident giving jitters has been reported. Former Assam DGP Sankar Barua who was in a scanner in the Saradha scam was found dead on Wednesday at his residence in Guwahati.</span></p>

<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">According to the reports, Barua who allegedly committed suicide and shot himself with a revolver was raided by CBI about two weeks ago in connection with the Saradha scam.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">A police official who opted to keep his identity anonymous informed that former DGP shot himself in the forehead after being discharged from hospital this morning.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The residence of Shankar Barua was one of 12 locations in Guwahati where the CBI sleuths had conducted searches on the scam which according to one official estimate is pegged upwards of Rs. 2, 500 crore.</span></p>]]></description>
			<dc:creator>Written by Charnamrit Sachdeva</dc:creator>
			<pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2014 10:01:35 -0600</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.newsx.com/component/k2/item/26784-#saradhascam-former-assam-dgp-under-scanner-in-saradha-scam-commits-suicide&amp;Itemid=665</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Sri Lankan national, caught spying for Pakistan, sent to NIA custody</title>
			<link>http://www.newsx.com/national/nation/item/26783-sri-lankan-national-caught-spying-for-pakistan-sent-to-nia-custody</link>
			<description><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/c215292205945806402f083b7b3ca1f1_Generic.jpg"><img align="right" border="0" src="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/c215292205945806402f083b7b3ca1f1_S.jpg" alt="sri-lankan-national-caught-spying-for-pakistan-sent-to-nia-custody" /></a><font color="#ff3300"><b>Featured</b></font><p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Chennai: A court here on Wednesday granted NIA six days custody of a Sri Lankan national held for allegedly spying for Pakistan.</span></p>

<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">In a brief order, judge of the designated NIA court, M Moni, allowed Arun Selvarajan's custody to the NIA from September 18 to 23.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">A petition was filed by the NIA seeking seven days custody of Arun following his 14-day judicial remand on September 11. He was arrested on September 10.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Yesterday, when the petition seeking custody came up for hearing, the judge sought the view of the accused. He responded by saying that "he was ready to go to police custody".</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Selvarajan allegedly posed as an event management professional and had acted at the behest of his handlers in the Pakistan High Commission in Colombo.</span></p>]]></description>
			<dc:creator>Edited by Priyanka Kukreja || Updated: 14:55 IST</dc:creator>
			<pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2014 09:33:48 -0600</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.newsx.com/national/nation/item/26783-sri-lankan-national-caught-spying-for-pakistan-sent-to-nia-custody</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>New book by Salman Khurshid to be out this November</title>
			<link>http://www.newsx.com/national/others-news/item/26782-new-book-by-salman-khurshid-to-be-out-this-november</link>
			<description><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/3c9154ea6aa752a486e7b9cb08959184_Generic.jpg"><img align="right" border="0" src="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/3c9154ea6aa752a486e7b9cb08959184_S.jpg" alt="new-book-by-salman-khurshid-to-be-out-this-november" /></a><p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">New Delhi: A book by former Union Minister Salman Khurshid, "At Home in India: The Muslim Saga" is set to hit book stores this November, his publishers said Wednesday.</span></p>

<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"It is a comprehensive, definitive and forceful account - by a witness to recent history in the making - which highlights fact that Muslims do feel at home in India and also provides rare insights into their thought processes, their aspirations and their problems," publishers said in a statement.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The upcoming book is being published by Hay House with distribution and marketing by Penguin Books.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The book covers a wide span from late nineteenth century to the present and brings out the pivotal roles played by a galaxy of distinguished Indian Muslims.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Kurshid describes how the Aligarh Muslim University and Delhi's Jamia Millia Islamia came into being and how many of their alumni became part of freedom movement.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"The author does not shy away from hypersensitive issues such as terrorism, communal riots, a Uniform Civil Code, present-day Muslim leadership (or lack of) and the place of women in Islam, with a focus on the Shah Bano case," the publishers said.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"He underscores the significance of the 'trust deficit' on the part of Muslims vis-a-vis the police (based on a recent report of the directors-general of police from different states) and spotlights the July 2014 verdict of the Supreme Court with regard to the Shariat and fatwas," Penguin said.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The former External Affairs Minister "rounds off the book with analysis of what the future could hold after the recent victory of the Bharatiya Janata Party and its allies in the 2014 Lok Sabha elections."</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The 61-year-old author has previously penned the book "Beyond Terrorism: New Hope for Kashmir" (1994) and a play "Sons of Babur" (2008).</span></p>]]></description>
			<dc:creator>Edited by Priyanka Kukreja || Updated: 14:55 IST</dc:creator>
			<pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2014 09:22:18 -0600</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.newsx.com/national/others-news/item/26782-new-book-by-salman-khurshid-to-be-out-this-november</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Big stars lining up for PM Narendra Modi reception in New York</title>
			<link>http://www.newsx.com/national/nation/item/26781-big-stars-lining-up-for-pm-narendra-modi-reception-in-new-york</link>
			<description><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/514b07a7fbfaab82f09e07e59982bf73_Generic.jpg"><img align="right" border="0" src="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/514b07a7fbfaab82f09e07e59982bf73_S.jpg" alt="big-stars-lining-up-for-pm-narendra-modi-reception-in-new-york" /></a><font color="#ff3300"><b>Featured</b></font><p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Washington: Young Indian-American pop star sensation Anjali Ranadive, popular playback singer Kavita Subramaniam along with renowned violinist L Subramaniam would perform at a public reception being hosted by Indian-American community for Prime Minister Narendra Modi in New York.</span></p>

<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Ranadive, the daughter of the Sacramento Kings owner Vivek Ranadive, would sing the US anthem, and Subramaniam would lend her voice to the Indian anthem before Modi's much anticipated speech to the Diaspora at the historic Madison Square Garden on September 28.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Subramaniam would enthrall the audience with his mesmerizing violin performance at Modi's reception being organised by the Indian-American Community Foundation (IACF), which was created recently to promote cooperation between the US and India and advance the shared values of democracy.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">IACF had earlier announced that Miss America 2014 Nina Davuluri and PBS NewsHour Weekend Anchor Hari Sreenivasan will emcee the event; thus adding a star line up to the Modi's reception, which is expected to be attended by a number of US lawmakers, governors and city leaders.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">In a statement, IACF spokesperson Anand Shah said a spectacular laser light show, holograms of India's historical luminaries, and live folk dances will precede Modi's speech.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"Prime Minister Modi taking the stage along with dozens of America's most important political leaders in front of tens of thousands of cheering supporters will demonstrate the potential of a relationship across borders," Shah said.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"The time has come for the world's most significant democracies - India and America - to join together on a platform of mutual respect and shared values," he said.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">To accommodate the thousands of people who were not lucky enough to get one of the 18,000 free tickets, the event would be broadcast live at the iconic Crystal Tower of the Times Square, with real time English sub-titles.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"The incredible demand to be a part of Indian American history in greeting Prime Minister Modi has pushed us to find more ways to let the community participate," Shah said.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"And that is why we decided to broadcast the event in Times Square, stream it online at www.Pmvisit.Org, and provide English subtitles and audio translation - ensuring that as many people as possible could be part of what promises to be one of the largest ever gatherings to hear a foreign leader speak on American soil."</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The IACF is also helping student groups and community organizers arrange "viewing parties" in their local areas.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Anticipating that thousands of people would be converging to mid-town Manhattan on September 28, local public transportation system in co-ordination with IACF have announced to run special buses, trains throughout the day.</span></p>]]></description>
			<dc:creator>Edited by Priyanka Kukreja || Updated: 14:40 IST</dc:creator>
			<pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2014 09:13:44 -0600</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.newsx.com/national/nation/item/26781-big-stars-lining-up-for-pm-narendra-modi-reception-in-new-york</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Minor girl gang-raped by six men in Varanasi</title>
			<link>http://www.newsx.com/regional/up/item/26780-minor-girl-gang-raped-by-six-men-in-varanasi</link>
			<description><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/4aa26a76a9f6b1c23509c7e1abfa7975_Generic.jpg"><img align="right" border="0" src="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/4aa26a76a9f6b1c23509c7e1abfa7975_S.jpg" alt="minor-girl-gang-raped-by-six-men-in-varanasi" /></a><p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Varanasi/Chandauli: A 17-year-old girl was allegedly kidnapped and gang-raped by six persons here, police said.</span></p>

<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The incident took place on September 9 when the girl, a student of class twelfth, was kidnapped by six persons while going to her house under Illia police station area of Chandauli district, police said.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The accused forcibly pulled her in their car and and took her to Allahabad where they held her captive and gang-raped her for almost six days, Superintendent of Police, Muniraj said.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">They brought her back to Varanasi and dropped her at Cantt railway station, he said, adding, one of the accused informed the parents of the girl over phone on Monday that they can find their daughter at the railway station.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Girls parents rushed to the railway station and found her there.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">An FIR was registered on Monday night against the six persons on the complaint of the girl's father.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">However, the girl has refused to go through the medical examination yesterday, Muniraj said.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The girl will be produced before the judicial magistrate for further decision into the case, the SP said, adding, all the six accused are absconding and an investigation into the case is on.</span></p>]]></description>
			<dc:creator>Edited by Priyanka Kukreja || Updated: 14:40 IST</dc:creator>
			<pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2014 09:02:10 -0600</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.newsx.com/regional/up/item/26780-minor-girl-gang-raped-by-six-men-in-varanasi</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Dozens of villagers hospitalised after drinking pit water in Palghar</title>
			<link>http://www.newsx.com/regional/maharashtra/item/26779-dozens-of-villagers-hospitalised-after-drinking-pit-water-in-palghar</link>
			<description><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/9ea3cf3ce763c981731885fced2d5d3d_Generic.jpg"><img align="right" border="0" src="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/9ea3cf3ce763c981731885fced2d5d3d_S.jpg" alt="dozens-of-villagers-hospitalised-after-drinking-pit-water-in-palghar" /></a><font color="#ff3300"><b>Featured</b></font><p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Palghar: At least a dozen tribals from Nandgaon village in Jawahar taluka here have been hospitalised for gastroenteritis after they drank contaminated water from pits, officials said Wednesday.</span></p>

<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The villagers were rushed to the Patangsha Kutir Rugnalaya in Jawahar two days ago after they complained of vomiting, giddiness and other complications, Dr Sanjeev Kamble, Deputy Director of Health Services Mumbai division, who is presently touring the rural regions of the newly formed Palghar district, said today.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The condition of the villagers, who are undergoing treatment in now stable, he said.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">According to Kamble, most of the patients from the tribal-dominated village have been consuming polluted water from the pits.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The DHO of Palghar, Dr R V Gaikwad is also camping in the region and supervising measures to avert the spread of the disease while ensuring that villagers get safe potable water, Kamble said.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">A ten-year-old boy Balu Laxman Wad died a few days back while being shifted to Jawhar hospital after his condition deteriorated while undergoing treatment at the village for drinking dirty water.</span></p>]]></description>
			<dc:creator>Edited by Priyanka Kukreja || Updated: 14:10 IST</dc:creator>
			<pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2014 08:49:51 -0600</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.newsx.com/regional/maharashtra/item/26779-dozens-of-villagers-hospitalised-after-drinking-pit-water-in-palghar</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Maruti Suzuki marketing and sales head Mayank Pareek resigns</title>
			<link>http://www.newsx.com/national/others-news/item/26778-maruti-suzuki-marketing-and-sales-head-mayank-pareek-resigns</link>
			<description><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/daca9bf033f46b38e548d0f06d9dd001_Generic.jpg"><img align="right" border="0" src="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/daca9bf033f46b38e548d0f06d9dd001_S.jpg" alt="maruti-suzuki-marketing-and-sales-head-mayank-pareek-resigns" /></a><p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">New Delhi: Maruti Suzuki India's marketing and sales head Mayank Pareek has quit the company after nearly 20 years of service at the country's largest carmaker.</span></p>

<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">While Pareek, who is designated Chief Operating Officer (marketing and sales), could not be reached for comments, however, according to people familiar with the development, he has put in papers to pursue 'better opportunities'.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The company spokesperson declined to comment.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">It is speculated that he may join homegrown auto major Tata Motors, which has been seeking a revival in fortunes in the passenger cars segment.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Besides the company chairman R C Bhargava, Pareek is the other Indian face of the company in which Japan's Suzuki Motor Corporation holds majority stake.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">His sudden departure comes at a time when Maruti is gearing up to launch its premium sedan Ciaz next month. The company has been struggling to make its presence felt in the bigger car segment.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Pareek had successfully continued the rural drive of the company initiated by former managing director Jagdish Khattar.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">He has been credited for keeping the company's sales counter ticking and increasing market share even when the Indian automobile market went on a slump in the last two years.</span></p>]]></description>
			<dc:creator>Edited by Priyanka Kukreja || Updated: 13:50 IST</dc:creator>
			<pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2014 08:18:46 -0600</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.newsx.com/national/others-news/item/26778-maruti-suzuki-marketing-and-sales-head-mayank-pareek-resigns</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>India home to 100 billionaires; 6th largest population globally</title>
			<link>http://www.newsx.com/national/business/item/26777-india-home-to-100-billionaires-6th-largest-population-globally</link>
			<description><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/31533e13b7ea6982cbb413f412b24048_Generic.jpg"><img align="right" border="0" src="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/31533e13b7ea6982cbb413f412b24048_S.jpg" alt="india-home-to-100-billionaires-6th-largest-population-globally" /></a><font color="#ff3300"><b>Featured</b></font><p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Singapore/New Delhi: India has retained its sixth position in terms of number of billionaires with 100 such people collectively having USD 175 billion in networth, while globally the number of uber-rich has reached a record high of 2,325 persons.</span></p>

<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">According to the Wealth-X and UBS Billionaire Census 2014, released on Wednesday, though the number of billionaires in the country has decreased over last year (in 2013 there were 103 billionaires) India still enjoys a decent 6th position (same as last year) in the top 10 league.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Interestingly, India has more number of billionaires than Switzerland, Hong Kong and France among others.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Moreover, the country's financial capital Mumbai, with 28 billionaires is among the top 20 'billionaire cities' globally, which was topped by New York which is home to 103 billionaires.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">On the top 40 billionaire countries/territories list, the United States maintained its position as the world's top billionaire country with a population of 571 billionaires in 2014, followed by China (190) and the United Kingdom (130) in the second and third position respectively.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">According to the the report, which looks at the global billionaire population from July 2013 to June 2014, India's billionaire population has decreased by 3 percent to 100 and the total billionaire wealth has fallen by USD 5 billion to USD 175 billion.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">However, the world's population of billionaires continues to grow.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The global billionaire population reached a record 2,325 with the addition of 155 new billionaires in 2014, registering a rise of 7 percent from 2013.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"The combined wealth of the world's billionaires increased by 12 percent to USD 7.3 trillion, which is higher than the combined market capitalisation of all the companies that make up the Dow Jones Industrial Average," the report said.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Europe, with 775 billionaires, is the region with the most billionaires and billionaire wealth (USD 2.37 trillion), while, Asia boasted the largest billionaire wealth increase, with the region's billionaires' fortunes growing by 18.7 percent over the past year.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"The region (Asia) is responsible for 30 percent of the net increase in global billionaire wealth in 2014.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Asia's billionaire population grew by 10 percent in 2014, with 52 new entrants into the billionaire club out of which 33 are from China," the report said.</span></p>]]></description>
			<dc:creator>Edited by Priyanka Kukreja || Updated: 13:30 IST</dc:creator>
			<pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2014 08:04:23 -0600</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.newsx.com/national/business/item/26777-india-home-to-100-billionaires-6th-largest-population-globally</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Pak police registers murder case against Sharif, ministers</title>
			<link>http://www.newsx.com/world/pakistan/item/26776-pak-police-registers-murder-case-against-sharif-ministers</link>
			<description><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/a0df9ffcdcdd2b732281ffce8a5b3722_Generic.jpg"><img align="right" border="0" src="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/a0df9ffcdcdd2b732281ffce8a5b3722_S.jpg" alt="pak-police-registers-murder-case-against-sharif-ministers" /></a><font color="#ff3300"><b>Featured</b></font><p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">A murder case has been registered against Pakistan Prime Minister Nawaz Sharif, his ministers and other top officials for their alleged involvement in the killing of anti-government protesters here, police said on Wednesday.</span></p>

<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The case was registered last night after a district judge ordered framing of murder charges against Sharif and others over the killing of protesters, the second criminal case to be filed against the embattled Prime Minister.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Pakistan Awami Tehrik (PAT), led by fiery cleric Tahirul Qadri, had approached the court for registering of case.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">At least three people were killed and over 500 injured in clashes with police on August 30 after the populist cleric and Pakistan Tehreek-e-Insaaf chief Imran Khan asked their supporters to march toward the official residence of Sharif.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">A police official from the Secretariat Police Station told PTI that the case was registered after the district and sessions judge on Monday "ordered us" to register the case while disposing of a petition filed by Qadri.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">He said section 302 of Pakistan Penal Code (intentional murder) and Section 7 of the Anti-Terrorism Act were also included in the case.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">It was second murder case against Sharif after one field last month in Lahore for killing of 14 workers of Qadri in clashes with police in June.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The nomination of a person in a case does not affect his legal status but conviction makes people ineligible for any public office in Pakistan.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Khan wants Sharif's ouster over alleged rigging in last year's poll which his party lost, while Qadri wants to bring a revolution in the country. They are agitating since August 14, demanding Sharif's ouster.</span></p>]]></description>
			<dc:creator>Edited by Priyanka Kukreja || Updated: 13:10 IST</dc:creator>
			<pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2014 07:50:36 -0600</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.newsx.com/world/pakistan/item/26776-pak-police-registers-murder-case-against-sharif-ministers</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Jayalalithaa greets PM Modi on his 64th birthday</title>
			<link>http://www.newsx.com/national/nation/item/26774-jayalalithaa-greets-pm-modi-on-his-64th-birthday</link>
			<description><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/1e62ed23270f7c6c62f71b8eda55fcec_Generic.jpg"><img align="right" border="0" src="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/1e62ed23270f7c6c62f71b8eda55fcec_S.jpg" alt="jayalalithaa-greets-pm-modi-on-his-64th-birthday" /></a><font color="#ff3300"><b>Featured</b></font><p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Chennai: Tamil Nadu Chief Minister Jayalalithaa on Wednesday greeted Prime Minister Narendra Modi on his 64th birthday, wishing him many years of good health to serve the country.</span></p>

<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"On the joyous occasion of your birthday, I would like to convey my felicitations to you and wish you many more happy returns of the day."</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"I pray that the Almighty may grant you many more years of good health to serve our nation," Jayalalithaa said in her message to Modi.</span></p>]]></description>
			<dc:creator>Edited by Priyanka Kukreja || Updated: 12:40 IST</dc:creator>
			<pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2014 07:09:33 -0600</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.newsx.com/national/nation/item/26774-jayalalithaa-greets-pm-modi-on-his-64th-birthday</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Premium trains between Lokmanya Tilak Terminus-Howrah, Secunderabad-Nizamuddin</title>
			<link>http://www.newsx.com/national/nation/item/26773-premium-trains-between-lokmanya-tilak-terminus-howrah-secunderabad-nizamuddin</link>
			<description><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/830357d422b770a58385e3332db87185_Generic.jpg"><img align="right" border="0" src="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/830357d422b770a58385e3332db87185_S.jpg" alt="premium-trains-between-lokmanya-tilak-terminus-howrah-secunderabad-nizamuddin" /></a><p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Nagpur: The Railways will run premium trains between Lokmanya Tilak Terminus (LTT) and Howrah and between Secunderabad and Hazrat Nizamuddin to clear holiday rush.</span></p>

<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Accordingly, Premium train number 2241 will depart LTT on September 23 and September 30 at 1:20 pm (on Tuesdays) and reach Howrah next day (Wednesday) at 4:15 pm.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">It will pass through Nagpur on Wednesdays at 1:20 am, a release from Nagpur division of Central Raiway, said today.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Similarly, Premium train number 2242 will leave Howrah on September 25 and October 02 ((Thursdays) at 6:30 pm and arrive at LTT at 11:45 pm on Fridays.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">It will arrive in Nagpur on September 26 and October 3 at 11:15 am. Trains will halt at Bhusawal, Nagpur, Raipur, Raurkela and Tatanagar in both directions.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">It will consists of 22 coaches including three 2AC, 16 SL, one pantry car and two SLRs.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The Premium train number 2723 will depart Secunderabad on September 26 (Friday) at 9 am and reach Nizamuddin next day (Saturday) at 9:15 am.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">It will pass through Nagpur at 8:23 pm on Friday.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Train number 2724 will leave Nizamuddin on September 27 (Saturday) at 5:05 pm and arrive at Secunderabad on Sunday at 7:25 pm. It will touch Nagpur on Saturday at 10:40 am. It will have a total of 16 coaches including one 2AC two 3AC, 10 SL, one pantry car and two SLRs.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">It will halt at Ramagundam, Nagpur, Bhopal, Jhansi and Agra Cantt in both the directions, the release added.</span></p>]]></description>
			<dc:creator>Edited by Priyanka Kukreja || Updated: 12:10 IST</dc:creator>
			<pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2014 06:32:54 -0600</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.newsx.com/national/nation/item/26773-premium-trains-between-lokmanya-tilak-terminus-howrah-secunderabad-nizamuddin</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Curb sugar intake to reduce tooth decay: study</title>
			<link>http://www.newsx.com/life-style/health/item/26772-curb-sugar-intake-to-reduce-tooth-decay-study</link>
			<description><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/588084c5ef7e360f2e0ab02b4ae04e68_Generic.jpg"><img align="right" border="0" src="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/588084c5ef7e360f2e0ab02b4ae04e68_S.jpg" alt="curb-sugar-intake-to-reduce-tooth-decay-study" /></a><font color="#ff3300"><b>Featured</b></font><p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Sugars in the diet should make up no more than 3 per cent of total energy intake to reduce the significant financial and social burdens of tooth decay, according to a new research.</span></p>

<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The study from University College London (UCL) and the London School of Hygiene &amp; Tropical Medicine, analysed the effect of sugars on dental caries, also known as tooth decay.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">They show that sugars are the only cause of tooth decay in children and adults.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Tooth decay is the most common non-communicable disease in the world, affecting 60-90 per cent of school-age children and the vast majority of adults, researchers said.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The treatment of dental diseases costs 5-10 per cent of total health expenditure in industrialised countries, they said.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Researchers used public health records from countries across the world to compare dental health and diet over time across large populations of adults and children.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">They found that the incidence of tooth decay was much higher in adults than children, and increased dramatically with any sugar consumption above zero per cent of energy.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Even in children, an increase from near-zero sugar to 5 per cent of energy doubles the prevalence of decay and continues to rise as sugar intake increases.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Current guidelines from the World Health Organisation set a maximum of 10 per cent of total energy intake from free sugars, with 5 per cent as a 'target'.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">This equates to around 50g of free sugars per day as the maximum, with 25g as the target. The latest research suggests that 5 per cent should be the absolute maximum, with a target of less than 3 per cent.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"Tooth decay is a serious problem worldwide and reducing sugars intake makes a huge difference," said study author Aubrey Sheiham, Emeritus Professor of Dental Public Health at UCL Epidemiology &amp; Public Health.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The study was published in the journal BMC Public Health.</span></p>]]></description>
			<dc:creator>Edited by Priyanka Kukreja || Updated: 11:30 IST</dc:creator>
			<pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2014 05:53:44 -0600</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.newsx.com/life-style/health/item/26772-curb-sugar-intake-to-reduce-tooth-decay-study</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>I believe in fairytales: Sonam Kapoor</title>
			<link>http://www.newsx.com/showbiz/celebrities/item/26771-i-believe-in-fairytales-sonam-kapoor</link>
			<description><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/e20e103793d6e01fdc448fbfb7df316c_Generic.jpg"><img align="right" border="0" src="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/e20e103793d6e01fdc448fbfb7df316c_S.jpg" alt="i-believe-in-fairytales-sonam-kapoor" /></a><font color="#ff3300"><b>Featured</b></font><p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">New Delhi: Actress Sonam Kapoor, who will be seen in the role of a clumsy girl, who falls in love with a Prince in her upcoming film 'Khoobsurat', says she is a believer of fairytales in real life.</span></p>

<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The 29-year-old actress said she did the Disney movie because she believes in happy endings and even though the concept of a fairytale does not find many takers today, people should hold onto it.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"The reason I did 'Khoobsurat' was because I just believe in a happily ever after... I am a strong believer of fairytales and think at the end everything will be good. We should not let that feeling go from our lives," Sonam told reporters here.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">'Khoobsurat', also starring Pakistani actor Fawad Khan, is the remake of Hrishikesh Mukherjee's 1980 film of the same name. Sonam reprises the character played by Rekha in the original. The film releases this Friday.</span></p>]]></description>
			<dc:creator>Edited by Priyanka Kukreja || Updated: 10:50 IST</dc:creator>
			<pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2014 05:23:41 -0600</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.newsx.com/showbiz/celebrities/item/26771-i-believe-in-fairytales-sonam-kapoor</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Sensex rebounds 127 points in early trade on global cues</title>
			<link>http://www.newsx.com/national/business/item/26770-sensex-rebounds-127-points-in-early-trade-on-global-cues</link>
			<description><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/f827065adced4fef6b385befeb5c21a2_Generic.jpg"><img align="right" border="0" src="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/f827065adced4fef6b385befeb5c21a2_S.jpg" alt="sensex-rebounds-127-points-in-early-trade-on-global-cues" /></a><font color="#ff3300"><b>Featured</b></font><p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Mumbai: After two sessions of losses, the benchmark BSE Sensex recovered sharply by over 127 points in early trade today on emergence of buying by funds and retail investors amid a firming trend in other Asian markets.</span></p>

<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The 30-share index, which had lost 568.53 points in the previous two sessions, rose by 127.37 points, or 0.48 per cent, to 26,619.88, with all sectoral indices, led by realty and metals, trading in positive zone with gains up to 1.</span></p>]]></description>
			<dc:creator>Edited by Priyanka Kukreja || Updated: 10:30 IST</dc:creator>
			<pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2014 05:01:56 -0600</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.newsx.com/national/business/item/26770-sensex-rebounds-127-points-in-early-trade-on-global-cues</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>#PMTurns64: Prime Minister Narendra Modi seeks blessings of his mother as he turns 64 today</title>
			<link>http://www.newsx.com/national/top-stories/item/26769-modi-turns-64-meets-mother-to-seek-blessings</link>
			<description><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/efbe03e411653d08b72f25f3babce6ef_Generic.jpg"><img align="right" border="0" src="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/efbe03e411653d08b72f25f3babce6ef_S.jpg" alt="modi-turns-64-meets-mother-to-seek-blessings" /></a><font color="#ff3300"><b>Featured</b></font><p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Prime Minister of India Narendra Modi turns 64 today and he met his mother Heeraben in Gandhinagar to seek her blessings. This is the first birthday of Narendra Modi after taking over the position of Prime Minister of India.</span></p>

<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">On the special day of her son’s birthday, the proud mother according to the sources donated Rs. 5, 000 for the Prime Minister’s Relief Fund for Jammu and Kashmir.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">According to the sources, PM Modi went to Gandhinagar, 23 km ahead from Ahmedabad alone in his normal sense without taking any support of his security guards to accompany him.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">&nbsp;</span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 10pt;"><iframe src="//www.youtube.com/embed/q4S-jmBHKfA" frameborder="0" width="684" height="415" allowfullscreen="true" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"></iframe></span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">His Japanese counterpart Shinzo Abe and President Pranab Mukherjee as well called the Indian PM to extend their good wishes to him on the special day.</span></span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">PM Modi had paid a visit to Japan only a fortnight back and the warmness between the two leaders was put on show at that time.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Apart from President Mukherjee, Vice President Hamid Ansari also wished him.</span></p>]]></description>
			<dc:creator>Written by Charnamrit Sachdeva</dc:creator>
			<pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2014 03:22:01 -0600</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.newsx.com/national/top-stories/item/26769-modi-turns-64-meets-mother-to-seek-blessings</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Iran's current uranium enrichment not acceptable: US</title>
			<link>http://www.newsx.com/world/us/item/26768-irans-current-uranium-enrichment-not-acceptable-us</link>
			<description><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/913cb88730ec007ec60bba635b128854_Generic.jpg"><img align="right" border="0" src="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/913cb88730ec007ec60bba635b128854_S.jpg" alt="irans-current-uranium-enrichment-not-acceptable-us" /></a><font color="#ff3300"><b>Featured</b></font><p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Washington: Iran cannot convince the world that its current ability to enrich uranium is acceptable, the top US negotiator said Tuesday ahead of new nuclear talks with global powers.</span></p>

<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">After months of intense negotiations the two sides have "identified potential answers to some key questions," Under Secretary of State Wendy Sherman said in a speech at an award-giving ceremony at Georgetown University.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">But she warned "we remain far apart on other core issues, including the size and scope of Iran`s uranium enrichment capacity."</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">As Iran and world powers prepare for new talks starting on Thursday in New York, Sherman said she expected the Islamic Republic "will try to convince the world that on this pivotal matter, the status quo ... should be acceptable."</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"It is not," Sherman stressed, as she was given a top award for distinction in the conduct of diplomacy.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"If it were, we wouldn`t be involved in this difficult and very painstaking negotiation."</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The five permanent members of the UN Security Council plus Germany (the P5+1) want Iran to scale down its nuclear activities to make any breakout move to manufacture a bomb extremely difficult.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">In return Tehran, which denies wanting nuclear weapons and says a peaceful atomic program is its right, wants the lifting of tough UN and Western sanctions.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">But Sherman stressed: "The world will agree to suspend and lift sanctions only if Iran takes convincing and verifiable steps to show that its nuclear program is and will remain entirely peaceful.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"We must be confident that any effort by Tehran to break out of its obligations will be so visible and time-consuming that the attempt would have no chance of success."</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Sherman insisted the ideas that the US and its allies have put forward in the hopes of reaching a deal by a November 24 deadline were "fair, flexible and consistent with Iran`s civilian nuclear needs and scientific knowhow."</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The talks in New York will be at the level of political directors. But foreign ministers from Iran and the six powers, present in New York for the UN General Assembly will likely also meet some time next week.</span></p>]]></description>
			<dc:creator>Edited by Priyanka Kukreja || Updated  8:40 IST</dc:creator>
			<pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2014 03:05:27 -0600</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.newsx.com/world/us/item/26768-irans-current-uranium-enrichment-not-acceptable-us</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>'Achhe din' myth exposed, BJP will be rejected in Haryana as well: Congress</title>
			<link>http://www.newsx.com/haryana-news/item/26767-achhe-din-myth-exposed-bjp-will-be-rejected-in-haryana-as-well-congress</link>
			<description><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/1160d90ff310b7a591caa3c09d3c08df_Generic.jpg"><img align="right" border="0" src="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/1160d90ff310b7a591caa3c09d3c08df_S.jpg" alt="achhe-din-myth-exposed-bjp-will-be-rejected-in-haryana-as-well-congress" /></a><font color="#ff3300"><b>Featured</b></font><p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Chandigarh: Congress on Tuesday termed the assembly bypolls results as a "mini referendum" saying the "achhe din" myth stands exposed as the people have rejected the "authoritarian" mode of governance, and asserted that the electorate of Haryana will also reject BJP in the October 15 elections.</span></p>

<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"The 'achhe din' myth stands exposed and the artificially created bubble has burst. The People of India have spoken once again in this mini-referendum - from Gujarat to UP - rejecting the governance style, lack of vision and authoritarian mode of governance," Congress national spokesman and Haryana Cabinet Minister Randeep Singh Surjewala said.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">He said the inclusive style of governance as shown by the Congress is the only way to run a country as diverse as India.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"We thank the people of India for showing the mirror to BJP and the Prime Minister," Surjewala said on the bypoll results today.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Asked what impact the bypoll results could have on the next month's assembly polls in Haryana, Surjewala said the people will reject the saffron party.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"BJP suffers from a phobia of arrogance in Haryana and has become an accumulating point for defectors, opportunists and rejected leaders," the senior Congress leader said.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">With Haryana Janhit Congress separating from BJP accusing it of "repeated betrayals", Surjewala said "with their own alliance having been shamelessly breached by BJP leadership, their now found love for INLD whom their own (BJP) President (Amit Shah) calls a goonda party is indeed intriguing and strange".</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"They (BJP) must answer clearly to the people of Haryana ans clarify this opportunistic brand of politics that they seem to be playing out," he said.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">BJP was dealt a major blow in the Assembly by-elections in Uttar Pradesh, Rajasthan and Gujarat, the states it had swept in the Lok Sabha polls four months ago, as it lost 13 of the 23 seats held by it.</span></p>]]></description>
			<dc:creator>Edited by Priyanka Kukreja || Updated: 8:20 IST</dc:creator>
			<pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2014 02:42:13 -0600</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.newsx.com/haryana-news/item/26767-achhe-din-myth-exposed-bjp-will-be-rejected-in-haryana-as-well-congress</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Writers, historians, scribes show solidarity with Kashmir's flood-hit people</title>
			<link>http://www.newsx.com/cities/item/26766-writers-historians-scribes-show-solidarity-with-kashmirs-flood-hit-people</link>
			<description><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/da6e404ffe4f564e03d1f5edcae6a158_Generic.jpg"><img align="right" border="0" src="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/da6e404ffe4f564e03d1f5edcae6a158_S.jpg" alt="writers-historians-scribes-show-solidarity-with-kashmirs-flood-hit-people" /></a><font color="#ff3300"><b>Featured</b></font><p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">New Delhi: Eminent writers, historians, scientists, journalists and civil society workers on Tuesday came forward to show their solidarity with the people Jammu and Kashmir battling the worst floods in the state's history.</span></p>

<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">At a discussion here, they called for prompt rehabilitation of the affected people and asked the authorities to speed up the relief and rescue work.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"We could not stop the floods but we could have certainly mitigated the damage to a very large extent. They were not flash floods. With modern technology, we could have predicted the water levels and gave concrete alerts to people," said Saleem Baig, Convener, INTACH (Indian National Trust for Art and Cultural Heritage), J&amp;K chapter.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Baig rejected reports of selective rescue operations and said "it is not the time to look at such developments. We should not converge long-standing political problems with something that is immediate and requires prompt action."</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Iftikar Gilani, senior journalist who had reported extensively about the state, pointed to loopholes in rescue operations and suggested a few solutions to streamline the operations in the valley.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"There is a dire need for more water pumps, water purification units and a team of pediatricians in the valley. Many Air India flights are unable to lift relief materials from major airports. The material is lying unclaimed at airports in Pune, Bangalore and Calcutta.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"Just 80 boats have been allotted for the rescue operations, against the requirement of 650. We need to also look at the kind of relief materials that the victims are in need of," said the journalist at the event at the Press Club of India here.</span></p>]]></description>
			<dc:creator>Edited by Priyanka Kukreja || Updated:  8:00 IST</dc:creator>
			<pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2014 02:23:56 -0600</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.newsx.com/cities/item/26766-writers-historians-scribes-show-solidarity-with-kashmirs-flood-hit-people</guid>
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
