<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet href="http://www.newsx.com/components/com_obrss/assets/xsl/atom-to-html.xsl" type="text/xsl"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
	<channel>
		<title>rss</title>
		<description><![CDATA[RSS Feed]]></description>
		<link>http://www.newsx.com/</link>
		<lastBuildDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2014 13:40:17 -0600</lastBuildDate>
		<generator>FeedCreator 1.8.3 (obRSS 1.9)</generator>
		<atom:link href="http://www.newsx.com/index.php?option=com_obrss&amp;task=feed&amp;id=2:rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
		<image>
			<url>http://www.newsx.com/images/</url>
			<title>rss</title>
			<link>http://www.newsx.com/</link>
			<description>RSS Feed</description>
		</image>
		<item>
			<title>34-yr-old woman raped, family robbed of Rs 10,000</title>
			<link>http://www.newsx.com/regional/other-states/item/26880-34-yr-old-woman-raped-family-robbed-of-rs-10000</link>
			<description><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/9795e66859227db0fab93d978bc0685a_Generic.jpg"><img align="right" border="0" src="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/9795e66859227db0fab93d978bc0685a_S.jpg" alt="34-yr-old-woman-raped-family-robbed-of-rs-10000" /></a><font color="#ff3300"><b>Featured</b></font><p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Jaipur: A 34-year-old woman was allegedly raped by five persons who also robbed her family of Rs 10,000 in cash and other valuables in Vaishali Nagar area here.</span></p>

<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The incident took place last night when the accused entered the house after removing window grills and held the family hostage, DCP Kailash Bishnoi said.</span><br /> <br /><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The woman alleged that she was raped whereas her husband and father-in-law were injured with iron rods, he said, adding, the duo was admitted to SMS hospital.</span><br /> <br /><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Two minor children were also present in the house when the incident occurred.</span><br /> <br /><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The accused took away Rs 10,000 in cash, ornaments and other valuables. A few suspected persons have been rounded up for questioning, police said. A case in relevant sections has been registered with Vaishali nagar police station.</span></p>]]></description>
			<dc:creator>Edited by Devendra Singh || Updated: 18:53 IST</dc:creator>
			<pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2014 13:22:45 -0600</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.newsx.com/regional/other-states/item/26880-34-yr-old-woman-raped-family-robbed-of-rs-10000</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>NCP awaiting word from Congress on seat sharing formula</title>
			<link>http://www.newsx.com/regional/maharashtra/item/26879-ncp-awaiting-word-from-congress-on-seat-sharing-formula</link>
			<description><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/870299ee10c8d07ea72818fbee5f0f0c_Generic.jpg"><img align="right" border="0" src="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/870299ee10c8d07ea72818fbee5f0f0c_S.jpg" alt="ncp-awaiting-word-from-congress-on-seat-sharing-formula" /></a><font color="#ff3300"><b>Featured</b></font><p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Mumbai: With notification for the October 15 Maharashtra assembly elections to be issued tomorrow, the NCP today said it is still awaiting a proposal from the Congress to discuss the seat-sharing arrangement but at the same time has completed all preparations to contest the polls which are barely a month away.</span></p>

<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">State Unit President Sunil Tatkare told reporters that his party had asked the Congress to take a call on finalising the seat sharing formula, but there has been "no response" as yet from the ally.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"We are hoping that we are invited for talks in a day or two as the poll notification will be issued tomorrow and the process of filing of nominations will begin. But, at the same time, we have completed our election preparations as well," he added.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Tatkare was talking to reporters after inducting Malegaon MLA belonging to the Jan Surajya Shakti party, Mufti Mohammed Ismail. Along with Ismail, leaders of local outfits from Malegaon also joined the party.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Tatkare said more inductions into the party will be held in next few days. Referring to senior leaders like Suryakanta Patil and Babanrao Pachpute resigning to join the BJP, Tatkare said ,"it was said that NCP is in trouble as everyone is quitting the party. But it is not so."</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">To a question on whether NCP plans to weaken the Congress by inducting Independent MLAs who had contested as rebels from seats in Congress quota, Tatkare said Congress was a very old party and such things don't weaken it.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Replying to Chief Minister Prithviraj Chavan's criticism of NCP that it fields rebels to defeat the Congress candidates, Tatkare said the same thing can be applied to Congress as well.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"In Parbhani Lok Sabha seat, Congress MLA Ramprasad Bordikar worked to defeat NCP nominee but still no action was taken against the legislator. While NCP sacked Deepak Kesarkar, Sawantwadi MLA who refused to campaign for Nilesh Rane in Ratnagiri-Sindhudurg Lok Sabha seat," he added.(more) PTI MR DK</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Tatkare further said if Congress says Supriya Sule won Baramati Lok Sabha seat because of them, the fact is that Congress won the Hingoli and Nanded lok Sabha seats because of NCP.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The NCP is demanding an equal number of seats (144) as the Congress in the State Assembly, a stand which it feels is "practical and justified."</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The Sharad Pawar-led outfit emerged as the single largest party with 71 seats in 2004, but ceded the chief ministerial post to ally Congress in return for two additional cabinet and three ministers of state berths.</span></p>]]></description>
			<dc:creator>Edited by Devendra Singh || Updated: 18:45 IST</dc:creator>
			<pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2014 13:10:06 -0600</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.newsx.com/regional/maharashtra/item/26879-ncp-awaiting-word-from-congress-on-seat-sharing-formula</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Drug trafficking: 7 months jail for HIV+ South African woman</title>
			<link>http://www.newsx.com/regional/delhi/item/26878-drug-trafficking-7-months-jail-for-hiv-south-african-woman</link>
			<description><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/2413a55603d75bf7855b16493f4a9a7d_Generic.jpg"><img align="right" border="0" src="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/2413a55603d75bf7855b16493f4a9a7d_S.jpg" alt="drug-trafficking-7-months-jail-for-hiv-south-african-woman" /></a><font color="#ff3300"><b>Featured</b></font><p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">An HIV positive South African woman has been awarded seven months in jail for carrying 12 kgs of a narcotic drug, by a Delhi court which took a lenient view considering her economic and social background.</span></p>

<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">It said that imposing a harsh sentence on her would not subserve the interests of justice.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"The sole purpose of punishing an offender is not retribution alone and that the courts while sentencing an offender must make an attempt, within the parameters of the law, to afford an opportunity to the offender to reform himself and lead the life of a normal, useful member of society," Special Judge Anu Grover Baliga said, while also imposing a fine of Rs 20,000 on her.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The court noted that her health was deteriorating due to the disease, saying, "The convict has been diagnosed to be HIV+ and suffering from hypertension and gynaecological ailments and that her blood CD4 count has been deteriorating and that her three minor children have nobody to look after in South Africa."</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">However, on the submission by the woman that she was forced to indulge in drug trafficking due to her economic condition, the court observed that "poverty cannot be taken as a justification for commission of crimes".</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">According to the prosecution, the Narcotics Control Bureau (NCB) team acting on secret information apprehended the woman in the wee hours of March 16, 2014 at Indira Gandhi International Airport here while she was about to fly to Nairobi by Kenya Airlines.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">During search conducted on her, 12 kgs of ephedrine hydrochloride (a contraband substance under Narcotic Drugs and Psychotropic Substances Act) was recovered from her suitcase.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The woman, who was charged under various sections of NDPS Act, confessed to the crime and pleaded guilty.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">She was convicted by the court for offences entailing a maximum punishment of 10 years rigorous imprisonment and Rs 1 lakh fine.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Pleading for leniency, the woman had told the court that she had two minor daughters and one minor son residing in South Africa and they have no one to look after as her husband had left them.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The woman said with nowhere to go, she had started residing at her husband's friend's house on rent in South Africa but had to leave the house after he raped her 15-year- old daughter.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">She told the court that it is to sustain her family that she was forced to indulge in drug trafficking.</span></p>]]></description>
			<dc:creator>Edited by Devendra Singh || Updated: 18:08 IST</dc:creator>
			<pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2014 12:33:48 -0600</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.newsx.com/regional/delhi/item/26878-drug-trafficking-7-months-jail-for-hiv-south-african-woman</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>#RightToBeVIP: RLD supporters continue to fight for their leader Ajit Singh’s eviction, 20 injured in the clash</title>
			<link>http://www.newsx.com/national/top-stories/item/26877-fighttobevip-rld-supporters-continue-to-fight-for-their-leader-ajit-singhs-eviction-20-injured-in-the-clash</link>
			<description><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/c4966846e6c0156337db862f2168c6de_Generic.jpg"><img align="right" border="0" src="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/c4966846e6c0156337db862f2168c6de_S.jpg" alt="fighttobevip-rld-supporters-continue-to-fight-for-their-leader-ajit-singhs-eviction-20-injured-in-the-clash" /></a><font color="#ff3300"><b>Featured</b></font><p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">UTTAR PRADESH: The central government’s action against the former ministers overstaying at their official bungalows met with politics and a stiff roadblock on Thursday.</span></p>

<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Against the eviction of their leader Ajit Singh, protestors from Rashtriya Lok Dal (RLD) fought a pitched battle in the backyard of Delhi.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Apart from blocking the arterial National Highway 58 at Muradnagar, situated 38 km away from the National Capital, and causing terrible traffic jams, the supporters of Singh’s RLD even attempted to cut off the water supply to Delhi.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">20 people including police officials and protestors were injured in the clashes that then followed.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Ajit Singh has been in the possession of the Lutyen’s zone bungalow at Tughlak Road for more than three decades which was earlier occupied by his father, former Prime Minister Chaudhary Charan Singh.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Now, as the Centre pressurizes Singh to vacate the place, his supporters have opted to hold a protest in context of turning the property into a memorial after late Charan Singh.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The disconnection of power supply to the house two days ago is what brought the issue to a head. It was ordered after continual eviction notices and a quasi-judicial order was unsuccessful to have any effect on the same.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The issue has now been tied to Jat pride as Haryana elections are soon to approach and Chief Minister of the state Bhupinder Singh Hooda has written to Urban Development Minister Venkaiah Naidu echoing the demand for a memorial.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">On the other hand, the Centre has objected the demand pointing out that no such demand was made in past 27 years or ever after the death of Charan Singh in 1987.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The Centre also expressed that had it been the case that Ajit Singh, a minister in the UPA government wished for a memorial, it could have been easily granted then.</span><br /><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Naidu in his response to Hooda pointed out that in 2000, the Union cabinet had ‘banned such conversions and this has been issued as a policy guideline’. Further, in July 2013, the Supreme Court had also asked the Centre not to convert bungalows into memorials, he wrote.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">“It is certainly not about the bungalow but it is all about the sentiments attached to it. It shall surrender the bungalow on September 25 but our party shall continue its fight to turn the same into a memorial,” Ajit Singh being adamant to create a memorial said.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Congress however slamming government on Ajit Singh’s bungalow issue said, “Unbecoming of democracy of our kinds, to cut off the water and electricity is extremely reprehensible, As far as aspirations of people from western UP is concern, this is for them to reach to the present government in our democratic set up, but we would say the way it has been done is extremely reprehensible and unbecoming of our kind of government.”</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Ajit Singh is among 30 former ministers and parliamentarians, whose power supply were disconnected by the New Delhi Municipal Council. Jitendra Singh and Mohd Azharuddin were also in the list.</span></p>]]></description>
			<dc:creator>Written by Charnamrit Sachdeva</dc:creator>
			<pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2014 12:09:47 -0600</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.newsx.com/national/top-stories/item/26877-fighttobevip-rld-supporters-continue-to-fight-for-their-leader-ajit-singhs-eviction-20-injured-in-the-clash</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Nalanda University reopens after 800 years, Sushma Swaraj inaugurates academic session </title>
			<link>http://www.newsx.com/regional/other-states/item/26876-nalanda-university-reopens-after-800-years-sushma-swaraj-inaugurates-academic-session</link>
			<description><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/e5442fd02522a7c6051a647d3f8f4551_Generic.jpg"><img align="right" border="0" src="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/e5442fd02522a7c6051a647d3f8f4551_S.jpg" alt="nalanda-university-reopens-after-800-years-sushma-swaraj-inaugurates-academic-session" /></a><p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Ancient Nalanda University, which once attracted students from across the world, was today formally inaugurated in its modern ‘avatar’ by External Affairs Minister Sushma Swaraj here.</span></p>

<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Hailing the occasion, Swaraj said as in the past the university would serve as ‘bridge and foundation’ in linking the country with the world through knowledge.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">“It is wrong to say that today we are rejuvenating the 427 AD Nalanda University because tradition never dies ...</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Nalanda is not just a university but a tradition.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">“Nalanda University is a link between the past, present and future,” she said at the function held at the International Conventional Centre.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Nalanda University was deeply etched in history and like in ancient times would serve as a magnet to attract students from across the globe, Swaraj said, adding during her recent visit to Bangladesh she found people there were interested in it.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Seeing the ‘tremendous response’ to the university it has now been decided that it would not be confined only to east Asian nations but would be opened to students from other countries too, she said and promised all help to it.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The Centre had already alloted Rs. 2,727 crore, which would be spent in building a high class campus of the university in 10 years, Swaraj said.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The minister supported Bihar Chief Minister Jitan Ram Manjhi’s request to the Centre for an airport here so that foreign students and dignatories could reach the university, which is situated about 12 km from the ruins of the ancient one and 100 km from Patna, easily.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Manjhi was present at the function along with many foreign dignatories, besides members of his ministry.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The foreign dignatories included Lim Thuan Kuan, Singapore High Commissioner to India and Chalit Manityakur, ambassador of Thailand in India. Diplomats from Australia, Vietnam, Germany, Japan and Laos were also present.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Secretary, East, to the External Affairs Ministry Anil Wadwah and university Vice-chancellor Gopa Sabarwal, faculty member Lord Meghnad Desai, former diplomat N K Singh and a host of intellectuals were also present on the occasion.</span></p>]]></description>
			<dc:creator>Edited by Devendra Singh || Updated: 17:36 IST</dc:creator>
			<pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2014 12:03:23 -0600</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.newsx.com/regional/other-states/item/26876-nalanda-university-reopens-after-800-years-sushma-swaraj-inaugurates-academic-session</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>IITs among world's 5 best entrepreneurial undergraduate institutes</title>
			<link>http://www.newsx.com/national/nation/item/26875-iits-among-worlds-5-best-entrepreneurial-undergraduate-institutes</link>
			<description><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/a9799555aef4850cd8847a1710cd2d95_Generic.jpg"><img align="right" border="0" src="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/a9799555aef4850cd8847a1710cd2d95_S.jpg" alt="iits-among-worlds-5-best-entrepreneurial-undergraduate-institutes" /></a><font color="#ff3300"><b>Featured</b></font><p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">New Delhi: Indian Institutes of Technology (IITs) are ranked fourth on a list of 50 best entrepreneurial undergraduate institutes in the world, HRD Minister Smriti Irani said on Friday.</span></p>

<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The ranking was compiled by PitchBook Data, a US-based private equity and venture capital research firm.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Sharing the achievement at an AICTE conclave on 'entrepreneurship education', Irani said the feat calls for further celebrations as the IITs have been ranked higher than some of the best Ivy League universities such as Harvard.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The minister referred to the rankings while underscoring the need to inculcate an entrepreneurial mindset among the youths, noting that knowledge and entrepreneurship are key to take the country ahead.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">In the study, the research firm found that the IITs had a total of 264 entrepreneurs, who have founded 205 companies and cumulatively raised USD 3.15 billion.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The paradigm of education, she said, should be such that it is able to cross the knowledge with analytical skills and logical reasoning, helping students acquire skills and entrepreneurial qualities.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">To help realise the objective, "we hope to revamp our pedagogy and curriculum to make it more relevant to our society and our students market-ready not just domestically but also internationally". "We would also like to inculcate an entrepreneurial mindset not only in schools and colleges through changes in curricula but through introduction of teaching training and teaching material designed especially for entrepreneurship," she said.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Noting that innovation has become increasingly open and collaborative today as opposed to the existing close inhouse innovation models, the minister suggested development of innovation clusters to promote collaboration between research organisations, industry and university.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"This would help exploit knowledge that would otherwise be left commercially unused by university," the minister said, underlining the need for a rigorous, transparent and outcome based method in evaluating the impact of programmes.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Irani said her ministry would soon operationalise a 'council for higher education and industry' so that "together we can bring about solution that our nation has so long sought".</span></p>]]></description>
			<dc:creator>Edited by Devendra Singh || Updated: 17:28 IST</dc:creator>
			<pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2014 11:53:37 -0600</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.newsx.com/national/nation/item/26875-iits-among-worlds-5-best-entrepreneurial-undergraduate-institutes</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Ghangapatna land scam: Odisha Crime Branch arrest seven persons</title>
			<link>http://www.newsx.com/regional/other-states/item/26874-ghangapatna-land-scam-odisha-crime-branch-arrest-seven-persons</link>
			<description><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/e9473fdbf582af4449f5b5f07e9dfee5_Generic.jpg"><img align="right" border="0" src="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/e9473fdbf582af4449f5b5f07e9dfee5_S.jpg" alt="ghangapatna-land-scam-odisha-crime-branch-arrest-seven-persons" /></a><p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Bhubaneswar: The Crime Branch of Odisha Police on Friday arrested seven persons including four government officials in connection with the land scam at Ghangapatna village.</span></p>

<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"The CB has been investigating into the land fraud case based on an FIR filed by the Revenue department. We have arrested seven persons including four officials of the Revenue department for their involvement in fraudulent activities," additional director general of police (ADG) BK Sharma told reporters here.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Stating that the accused persons were arrested under different sections of the IPC including cheating (420), Sharma said all seven persons were found having link with the land fraud. They included two former additional tehsildar rank officers, one revenue inspector, and one record keeper.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"The three others were members from public who had specific roles in registration of land in name of certain persons," the ADG said.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Based on the report of the Khurda district collector and local tehsildar, Chief Minister Naveen Patnaik last month directed the crime branch to probe the land fraud involving about 100 acre of land at Ghangapatna village. The CB was told to submit its report within two months.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Meanwhile, Revenue Minister Bijayshree Routray said the government has last week retrieved 76 acre of land in the illegal possession of different persons.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">This 76 acre of land included 7 acre in the name of Nivriti Export Private Limited, in which BJP state president K V Singhdeo's ex-MP wife Sangeeta and daughter Nivriti were directors, the minister said adding that another 5 acre of land belonged to Gokarneswar Charitable Trust where BJD MP Kalpataru Das's MLA son Pranab Balabantray was a trustee.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Both Singhdeo and Das have expressed surprise over the minister's statement saying that they were not aware of any notice before the government recorded the land in name of the government.</span></p>]]></description>
			<dc:creator>Edited by Devendra Singh || Updated: 17:18 IST</dc:creator>
			<pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2014 11:47:17 -0600</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.newsx.com/regional/other-states/item/26874-ghangapatna-land-scam-odisha-crime-branch-arrest-seven-persons</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title> Nirbhaya centres in UP districts to help women</title>
			<link>http://www.newsx.com/regional/up/item/26873-nirbhaya-centres-in-up-districts-to-help-women</link>
			<description><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/fc933a1b1768d900b951ce4a5e78c306_Generic.jpg"><img align="right" border="0" src="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/fc933a1b1768d900b951ce4a5e78c306_S.jpg" alt="nirbhaya-centres-in-up-districts-to-help-women" /></a><font color="#ff3300"><b>Featured</b></font><p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Lucknow: With a view to providing prompt help to victims of crime against women, Nirbhaya centres will be opened in all the districts of Uttar Pradesh.</span></p>

<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"Nirbhaya centres will be set up in women hospitals or women police stations with the view to providing immediate medical and other help to the victims of crime or violence against women," an official release quoting Chief Secretary Alok Ranjan said here today.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The Chief Secretary said arrangements should be made for lodging FIRs of the victims at these Nirbhaya centres.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The centres have been named after 'Nirbhaya (fearless one)' -- the young woman, who had been brutally gang-raped in a moving bus in New Delhi in December 2012, triggering a nation-wide outrage.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">For running and overall monitoring of these centres at the state level, a committee headed by the Chief Secretary would be set up soon and nodal officers nominated in home, medical, health and law departments for completing necessary works for setting up these centres, the release said.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The Chief Secretary, who chaired a meeting in this regard with officials concerned, also directed them to complete the formalities for setting up Asha Jyoti Kendras in pilot districts for providing all schemes meant for empowerment of women under one umbrella.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">He also called for taking up awareness drive for women through the state information department and warned that laxity in providing relief to victims and ensuring safety of women would not be tolerated.</span></p>]]></description>
			<dc:creator>Edited by Devendra Singh || Updated: 17:11 IST</dc:creator>
			<pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2014 11:38:57 -0600</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.newsx.com/regional/up/item/26873-nirbhaya-centres-in-up-districts-to-help-women</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>FM channels can start with using AIR news: Prakash Javadekar </title>
			<link>http://www.newsx.com/national/nation/item/26872-fm-channels-can-start-with-using-air-news-prakash-javadekar</link>
			<description><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/82ec6f142ec82b579965a9418392b395_Generic.jpg"><img align="right" border="0" src="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/82ec6f142ec82b579965a9418392b395_S.jpg" alt="fm-channels-can-start-with-using-air-news-prakash-javadekar" /></a><font color="#ff3300"><b>Featured</b></font><p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Union Minister for Information and Broadcasting Prakash Javadekar on Friday said that government has an idea of allowing FM Radio channels broadcast news provided by All India Radio (AIR), which in the coming days could also work as a news agency.</span></p>

<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Mr. Javadekar said that FM Radio is allowed to disseminate information related to traffic and other things like government announcements.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">“The issue is of the news, and we have said to start with we are saying, AIR news. People thought it has to be only clip from AIR news, so the AIR bulletins in the same voice, as it is will have to be broadcast,” Mr. Javadekar, who was speaking at an event organised by the CII said.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">He added that people on AIR speak well, have credibility and that is also because of the style.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">“So those who want the clip can get it and we will also charge for it. And for those who don’t want the clip, in their voice say the DJ to read out news....so AIR has various news (categories) and we will also work as a news agency and will give you more and more news from AIR terminals.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">“From there also you can pick up news and go ahead. So that’s the beginning point,” he added.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Later on the sidelines of another event, Mr. Javadekar was asked whether the news agency, that he had spoken about, would cater to private FM Radio stations.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">“This is just an idea,” he said and added that the government will review the ground situation.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">“We will take review of what exists on ground. What can it function as and how it can work? So, you do not ask as if I have started a news agency. It’s an idea. It is in conceptual stage,” he said.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">He was asked about a proposal that news agencies can also be a source for FM Radio and whether the government has rejected it?</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">“No, nothing is rejected.... To start with we are starting with AIR news clipping. After the experience, we will move ahead,” he said.</span></p>]]></description>
			<dc:creator>Edited by Devendra Singh || Updated: 17:05 IST</dc:creator>
			<pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2014 11:27:33 -0600</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.newsx.com/national/nation/item/26872-fm-channels-can-start-with-using-air-news-prakash-javadekar</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Chinese President Xi quoted Tagore, Gandhi to spiritually connect with Indians</title>
			<link>http://www.newsx.com/national/nation/item/26871-chinese-president-xi-quoted-tagore-gandhi-to-spiritually-connect-with-indians</link>
			<description><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/e21016143e6ce82f6420f82c40502403_Generic.jpg"><img align="right" border="0" src="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/e21016143e6ce82f6420f82c40502403_S.jpg" alt="chinese-president-xi-quoted-tagore-gandhi-to-spiritually-connect-with-indians" /></a><font color="#ff3300"><b>Featured</b></font><p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Beijing: Chinese President Xi Jinping tried to spiritually connect with Indians by quoting poets like Rabindranath Tagore whose works are very popular in China, analysts have said.</span></p>

<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Xi has quoted a wide range of prominent figures and idiomatic phrases from China and India to illustrate Beijing's diplomatic philosophy and its increased priorities in South Asia during his address at the Indian Council of World Affairs yesterday, state media reported.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Xi also quoted Rabindranath Tagore, Mahatma Gandhi and Jawaharlal Nehru.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"Grow like a summer flower, magnificently; die like an autumn leaf, quietly and beautifully!" Xi said, quoting Tagore, adding that he had read several poetry collections of the late Nobel Prize winner in literature.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">To boost cultural exchanges with South Asian countries, China will provide 10,000 scholarships to the region, training to 5,000 people and help in cultivation of 5,000 Chinese- language teachers, Xi said.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"Spiritual resonance is something that goes way beyond the reach of politics and economy," said Sun Shihai, a researcher on Southern Asian studies at the Chinese Academy of Social Sciences.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">In the speech, Xi said all South Asian countries are "China's important cooperative partners", and he defined the cooperative agenda as "a huge treasure to be exploited".</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Fu Xiaoqiang, an expert on South Asian studies at the China Institutes of Contemporary International Relations, said China has taken a "balanced approach" when designing its South Asian policies - presenting priorities placed in both the regional power of India as well as the other small and mid-size countries.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">To illustrate Beijing's unchanged commitment to its peaceful development path, Xi quoted an ancient Chinese saying: "Do unto others as you would be done by."</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Zhou Gang, former Chinese ambassador to India, said the Maritime Silk Road is a platform of great openness and many South Asian countries, including Maldives, Sri Lanka, Bangladesh and Pakistan, have already been brought into the initiative.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Under the ambitious project, China plans to build a maze of roads for the revival of ancient Silk Road connecting China, Central Asia with Europe, Bangladesh, China, India, Myanmar (BCIM) Economic Corridor.</span></p>]]></description>
			<dc:creator>Edited by Devendra Singh || Updated: 16:23 IST</dc:creator>
			<pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2014 10:51:27 -0600</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.newsx.com/national/nation/item/26871-chinese-president-xi-quoted-tagore-gandhi-to-spiritually-connect-with-indians</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Gujarat fisherman's body arrives in Mumbai from Pakistan</title>
			<link>http://www.newsx.com/regional/maharashtra/item/26870-gujarat-fisherman-body-arrives-in-mumbai-from-pakistan</link>
			<description><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/5f840ef3bc3c128a515be12f8bb4777e_Generic.jpg"><img align="right" border="0" src="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/5f840ef3bc3c128a515be12f8bb4777e_S.jpg" alt="gujarat-fisherman-body-arrives-in-mumbai-from-pakistan" /></a><font color="#ff3300"><b>Featured</b></font><p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Vadodara: Fifty-five days after his death in a Pakistani jail under mysterious circumstances, the body of a Gujarat fisherman was flown to Mumbai from where it is being brought to his native village in the state on Friday.</span></p>

<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The mortal remains of fisherman Bala Narad Singad, who died in a Karachi jail on July 25, reached Mumbai late last night and is expected to reach his native Soneri village in Una taluka of Gir Somnath district later today, Gujarat fisheries department official J K Rathod, who received the body, told PTI over phone.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The state government had deputed Rathod and another official P Gadiya to receive the body in Mumbai.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">After completing the required formalities at Mumbai's Chhatrapati Shivaji international airport, the two officials left with the body last evening.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"We have received the body which is being taken by road to Soneri village," Gadiya said.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Singad, his two brothers and some other fishermen were arrested by Pakistani Marine Security Agency (PMSA) off Jakhau coast in April this year for allegedly straying into its territorial waters illegally.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The Pakistani government has not mentioned anything over the release of his two brothers, also lodged in the same jail in Karachi, an official said.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Learning about his death after over a month ago in August, the Indian High Commission office had informed the government. The state government did not want matters to be delayed further and hence, took immediate steps to complete the procedures to bring back Singad, an official had earlier said.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Singad's wife Samjuben had earlier said, "I learnt about the death of my husband from a letter written by his younger brother Bharat (lodged in Karachi jail) which was delivered to me August 28."</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The letter, written soon after her husband's death was not allowed to reach her for over a month, the woman, who is illiterate, had alleged. She had later approached her village sarpanch, who informed her about the demise.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">She also demanded a probe into the 'mysterious' circumstances leading to the death of her husband.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Meanwhile, All Gujarat Fisherman Association appealed to the Gujarat government and social organizations to provide financial assistance to the deceased's family, comprising his wife and three minor children.</span></p>]]></description>
			<dc:creator>Edited by Devendra Singh || Updated: 15:48 IST</dc:creator>
			<pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2014 10:15:48 -0600</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.newsx.com/regional/maharashtra/item/26870-gujarat-fisherman-body-arrives-in-mumbai-from-pakistan</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Floods wipe out crops in Jammu, losses pegged at Rs 365 cr</title>
			<link>http://www.newsx.com/regional/j-k/item/26869-floods-wipe-out-crops-in-jammu-losses-pegged-at-rs-365-cr</link>
			<description><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/f259f3f224b54749c68f79f1c5e49dec_Generic.jpg"><img align="right" border="0" src="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/f259f3f224b54749c68f79f1c5e49dec_S.jpg" alt="floods-wipe-out-crops-in-jammu-losses-pegged-at-rs-365-cr" /></a><font color="#ff3300"><b>Featured</b></font><p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Jammu: As the flood waters recede, a grim picture emerges from the agriculture sector in Jammu where the deluge has washed away crops worth Rs 365 crore and 13,000 hectares of cultivable land.</span></p>

<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">While the Maize crop suffered Rs 248 crore damage, rice/paddy crops suffered a loss of Rs 48 crore followed by Rs 40 crore loss to vegetable crops besides damage to pulses and saffron.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"Loss of 365 crore has been caused to crops in Jammu region in the flash floods", Director, Agriculture, Jammu, S S Jamwal told PTI.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">He said an elaborate report has been submitted to the government on the basis of the preliminary assessment done across the region.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Jamwal, who himself led teams of the Department of Agriculture to assess the losses caused to crops and farm lands, said 13,000 hectares of agriculture land has been washed away in the floods.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Tawi, Basantar and Devak rivers have changed courses at places resulting in major damage to huge chunks of agriculture land in Niki Tawi and Ramgarh belts of Jammu and Samba districts.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"It is the biggest challenge for the government to ensure protections to farm lands and later reclaiming these lands for use in agriculture activities", Jamwal said.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Taking stock of the situation, the Department of Agriculture has pressed into service its monitoring teams to make an on-the-spot assessment of damages caused to vegetables, paddy, maize, pulses and fodder crops by the flash floods and heavy rains in different districts of Jammu division since September 14.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Jamwal has also held detailed interaction with farmers of Kukrian, Kothey Manhasan, Haripur, Chak Jaggar, Thub, Mahaveer Basti, Kothey Puran, Ghou Manhasan, Sandawan, Bhagatpur, Suhagani, Chakrali, Nai basti, Marh, Kana Chak, Kayanpur, Panjore and adjoining areas of Marh sub-division.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Hit by the floods, farmer Parkash Singh of Kukerian area said, "There has been tremendous loss to the farmers of the area who need immediate relief and help. We have lost everything. Our life depends on farming".</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Similarly, Janak Singh said, "We cannot do farming for the next one year as some land has been washed away and some rendered barren by the floods. We will take more than one year to reclaim the farm land".</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">In Suhagani panchyat and adjoining areas, about 500 acres of cultivated area has been affected due to breach of protection bunds and floods in Tawi River.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Some of the areas on which paddy and other Kharif crops were grown have been totally washed away. The land has been converted into a riverbed and silt, sand and stones have deposited on a large cultivated area.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"Vegetables particularly hybrids and cauliflower sown by farmers have been completely destroyed due to heavy and continuous rains", Jamwal said.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Vegetables which are sown early like radish and knol-khol have been damaged in Nai Basti, Marh, Gajansoo Kana Chak and Panjore areas, he said.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">At Kanachak, farmers said the losses to vegetable and other rabi crops was huge as areas, which were supplying vegetables to Jammu city, are now unsuitable for cultivation.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Many pumpsets and cattle sheds have also been damaged and washed away due to the flood waters besides irrigation channels.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The Director, after visiting the affected areas at Kothey Manhasan, Nai basti, Kana Chak and Panjore, has instructed the field staff to identify the damaged patches and carry out detailed documentation of the crops and the areas damaged.</span></p>]]></description>
			<dc:creator>Edited by Devendra Singh || Updated: 15:35 IST</dc:creator>
			<pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2014 10:03:56 -0600</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.newsx.com/regional/j-k/item/26869-floods-wipe-out-crops-in-jammu-losses-pegged-at-rs-365-cr</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>J&amp;K facing shortage of 12 lakh measles vaccines: CM Omar Abdullah </title>
			<link>http://www.newsx.com/regional/j-k/item/26868-jk-facing-shortage-of-12-lakh-measles-vaccines-cm-omar-abdullah</link>
			<description><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/3e42961c007eda4dd0db0a0df29005c6_Generic.jpg"><img align="right" border="0" src="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/3e42961c007eda4dd0db0a0df29005c6_S.jpg" alt="jk-facing-shortage-of-12-lakh-measles-vaccines-cm-omar-abdullah" /></a><font color="#ff3300"><b>Featured</b></font><p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Srinagar: Jammu and Kashmir Chief Minister Omar Abdullah on Friday said while the Centre has been very helpful in dealing with floods, the state is facing a shortage of nearly 12 lakh measles vaccines, which they will now purchase from the open market.</span></p>

<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"We need to vaccinate 13 lakh children in the age group of 0-15 years so that we do not have measles epidemic. We have only received one lakh vaccines from the Centre. I have now told my department not to wait for this for Government of India and procure vaccine from the market," Omar told PTI.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">He said the Centre has been helpful and "in some respects their own channels have been inundated by the floods in the scale of what is required. Therefore, supplies are not as quickly available to us as we would have liked."</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Omar said money has been put in the Chief Minister's Relief Fund, which was set up after the devastating floods.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"As of yesterday, about Rs 55 crore were deposited in the CM Relief fund, most of it from seven or eight states. Largest individual contribution, I am grateful to him, has been from (UP Chief Minister) Akhilesh Yadav. Other states have given Rs 5 crore etc. I have money which I am going to purchase vaccines and chlorine tablets," he said.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Against a promised 50 lakh chlorine tablets, the state had received only 10 lakh tablets so far from the Centre, Omar said, adding, "We will try, whatever is to be procured, to procure it from open market."</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The Chief Minister said according to conservative estimates, the damage to equipment in the ground floors of various state hospitals which were affected by the floods is to the tune of Rs 150 crore.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"All our diagnostic and laboratory equipment that has been mostly in the ground floor and even at first floor has been damaged. A conservative estimate of the Health Department is that hospital equipment worth Rs 150 crore has been destroyed.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"Obviously, this can't be replaced overnight. But in our memorandum which we are going to submit to the Government of India, this is going to be part of it so that we can immediately procure new equipment so that we make these hospital fully functional," he said.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Omar said he has put money at the disposal of Medical Superintendents of various hospitals in the state for purchase of life saving drugs.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"I have put the money at the disposal of Superintendents of Hospitals--Rs 5 lakh for district hospitals, Rs 10 lakh for city hospitals and Rs 15 lakh for SKIMS hospital-- so that they can make purchases themselves, so they should not be short of anything," he added.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Omar said there was no sign of any epidemic or outbreak of disease in the flood affected areas so far.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"Fortunately, the patients who are coming to the medical camps of the army, CRPF, NDRF and government medical camps, there is no trend of epidemic of illness. It is very regular treatments that they are coming for which leads us to believe that thus far there are no signs of epidemic," he said.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The Chief Minister said disposal of over 300 animal carcasses has been a major achievement in preventing the outbreak of diseases.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"One of the major things we have achieved is disposal of animal carcases. We have disposed off 300 animal carcasses so far in three nights we have started two days ago. If you calculate it, one truck carries only 2 carcasses at a time... that is about 150 truck ferries," he added</span></p>]]></description>
			<dc:creator>Edited by Devendra Singh || Updated: 15:16 IST</dc:creator>
			<pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2014 09:43:45 -0600</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.newsx.com/regional/j-k/item/26868-jk-facing-shortage-of-12-lakh-measles-vaccines-cm-omar-abdullah</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>President Xi Jinping keeps tradition alive, meets family of Dr Kotnis</title>
			<link>http://www.newsx.com/national/nation/item/26867-president-xi-jinping-keeps-tradition-alive-meets-family-of-dr-kotnis</link>
			<description><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/6d1556511909b9c689c49b6776161f89_Generic.jpg"><img align="right" border="0" src="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/6d1556511909b9c689c49b6776161f89_S.jpg" alt="president-xi-jinping-keeps-tradition-alive-meets-family-of-dr-kotnis" /></a><font color="#ff3300"><b>Featured</b></font><p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">New Delhi: It has been a tradition with visiting Chinese leaders to meet the family of Dr Dwarkanath Kotnis and President Xi Jinping followed it by meeting the sister of the famed physician and recalling "the fine representative who gave his precious life in China".</span></p>

<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">For the meeting, the Chinese Consulate-General in Mumbai specially flew Kotnis's 93-year-old sister Manorama, who is wheel chair bound, and her family to Delhi so that Xi could meet and felicitate her.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Dr Kotnis, who is revered in China for his contributions, was an Indian physician who died while treating Chinese soldiers during the second China-Japan war in 1942.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"In the critical hour of Chinese people's war with Japanese aggression, the Indian medical mission travelled thousands of miles to assist us and fought shoulder to shoulder with people of my father's generation against Japanese fascists. The fine representative, young Dr Kotnis gave his precious life in China.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"General Mao Zedong once wrote in his honour 'The Chinese army has lot a helping hand, the nation a friend. Let us always bear in mind his international spirit,'" Xi said, remembering Kotnis.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Appreciating the gesture of the Chinese leadership who keeps meeting the family till date, Manorama, who has partially lost her vision, said, "Even when a new Consul- General takes charge in Mumbai, he comes to visit the family of Dr Kotnis."</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"Till now, our extended family has visited China 20 times. They have maintained the warmth for all these years," said Rajan Borkar, son-in-law of Kotni's elder brother, whose family now takes care of Manorama.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Kotnis went to China in 1937 as part of an Indian medical mission after China was invaded by Japan. He served on the battlefield and saved lives of many Chinese soldiers. After working for four years in China, he fell ill and died at a young age of 32.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">In China, Kotnis fell in love and married a Chinese nurse who worked with him. Quo Qinglan, who remained in China, died in 2012 in the city of Dalian. They also had a son, who was studying to become a doctor but he died when he was 24.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">This is not a first time that a visiting Chinese leader has met the family of Kotnis. Last year, Premier Li Keqiang had met his family.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">In 2006, when Chinese President Hu Jintao visited India, he met the family. In the past, the Kotnis family met with then premier Zhou Enlai in 1950, followed by president Jiang Zemin in 1996.</span></p>]]></description>
			<dc:creator>Edited by Devendra Singh || Updated: 15:09 IST</dc:creator>
			<pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2014 09:33:40 -0600</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.newsx.com/national/nation/item/26867-president-xi-jinping-keeps-tradition-alive-meets-family-of-dr-kotnis</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Delhi to witness 14th Family Fun Car Rally</title>
			<link>http://www.newsx.com/cities/item/26866-delhi-to-witness-14th-family-fun-car-rally</link>
			<description><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/992c1e7f77b4cb912443c1605b879cf7_Generic.jpg"><img align="right" border="0" src="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/992c1e7f77b4cb912443c1605b879cf7_S.jpg" alt="delhi-to-witness-14th-family-fun-car-rally" /></a><font color="#ff3300"><b>Featured</b></font><p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">NEW DELHI: Coming 21st September, Sunday, Delhi will experience the most thrilling day of the season as Rashi Entertainment in association with Skoda India continues their legacy with 14th Family Fun Car Rally with a bang in Delhi.</span></p>

<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The rally of Skoda families in Delhi NCR will flag off from Hotel Tivoli Garden Resort Hotel, Chhattarpur and will cross the city roads of Delhi to serve a purpose towards our society.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The rally is famous for its several unique features that make it special for the participants. The ambience at the starting point will exude energy, youthfulness and enthusiasm</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Rajeev Jain, Director Rashi Entertainment states, “This annual rally organized by us has become a much sought after event for all car lovers. It holds the promise of fun, adventure and excitement all the way till the finishing point.”</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">While allowing a total of four members from a family to participate, the high point of the rally is that it gives the participants an opportunity to pile up scores through randomly picking up points from sealed envelopes and general knowledge questionnaires available at the marshal booths scattered along the 55 km long route.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">“SKODA will always focus on developing long lasting relationships with its customers. We urge customers to come and experience the brand and enjoy the product as an entire family. This initiative will also give them an opportunity to understand the brand and experience some other core values of SKODA. We encourage customers to constantly give us feedback and become part of the Škoda family” Mr Jay Bhasin, Regional Head Sales – North &amp;East, SKODA AUTO India.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Participants are suggested to decorate their car in the most attractive manner and also dress themselves up to contest for the Best Dressed Family.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">This annual event has become a much sought after event for people of all genres. It holds the promise of fun, adventure and excitement all the way till the finishing point. For registration, one can log on to www.skodafuncarrally.com.</span></p>]]></description>
			<dc:creator>NewsX Bureau</dc:creator>
			<pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2014 09:19:03 -0600</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.newsx.com/cities/item/26866-delhi-to-witness-14th-family-fun-car-rally</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Heavy rain forecast in Odisha</title>
			<link>http://www.newsx.com/regional/other-states/item/26865-heavy-rain-forecast-in-odisha</link>
			<description><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/edfc8c3f499fe471fa342202c63db72c_Generic.jpg"><img align="right" border="0" src="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/edfc8c3f499fe471fa342202c63db72c_S.jpg" alt="heavy-rain-forecast-in-odisha" /></a><font color="#ff3300"><b>Featured</b></font><p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Bhubaneswar: Heavy rainfall coupled with gusty surface wind is likely to lash some places of interior and coastal Odisha till tomorrow due to a low pressure which triggered rains in several areas during last couple of days.</span></p>

<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Rain and thundershower is likely to occur at most places of Odisha under the impact of the low pressure area over northwest and adjoining westcentral Bay of Bengal off Odisha coast, the MeT office said here today.</span></p>]]></description>
			<dc:creator>Edited by priyanka Kukreja || Updated: 14:50 IST</dc:creator>
			<pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2014 09:11:45 -0600</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.newsx.com/regional/other-states/item/26865-heavy-rain-forecast-in-odisha</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Indian Muslims will live and die for India: Modi</title>
			<link>http://www.newsx.com/national/nation/item/26864-indian-mulims-will-live-and-die-for-india-modi</link>
			<description><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/32616438ad67dc4fa6ad4fee7d7d7ae6_Generic.jpg"><img align="right" border="0" src="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/32616438ad67dc4fa6ad4fee7d7d7ae6_S.jpg" alt="indian-mulims-will-live-and-die-for-india-modi" /></a><font color="#ff3300"><b>Featured</b></font><p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Indian Muslims will live and die for India, Prime Minister Narendra Modi has said, maintaining that they will not dance to the tunes of terror outfit al-Qaeda.</span></p>

<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">“My understanding is that they are doing injustice towards the Muslims of our country. If anyone thinks Indian Muslims will dance to their tune, they are delusional.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">“Indian Muslims will live for India, they will die for India — they will not want anything bad for India,” he told CNN in an interview.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">He was also put a question about the remarkable phenomenon that out of the 170 million Muslims in India, there seemed to be no or very few members of al-Qaeda even though it is in Afghanistan and Pakistan. “What is it that has made this community not as susceptible?”</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Mr. Modi answered that first he was not the authority for doing a psychological and religious analysis on this.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">“But the question is whether or not humanity should be defended in the world. Whether or not believers in humanity should unite. This is a crisis against humanity, not a crisis against one country or one race. So we have to frame this as a fight between humanity and inhumanity, nothing else,” he said.</span></p>]]></description>
			<dc:creator>Edited by priyanka Kukreja || Updated: 14:20 IST</dc:creator>
			<pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2014 08:47:31 -0600</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.newsx.com/national/nation/item/26864-indian-mulims-will-live-and-die-for-india-modi</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Gold worth Rs 2.4 cr seized at Chennai airport</title>
			<link>http://www.newsx.com/regional/other-states/item/26863-gold-worth-rs-24-cr-seized-at-chennai-airport</link>
			<description><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/30b2929d1eb51098677af1f69376252d_Generic.jpg"><img align="right" border="0" src="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/30b2929d1eb51098677af1f69376252d_S.jpg" alt="gold-worth-rs-24-cr-seized-at-chennai-airport" /></a><p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Gold worth about Rs 2.4 crore was seized in two separate incidents at the airport here, officials said today.</span></p>

<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Air Intelligence Unit of Customs seized seven kg gold, worth Rs two crore, from one Manmeet Singh Bhardwaj who arrived from Hong Kong last night.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The gold was recovered from his check-in baggage, officials said.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">In the second incident, 1.4 kg of gold was seized from a woman passenger who arrived from Kuala Lumpur last night. She had concealed the gold in her body, they said, adding, it was valued around Rs 40 lakh.</span></p>]]></description>
			<dc:creator>Edited by priyanka Kukreja || Updated: 13:50 IST</dc:creator>
			<pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2014 08:04:13 -0600</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.newsx.com/regional/other-states/item/26863-gold-worth-rs-24-cr-seized-at-chennai-airport</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Assam: Jawan seriously injured in ambush by ULFA militants</title>
			<link>http://www.newsx.com/national/nation/item/26862-assam-jawan-seriously-injured-in-ambush-by-ulfa-militants</link>
			<description><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/db7be279166f605cbb6b1b1862402f4b_Generic.jpg"><img align="right" border="0" src="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/db7be279166f605cbb6b1b1862402f4b_S.jpg" alt="assam-jawan-seriously-injured-in-ambush-by-ulfa-militants" /></a><font color="#ff3300"><b>Featured</b></font><p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Sibsagar: A jawan was seriously injured in an ambush by ULFA(I) militants at Kanobari in Assam's Sibsagar district on Friday.</span></p>

<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The militants exploded two IEDs between two tea gardens at Kherbari Tiniali when jawans of the 4th Rajput Regiment were moving in three trucks to Naharkatia at about 7.30 am, police officials said.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">One jawan was seriously wounded and has been hospitalised. A truck was also damaged in the explosion, they said.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The IEDs were exploded by remote control as long wires were found in the area. A bag was also recovered from the spot, but its contents would be known after bomb experts examined it.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Many tea bushes of the tea gardens on both sides of the road were burnt under the impact of the explosion, they said.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The local people claimed that the sound of the blast could be heard about half a km away.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The Paresh Baruah-led ULFA (I) in an email to the media claimed responsibility for the blast.</span></p>]]></description>
			<dc:creator>Edited by priyanka Kukreja || Updated: 13:40 IST</dc:creator>
			<pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2014 07:51:48 -0600</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.newsx.com/national/nation/item/26862-assam-jawan-seriously-injured-in-ambush-by-ulfa-militants</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Spouse's personality influences career success</title>
			<link>http://www.newsx.com/life-style/most-popular/item/26861-spouses-personality-influences-career-success</link>
			<description><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/6651e56d2a1d89f5d3a9dd945f558886_Generic.jpg"><img align="right" border="0" src="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/6651e56d2a1d89f5d3a9dd945f558886_S.jpg" alt="spouses-personality-influences-career-success" /></a><font color="#ff3300"><b>Featured</b></font><p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Washington: When it comes to pay raises, promotions and other measures of career success, your spouse at home may play a key role, a new research suggests.</span></p>

<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"Our study shows that it is not only your own personality that influences the experiences that lead to greater occupational success, but that your spouse's personality</span><br /><span style="font-size: 10pt;">matters too," said Joshua Jackson, assistant professor of psychology in Arts &amp; Sciences from Washington University in St Louis and lead author of the study.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Although we marry "for better for worse, for richer for poorer," this study is among the first to demonstrate that the personality traits of the spouse we choose may play a role in determining whether our chosen career makes us richer or poorer.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"The experiences responsible for this association are not likely isolated events where the spouse convinces you to ask for a raise or promotion," Jackson said.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"Instead, a spouse's personality influences many daily factors that sum up and accumulate across time to afford one the many actions necessary to receive a promotion or a raise," said Jackson.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The findings are based on a five-year study of nearly 5,000 married people ranging in age from 19 to 89, with both spouses working in about 75 per cent of the sample.</span><br /><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Jackson and co-author Brittany Solomon, a graduate student in psychology at Washington University, analysed data on study participants who took a series of psychological tests to assess their scores on five broad measures of personality - openness, extraversion, agreeableness, neuroticism and conscientiousness.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">In an effort to gauge whether these spousal personality traits might be seeping into the workplace, they tracked the on-the-job performance of working spouses using annual surveys designed to measure occupational success - self-reported opinions on job satisfaction, salary increases and the likelihood of being promoted.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Workers who scored highest on measures of occupational success tended to have a spouse with a personality that scored high for conscientiousness, and this was true whether or not both spouses worked and regardless of whether the working spouse was male or female, the study found.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The study was published in the journal Psychological Science.</span></p>]]></description>
			<dc:creator>Edited by priyanka Kukreja || Updated: 13:20 IST</dc:creator>
			<pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2014 07:34:10 -0600</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.newsx.com/life-style/most-popular/item/26861-spouses-personality-influences-career-success</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Tibetans stage protest outside Xi's hotel in New Delhi</title>
			<link>http://www.newsx.com/national/nation/item/26860-tibetans-stage-protest-outside-xis-hotel-in-new-delhi</link>
			<description><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/dee9d70461d687f58e0e569a65c66aef_Generic.jpg"><img align="right" border="0" src="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/dee9d70461d687f58e0e569a65c66aef_S.jpg" alt="tibetans-stage-protest-outside-xis-hotel-in-new-delhi" /></a><font color="#ff3300"><b>Featured</b></font><p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Scores of Tibetans staged a protest this morning outside the Hotel Taj Palace, where Chinese President Xi Jinping and his wife are staying.</span></p>

<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Protesters carrying placards that read “Freedom is my birth right”, “Freedom of Tibet, Security of India” raised anti—China slogans.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Some Tibetans also tried to enter the premises of the hotel, but police managed to prevent them from doing so.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">“As the Tibetans refused to budge, scores of protesters have been detained by the police,” said a senior police officer.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Security has been tightened around the hotel.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">A group of Tibetans had on Thursday staged a protest and clashed with police outside Hyderabad House, the venue for the bilateral talks between the Chinese President and Prime Minister Narendra Modi.</span></p>]]></description>
			<dc:creator>Edited by priyanka Kukreja || Updated: 12:55 IST</dc:creator>
			<pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2014 07:19:02 -0600</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.newsx.com/national/nation/item/26860-tibetans-stage-protest-outside-xis-hotel-in-new-delhi</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Pleasant morning in Delhi</title>
			<link>http://www.newsx.com/cities/item/26859-pleasant-morning-in-delhi</link>
			<description><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/157f7e5aad2d39eae96897b105cd2981_Generic.jpg"><img align="right" border="0" src="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/157f7e5aad2d39eae96897b105cd2981_S.jpg" alt="pleasant-morning-in-delhi" /></a><font color="#ff3300"><b>Featured</b></font><p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">New Delhi: It was a pleasant start to the day in Delhi today with the minimum temperature settling at 25.3 degrees Celsius.</span></p>

<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The humidity level recorded till 8:30 AM was 64 per cent.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The maximum temperature is expected to go up to 35 degrees Celsius.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Met officials said that there was no likelihood of rains.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Yesterday the maximum temperature settled at 35.7 degrees Celsius, which was a notch above normal, while the minimum settled at 25.</span></p>]]></description>
			<dc:creator>Edited by priyanka Kukreja || Updated: 12:20 IST</dc:creator>
			<pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2014 07:01:53 -0600</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.newsx.com/cities/item/26859-pleasant-morning-in-delhi</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Chargesheet against ten Indian Mujahideen members for waging war against India</title>
			<link>http://www.newsx.com/national/nation/item/26858-chargesheet-against-ten-indian-mujahideen-members-for-waging-war-against-india</link>
			<description><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/324fe9791c1ade0bc3a7b8c22efabca5_Generic.jpg"><img align="right" border="0" src="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/324fe9791c1ade0bc3a7b8c22efabca5_S.jpg" alt="chargesheet-against-ten-indian-mujahideen-members-for-waging-war-against-india" /></a><font color="#ff3300"><b>Featured</b></font><p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Jodhpur: Ten alleged members of Indian Mujahideen who were arrested this year from Rajasthan and Jharkhand were on Thursday booked for waging war against the country as police filed a charge-sheet against them in the court of Additional Chief Judicial Magistrate here.</span></p>

<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The ACJM court transferred the case to District and Sessions Court where the case will be heard from October 1.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Anti-Terrorist Squad of Rajasthan Police filed the charge sheet with operative part running into 97 pages and comprising a list of 340 documents.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">After receiving the charge sheet, Magistrate Pawan Agarwal referred the case to the District and Sessions Court.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The ATS had arrested the terror suspects in March-April this year.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Seven of the accused -- Mohd Sakib Ansari (23), Barkat Ali (28), Adil Ansari (23), Ashraf Ali (40), Mashraf Iqbal (32), Mohd Jawed (28) and Zaheer Haq (30) -- were nabbed from different parts of Jodhpur.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Of the remaining three, Mohd Maroof (23) was picked up from Jaipur, Mohd Ammar Yassar (22) from Dhanbad and Mohd Waqar Azhar alias Haneef alias Mohsin (21) from Pali.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"All the suspects are charged under Sections 4, 5, 6 of the Explosive Substances Act 1908 and Sections 16, 17, 18, 18A,, 18B, 19, 20, 23, 38 of the Unlawful Activities (Prevention) Act 1967 and Sections 120 B, 121, 121A, 122 of IPC," said a defence counsel.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Adil has been charged only under Section 19 of Explosive Substances Act and Section 212 of IPC, defence counsel said.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The charge sheet also includes a list of the things seized during its investigation of the case.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">These include a gunny bag containing black gun powder weighing 34.880kg, two samples of the same in a small bottle (meant for testing of intensity), residuals of the test of Improvised Explosive Device (IED), an empty shell of detonator, some SIM cards, cell phones, laptops, CPUs and a Gypsy car and documents like ration card, etc.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Section 121 of Indian Penal Code relates to waging, or attempting to wage war, or abetting waging of war against the Government of India.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">And, Section 122 pertains to collecting arms with an intention of waging war against the government.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">According the charge sheet, Mohd Maroof, an engineering student, came into contact with one Mohd Atta on internet who introduced him to the head of IM, Iqbal Bhatkal, and his brother Riyaz Bhatkal.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Maroof later became a member of IM and learnt to use proxy servers to conceal his identity besides all the tricks to escape being caught by any surveillance agency.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Maroof was trying to set up an IM module in Rajasthan, which was finally busted by the ATS in March this year.</span></p>]]></description>
			<dc:creator>Edited by priyanka Kukreja || Updated: 11:50 IST</dc:creator>
			<pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2014 06:19:49 -0600</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.newsx.com/national/nation/item/26858-chargesheet-against-ten-indian-mujahideen-members-for-waging-war-against-india</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Rupee up 10 paise against dollar in early trade</title>
			<link>http://www.newsx.com/national/business/item/26857-rupee-up-10-paise-against-dollar-in-early-trade</link>
			<description><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/cb5d5638d43189b913afbb4b72487aaf_Generic.jpg"><img align="right" border="0" src="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/cb5d5638d43189b913afbb4b72487aaf_S.jpg" alt="rupee-up-10-paise-against-dollar-in-early-trade" /></a><font color="#ff3300"><b>Featured</b></font><p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Mumbai: Extending its rising streak for the the fourth straight day, the rupee strengthened by 10 paise to 60.74 against the US dollar in early trade today at the Interbank Foreign Exchange market on continued selling of the American currency by exporters.</span></p>

<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">A higher opening of the domestic equity market also supported the rupee but the dollar's rise against other currencies overseas capped the gains, dealers said.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Yesterday, the Indian rupee ended eight paise higher at 60.</span></p>]]></description>
			<dc:creator>Edited by priyanka Kukreja || Updated: 11:30 IST</dc:creator>
			<pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2014 06:03:57 -0600</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.newsx.com/national/business/item/26857-rupee-up-10-paise-against-dollar-in-early-trade</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Sitharaman's baggage lost on AI flight on way to Australia</title>
			<link>http://www.newsx.com/national/nation/item/26856-sitharamans-baggage-lost-on-ai-flight-on-way-to-australia</link>
			<description><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/71961eb13d6a355fa4222c909e0e1576_Generic.jpg"><img align="right" border="0" src="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/71961eb13d6a355fa4222c909e0e1576_S.jpg" alt="sitharamans-baggage-lost-on-ai-flight-on-way-to-australia" /></a><p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Melbourne: Union Minister of State for Commerce and Industry Nirmala Sitharaman has become the latest victim of misplaced baggage on an Air India flight as her checked in luggage went missing on her way to Australia.</span></p>

<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"Landed in Sydney to take a connecting flight to Cairns. My checked in luggage not traceable," Sitharaman tweeted after landing in Sydney this morning.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">She is travelling to Cairns to attend G20 meeting of finance ministers and central bank governors on the weekend.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">An hour later, she tweeted, "On board my connecting flight to Cairns. All my formal wear in the lost suitcase! Not sure I can buy Saris in Cairns! Situation precarious."</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Air India Manager Madhu Mathen later said the lost baggae has been traced and it will be reaching Cairns in next six hours.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">G20 Finance Ministers and Central Bank Governors meeting is scheduled to be held in Cairns and expected to be attended by delegates, their families and staff from 24 countries and 12 international organisations, such as the International Monetary Fund, World Bank and the United Nations.</span></p>]]></description>
			<dc:creator>Edited by priyanka Kukreja || Updated: 11:20 IST</dc:creator>
			<pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2014 05:41:41 -0600</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.newsx.com/national/nation/item/26856-sitharamans-baggage-lost-on-ai-flight-on-way-to-australia</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>#ScotlandDecides: Scotland rejects Independence from the United Kingdom</title>
			<link>http://www.newsx.com/national/top-stories/item/26855-scotland-appears-set-to-reject-independence</link>
			<description><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/155815508a5b210b9af83c492ed00598_Generic.jpg"><img align="right" border="0" src="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/155815508a5b210b9af83c492ed00598_S.jpg" alt="scotland-appears-set-to-reject-independence" /></a><font color="#ff3300"><b>Featured</b></font><p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">LONDON: In a historic referendum that threatened to rip the United Kingdom apart, Scotland has voted against independence, the BBC forecast today post the preliminary results showed 54.3 percent voting ‘NO’ and 45.7 percent voting ‘Yes’.</span></p>

<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The First Deputy Prime Minister of Scotland, Nicola Sturgeon on Friday accepted that the campaign of her party for Independence had likely been beaten.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">“It looks at though we might not get the Yes vote that I was hoping for,” Nicola Sturgeon expressed.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The ‘Yes’ camp had its hopes high on a massive victory in the largest constituency of Glasglow to close the gap, but could in real register a winning gap of 54.5 percent to 46.5 percent.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">“We have just had a whole slew of results here... that really did add to the evidence that the 'No' side are looking set to win this referendum and probably doing so fairly comfortably,” polling expert John Curtice and added that it would, ‘require something extraordinary’ to put off a ‘No’ victory ‘within the next two to three hours’.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">At 84 percent, so far, turnout for the vote looked set to break records for United Kingdom post-war elections.</span></p>]]></description>
			<dc:creator>Written by Charnamrit Sachdeva</dc:creator>
			<pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2014 05:17:17 -0600</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.newsx.com/national/top-stories/item/26855-scotland-appears-set-to-reject-independence</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Param Vir Chakra Memorial dedicated to nation</title>
			<link>http://www.newsx.com/national/nation/item/26854-param-vir-chakra-memorial-dedicated-to-nation</link>
			<description><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/52899a6a7f1e74f02def3e476ad1063d_Generic.jpg"><img align="right" border="0" src="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/52899a6a7f1e74f02def3e476ad1063d_S.jpg" alt="param-vir-chakra-memorial-dedicated-to-nation" /></a><font color="#ff3300"><b>Featured</b></font><p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Port Blair: A memorial built as a testimony to the sacrifices made by soldiers has been dedicated to the nation at the Marina Park here.</span></p>

<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The memorial was dedicated to the nation by Andaman and Nicobar Islands Lieutenant Governor Lt Gen A K Singh (Retd).</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Param Vir Chakra, India's highest gallantry award, is awarded to officers and enlisted personnel of all military branches for the highest degree of valour and self-sacrifice in the presence of the enemy and may be awarded posthumously.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The memorial would serve as an inspiration to the youth about the bravery, valour and the supreme sacrifices made by the country's brave sons, Singh said.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Expressing hope that this memorial would invigorate feelings of courage and love for the country among the youth, the Lt Governor complimented the Port Blair Municipal Corporation for developing the memorial.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">While Cellular Jail in the islands is a testimony to the sacrifices made by our freedom fighters, this memorial will remind the people about the sacrifices made by our brave hearts in the post Independence era, he said.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">In his speech on the occasion, the Commander-in-Chief A&amp;N Command, Vice Admiral Pradeep Kumar Chatterjee said patriotism is in the DNA of the islanders and with the construction of this memorial, they have shown their respect to the valiant men of the nation.</span></p>]]></description>
			<dc:creator>Edited by priyanka Kukreja || Updated: 10:30 IST</dc:creator>
			<pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2014 04:52:55 -0600</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.newsx.com/national/nation/item/26854-param-vir-chakra-memorial-dedicated-to-nation</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>'Peaceful ties between dragon and elephant key to world peace'</title>
			<link>http://www.newsx.com/national/nation/item/26853-peaceful-ties-between-dragon-and-elephant-key-to-world-peace</link>
			<description><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/f02f14206ad8aea2a196246efb390880_Generic.jpg"><img align="right" border="0" src="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/f02f14206ad8aea2a196246efb390880_S.jpg" alt="peaceful-ties-between-dragon-and-elephant-key-to-world-peace" /></a><font color="#ff3300"><b>Featured</b></font><p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">New Delhi: If the "Chinese dragon" and the "Indian elephant" co-exist harmoniously, it will not only benefit 2.5 billion people in the two nations but also have far-reaching impact in the region and the world, Chinese President Xi Jinping said here on Thursday.</span></p>

<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"Both China and India are influential countries in the world. When our two nations speak with one voice, the whole world will listen attentively," China's official Xinhua news agency quoted Xi as telling Prime Minister Narendra Modi during their talks.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">If the "Chinese dragon" and the "Indian elephant" co-exist harmoniously and realise peaceful, cooperative development, it will benefit 2.5 billion people in the two nations as well as those in other developing countries, and will have far- reaching effect in the region and the world as a whole, Xi said.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The report said that China and India have decided to step up trade and investment engagement to forge a closer development partnership despite their border disputes "left over by history".</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"On border issue, the two countries should continue to carry out friendly consultation to seek a fair and reasonable solution that both sides can accept," Xi, also General Secretary of the ruling Communist Party of China, said.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"Before the border issue is eventually solved, we should jointly manage and control our disputes in a proper way and maintain peace and tranquility in the border regions. We should not let the border issue affect our bilateral relations," the Chinese President said as tension persisted in Chumar area in northeast Ladakh where Chinese troops were reported to have stepped up their presence today camping at three places in the Indian territory and refusing to vacate.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">India asserts that the border dispute covered about 4,000 km, while China claims that it confined to about 2,000 km to the area of Arunachal Pradesh, which it refers as Southern Tibet.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The report also noted that the two Asian neighbours have agreed on investment in India's railways, industrial parks and the adjustment of their trade imbalance.</span></p>]]></description>
			<dc:creator>Edited by priyanka Kukreja || Updated: 10:20 IST</dc:creator>
			<pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2014 04:43:04 -0600</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.newsx.com/national/nation/item/26853-peaceful-ties-between-dragon-and-elephant-key-to-world-peace</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Barack Obama nominates Richard Verma as new US envoy to India</title>
			<link>http://www.newsx.com/national/nation/item/26852-barack-obama-nominates-richard-verma-as-new-us-envoy-to-india</link>
			<description><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/cb9206ce065bad12637d99fa9544a7d5_Generic.jpg"><img align="right" border="0" src="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/cb9206ce065bad12637d99fa9544a7d5_S.jpg" alt="barack-obama-nominates-richard-verma-as-new-us-envoy-to-india" /></a><font color="#ff3300"><b>Featured</b></font><p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Washington: President Barack Obama on Thursday nominated Indian-American, Richard Rahul Verma, as the next US Ambassador to India, ahead of Prime Minister Narendra Modi's visit to Washington later this month.</span></p>

<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">If confirmed by the US Senate, Verma, who earlier served as the Assistant Secretary of State for Legislative Affairs and is now in the private sector, would be the first Indian-American to serve as the top US diplomatic position in New Delhi.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Obama announced his nomination along with several other key administration appointments.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"I am grateful that these impressive individuals have chosen to dedicate their talents to serving the American people at this important time for our country. I look forward to working with them in the months and years ahead," Obama said in a statement.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The US Embassy in New Delhi is currently headed by a Charge d'affaires, Kathleen Stephens.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Verma, 45, said to be a close confidant of the President and also former Secretary of State Hillary Clinton, currently serves as Senior Counselor at Steptoe &amp; Johnson LLP and Albright Stonebridge Group. He is also a Senior National Security Fellow at the Center for American Progress.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Previously, he was Assistant Secretary for Legislative Affairs at the Department of State from 2009 to 2011 and Partner at Steptoe and Johnson LLP from 2007 to 2009.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">He was Senior National Security Advisor, Counsel and Foreign Policy Advisor to the Senate Majority Leader Harry Reid from 2002 to 2007, and an Associate at Steptoe &amp; Johnson from 1998 to 2002.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Verma served on active duty in the US Air Force from 1994 to 1998 and received, among other decorations, the Meritorious Service Medal and Air Force Commendation Medal.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Earlier in his career, Verma was a Field Representative for the National Democratic Institute in Eastern Europe and worked in the House of Representatives for Congressman John P Murtha.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">He served on the Commission on the Prevention of Weapons of Mass Destruction, Proliferation and Terrorism in 2008 and has been a member of the Secretary of State's Foreign Affairs Policy Board.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Verma currently serves on the boards of Human Rights First, the Clinton Foundation, and the National Democratic Institute. He received a BS from Lehigh University, a JD from American University, and an LLM from Georgetown University Law Center.</span></p>]]></description>
			<dc:creator>Edited by priyanka Kukreja || Updated: 9:20 IST</dc:creator>
			<pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2014 03:45:10 -0600</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.newsx.com/national/nation/item/26852-barack-obama-nominates-richard-verma-as-new-us-envoy-to-india</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>It was a challenge to dance with Hrithik: Katrina Kaif</title>
			<link>http://www.newsx.com/showbiz/celebrities/item/26851-it-was-a-challenge-to-dance-with-hrithik-katrina-kaif</link>
			<description><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/98bb10e848885c5a5b38f39842ad2d5b_Generic.jpg"><img align="right" border="0" src="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/98bb10e848885c5a5b38f39842ad2d5b_S.jpg" alt="it-was-a-challenge-to-dance-with-hrithik-katrina-kaif" /></a><font color="#ff3300"><b>Featured</b></font><p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Mumbai: Hrithik Roshan, considered one of the best dancers in Bollywood is seen doing some high octane dance moves in his next 'Bang Bang' and his co-star Katrina Kaif says she had to try hard to match up to the actor.</span></p>

<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The 31-year-old actress is playing the female lead in the action thriller, which is the official remake of the Hollywood film 'Knight and Day' starring Tom Cruise and Cameron Diaz.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"Dancing with Hrithik was the biggest challenge.</span></p>]]></description>
			<dc:creator>Edited by priyanka Kukreja || Updated: 9:00 IST</dc:creator>
			<pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2014 03:22:34 -0600</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.newsx.com/showbiz/celebrities/item/26851-it-was-a-challenge-to-dance-with-hrithik-katrina-kaif</guid>
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
