<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet href="http://www.newsx.com/components/com_obrss/assets/xsl/atom-to-html.xsl" type="text/xsl"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
	<channel>
		<title>rss</title>
		<description><![CDATA[RSS Feed]]></description>
		<link>http://www.newsx.com/</link>
		<lastBuildDate>Mon, 15 Sep 2014 12:19:59 -0600</lastBuildDate>
		<generator>FeedCreator 1.8.3 (obRSS 1.9)</generator>
		<atom:link href="http://www.newsx.com/component/obrss/rss?format=" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
		<image>
			<url>http://www.newsx.com/images/</url>
			<title>rss</title>
			<link>http://www.newsx.com/</link>
			<description>RSS Feed</description>
		</image>
		<item>
			<title>UP: FIR registered against son of Congress MP after clash in Amethi</title>
			<link>http://www.newsx.com/regional/up/item/26716-up-fir-registered-against-son-of-congress-mp-after-clash-in-amethi</link>
			<description><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/5d89d37127731678b9c9a033b6917068_Generic.jpg"><img align="right" border="0" src="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/5d89d37127731678b9c9a033b6917068_S.jpg" alt="up-fir-registered-against-son-of-congress-mp-after-clash-in-amethi" /></a><font color="#ff3300"><b>Featured</b></font><p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Amethi: An FIR has been registered against 257 people, including Anant Vikram Singh, the son of Congress MP Sanjay Singh, in connection with the killing of a constable in a clash.</span></p>

<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"An FIR has been registered against 257 people including 250 unidentified ones in connection with yesterday's clash at Amethi police station," District Magistrate Jagatraj Tiwari told reporters here on Monday.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Holding Anant Vikram responsible for the clash between his supporters and the police, the DM said he (Vikram) incited people by sending them messages to gather at the spot.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">45-year-old constable Vijay Mishra was Sunday killed and six persons were injured in a clash between police and Anant Vikram's supporters here, who had gathered outside 'Bhoopati Bhawan', Sanjay Singh's ancestral house, to prevent his (Sanjay's) entry inside it.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Anant Vikram occupies the residence with his mother and Sanjay Singh's first wife, Garima.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Sanjay Singh and his second wife Amita are locked in a dispute over the ancestral house with Anant Vikram and Garima.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Apart from Anant Vikram Singh, those named in the FIR include his supporters Vijay Pratap Singh, Chintu Kumar, Sanjay, Awadhesh, Binnu, and Sunil, Tiwari said.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"While Anant has alleged that he is facing life threat from father Sanjay, a similar allegation was made by Sanjay. We have deputed three SHOs of different police stations inside the Bhoopati Bhawan," he said.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Later, addressing a press conference, Congress MP Sanjay Singh alleged that his first wife Garima was using Anant Vikram for property.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"I will decide who should live in the 'Rajmahal' and who should not after taking legal advice. Anant and daughters Shaivya and Mahima lived with me for 19 years. When Anant was with me he was captain in Merchant Navy and now he is going to become accused of murder," Singh said.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Replying to a question, Singh said, "I am a responsible father and will get the issue resolved. Some people in media are exaggerating the issue."</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">He further said, that he was owner of the property and could not be stopped from entering it.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The District Magistrate, on being asked why Sanjay was given permission to hold a press conference and Anant was denied permission for the same, said, "As Sanjay is the owner of the 'Rajmahal' he will decide whom to talk to. As far as Anant is concerned, he was denied permission as it could create violence in the area".</span></p>]]></description>
			<dc:creator>Edited by Kirti Dwivedi | Updated: 4:35 IST</dc:creator>
			<pubDate>Mon, 15 Sep 2014 12:09:33 -0600</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.newsx.com/regional/up/item/26716-up-fir-registered-against-son-of-congress-mp-after-clash-in-amethi</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>No proposal for Modi-Sharif meeting in New York: Abdul Basit</title>
			<link>http://www.newsx.com/national/nation/item/26715-no-proposal-for-modi-sharif-meeting-in-new-york-abdul-basit</link>
			<description><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/39a7c786550a0aabe24c94f5fc4df0d4_Generic.jpg"><img align="right" border="0" src="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/39a7c786550a0aabe24c94f5fc4df0d4_S.jpg" alt="no-proposal-for-modi-sharif-meeting-in-new-york-abdul-basit" /></a><font color="#ff3300"><b>Featured</b></font><p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">New Delhi: Pakistan Monday said it was not aware of any proposal for a meeting between Prime Minister Narendra Modi and his Pakistani counterpart Nawaz Sharif in New York on the margins of UN General Assembly this month.</span></p>

<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"As of this moment, I am not aware of any proposal on this (Modi-Sharif meeting)," Pakistan High Commissioner to India Abdul Basit said here at a function.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">While Prime Minister Modi will be in New York from September 26 to 29, Sharif is scheduled to be there from September 22 to 27.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;"> Though there is an overlapping of small period when both the leaders will be there, a meeting is unlikely given the frosty ties between the two countries.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The two countries witnessed a war of words last month as India cancelled Foreign Secretary-level meeting after Pakistan went ahead with talks with the Kashmiri separatists despite India asking it to choose a "dialogue with India or talks with separatists".</span></p>]]></description>
			<dc:creator>Edited by Kirti Dwivedi | Updated:  4:55 IST</dc:creator>
			<pubDate>Mon, 15 Sep 2014 11:23:17 -0600</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.newsx.com/national/nation/item/26715-no-proposal-for-modi-sharif-meeting-in-new-york-abdul-basit</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Hafiz Saeed is a Pak national, he is free to roam around, says Abdul Basit</title>
			<link>http://www.newsx.com/national/nation/item/26714-hafiz-saeed-is-a-pak-national-he-is-free-to-roam-around-says-abdul-basit</link>
			<description><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/f4821773dbf4bcb506c9aae73a286651_Generic.jpg"><img align="right" border="0" src="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/f4821773dbf4bcb506c9aae73a286651_S.jpg" alt="hafiz-saeed-is-a-pak-national-he-is-free-to-roam-around-says-abdul-basit" /></a><font color="#ff3300"><b>Featured</b></font><p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">New Delhi: Even as New Delhi's demand that 26/11 mastermind Hafiz Saeed be brought to justice, remains unheeded, Pakistan High Commissioner to India Abdul Basit on Monday described the Jamaat-ud-Dawa chief as a Pakistani national who is “free to roam around” in the country.</span></p>

<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Speaking to reporters on the sidelines of an event here, Basit said, “ Hafiz Saeed is a Pakistani national, he is free to roam around. What's the problem?” The Pak envoy was responding to a query on reports that Saeed is roaming around freely in Pakistan-occupied Kashmir (PoK).</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Basit also pitched for early resumption of talks between the two countries. “Let us hope that the talks between India &amp; Pakistan resume sooner than later,” he said.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The 'what's wrong with Saeed' assertion by the Pakistani official comes at a time when Indian intelligence officials have warned of a possible attempt by Saeed to launch a major terror attack in India.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Prior to his visit to th PoK, the JuD chief was seen near the Indo-Pak international border in Rajasthan. Later Indian intelligence agencies had issued an alert about the presence of a group of terror operatives waiting across the border waiting to cross over into India.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">India has been pressing Pakistan to act against Saeed, given his link to the 26/11 Mumbai attack that led to death of 166 people. However, Pakistan has all along maintained that there is no credible evidence linking him to the terror attack.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Importantly, Ajmal Kasab, the lone terrorist captured during 26/11 terror strike, had claimed meeting Saeed in a training camp in PoK, where all 10 terrorists who attacked Mumbai were given commando training.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The US State Department has also placed Saeed-run JuD on the list of banned foreign terrorist organisations and offered a reward of $10 million for information leading to the arrest of Saeed. JuD is a frontal organization for terror group Laskar-e-Toiba (LeT).</span></p>]]></description>
			<dc:creator>Edited by Kirti Dwivedi | Updated: 4:35 IST</dc:creator>
			<pubDate>Mon, 15 Sep 2014 11:10:26 -0600</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.newsx.com/national/nation/item/26714-hafiz-saeed-is-a-pak-national-he-is-free-to-roam-around-says-abdul-basit</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Love Jihad: Will play an active role to clear doubts on Muslim laws, AIMPLB  says </title>
			<link>http://www.newsx.com/national/nation/item/26713-love-jihad-will-play-an-active-role-to-clear-doubts-on-muslim-laws-aimplb-says</link>
			<description><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/8b551e870b1d56ba9001161ead4a2804_Generic.jpg"><img align="right" border="0" src="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/8b551e870b1d56ba9001161ead4a2804_S.jpg" alt="love-jihad-will-play-an-active-role-to-clear-doubts-on-muslim-laws-aimplb-says" /></a><font color="#ff3300"><b>Featured</b></font><p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Lucknow: In the wake of a raging controversy over the issue of 'Love Jihad' raised by right wing outfits, All India Muslim Personal Law Board has decided to remove misconceptions among people with regard to the subject besides concepts pertaining to the Islamic law.</span></p>

<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">At a conference on 'Islamic laws of Nikah, Polygamy and Adoption' organised here Sunday night, AIMPLB decided to enhance the activities of its Tafheem-e-Shariat committee to remove misconceptions about different aspects of the Sharia Law, the board's member Maulana Khalid Rasheed Farangimahli said Monday.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"Several speakers expressed concern over topics such as a non-Islamic subject like 'Love Jihad' being made an issue, attempts to spread hatred among the new generation about Islam, wrong reporting in media on Sharia law, presenting the Sharia views in a distorted manner in the courts."</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"AIMPLB's efforts will be to underline the need to remove doubts among non-Muslims on Sharia and other issues," he said.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">'Love Jihad' is the term being used by right wing Hindu outfits while referring to alleged conversion of Hindu girls through marriage, a concept which has been dubbed as "false propaganda" by Muslim religious leaders and scholars saying that Islam does not allow forced conversions.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Farangimahli said the Tafheem-e-Shariat committee would apprise the people, especially Muslim lawyers, on the concepts of nikah (marriage), polygamy, adoption and other such issues through seminars, books and other means, with a view to provide them better knowledge on these subjects so that they can present their case in the court properly, he said.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Besides the committee would also distribute pamphlets, books and use media for the purpose.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">To clear misconceptions, AIMPLB had organised similar conferences in Mumbai, Hyderabad, Bengaluru, Delhi and Aligarh and it now plans to hold another such conference next month in Allahabad, Farangimahli said, adding that by February next year, six such conferences would be organised in the country.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The speakers at the conference especially made reference to the allegations on Muslims regarding polygamy and pointed out that Islam permits it only under special circumstances, Farangimahli said.</span></p>]]></description>
			<dc:creator>Edited by Kirti Dwivedi | Updated: 4:35 IST</dc:creator>
			<pubDate>Mon, 15 Sep 2014 10:58:43 -0600</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.newsx.com/national/nation/item/26713-love-jihad-will-play-an-active-role-to-clear-doubts-on-muslim-laws-aimplb-says</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Nearly 300 people dead in Pakistan floods</title>
			<link>http://www.newsx.com/world/pakistan/item/26712-nearly-300-people-dead-in-pakistan-floods</link>
			<description><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/f7e4b22121e8776f7273b81c854fd858_Generic.jpg"><img align="right" border="0" src="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/f7e4b22121e8776f7273b81c854fd858_S.jpg" alt="nearly-300-people-dead-in-pakistan-floods" /></a><font color="#ff3300"><b>Featured</b></font><p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Islamabad: Nearly 300 people have died and over two million affected due to rains and devastating floods in Pakistan, even as swelling waters continued to ravage the southern Punjab province, officials said today.</span></p>

<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The floods were triggered after massive monsoon rains that started on September 3 and continued for several days.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Reema Zubari of National Disaster Management Authority (NDMA) said that 209 people have been killed in Punjab, 66 in Pakistan-occupied Kashmir and 14 in Gilgit-Baltistan region.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">She said that more than 2,410,000 were affected in Punjab and over 40,000 in PoK and Gilgit-Baltistan.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The floods have also destroyed crops over 1.5 million acres, dislocating poor localities and washing away villages.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The force of deluge is now on the Panjnad headworks, which is the last main waterwork in Punjab, before it starts hitting southern province of Sindh.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">TV channels reported that several villages were flooded after a breach in the Lakhpal embankment along the Chenab river.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">They said the death toll from yesterday's capsized boat has reached 20. The boat was carrying a wedding party. The groom was among the dead.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The army and civilian rescue and relief workers are working hard to save people.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Meanwhile, life is becoming normal in the flood hit areas of Sialkot and Gujranwala.</span></p>]]></description>
			<dc:creator>Edited by Kirti Dwivedi | Updated: 4:05 IST</dc:creator>
			<pubDate>Mon, 15 Sep 2014 10:42:24 -0600</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.newsx.com/world/pakistan/item/26712-nearly-300-people-dead-in-pakistan-floods</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>J&amp;K government must provide basic necessities, ex-gratia to all the flood victims, says SC</title>
			<link>http://www.newsx.com/national/nation/item/26711-jk-government-must-provide-basic-necessities-ex-gratia-to-all-the-flood-victims-says-sc</link>
			<description><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/400ca734b2b08335065d1ae9693c684d_Generic.jpg"><img align="right" border="0" src="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/400ca734b2b08335065d1ae9693c684d_S.jpg" alt="jk-government-must-provide-basic-necessities-ex-gratia-to-all-the-flood-victims-says-sc" /></a><font color="#ff3300"><b>Featured</b></font><p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">New Delhi: The Supreme Court has expressed concerns on the rescue and relief operations in the flood-hit Jammu and Kashmir. The court has said that the state government must provide basic necessities to flood victims.</span></p>

<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The state government must focus on providing food, water and medicines, the court said. "The focus should be on rehabilitation of flood victims," it added.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The court said that the state government must also give ex-gratia payments to every family.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The Centre, in its report on the Jammu and Kashmir floods, has said that it has done its best for the people of the flood-ravaged state.</span></p>]]></description>
			<dc:creator>Edited by Kirti Dwivedi | Updated: 3:45 IST</dc:creator>
			<pubDate>Mon, 15 Sep 2014 10:30:02 -0600</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.newsx.com/national/nation/item/26711-jk-government-must-provide-basic-necessities-ex-gratia-to-all-the-flood-victims-says-sc</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>I will sue the doctors for forcefully showing me porn, says god-man Nithyananda</title>
			<link>http://www.newsx.com/cities/item/26709-i-will-sue-the-doctors-for-forcefully-showing-me-porn-says-god-man-nithyananda</link>
			<description><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/9ebb41a89f65082d105695c086defddb_Generic.jpg"><img align="right" border="0" src="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/9ebb41a89f65082d105695c086defddb_S.jpg" alt="i-will-sue-the-doctors-for-forcefully-showing-me-porn-says-god-man-nithyananda" /></a><font color="#ff3300"><b>Featured</b></font><p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">BANGALORE: The self style god-men in India are increasingly getting indulged into rape scams. Another name in the league, rape-accused god-man Nithyananda has who recently underwent potency test in context to rape charges against him, has issued a legal notice to the doctors who allegedly showed him pornographic videos on Wednesday to test his potency.</span></p>

<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The notice issued by Nithya which has also been sent to the Central Investigation Department states that it is indefinite in the canons of medical and legal jurisprudence to let somebody see porn clips to test a person’s potency.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The god-man described the attempts of the doctors to make him watch sexually explicit clipping, with full knowledge that he was a ‘sanyasi’ as ‘crude and inhuman’. The notice also says that porn material is prohibited in India and its possession and exhibition is illegal.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">36-year-old Nithyananda expressed that he reserves the right to begin criminal action against the doctors and investigators, and file a suit against them for defamation and damages.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">According to the god-man’s allegations, he was continually abused in the presence of other doctors in foul language and as he claims, the doctors did not even bother about the lady doctors moving around.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">According to the notice, some doctors gate-crashed and united the team administering the test on him. As he suggests, on being quizzed regarding their identity, they said they were from the nephro-urology department. A couple of them claimed to be representatives of complainant Arati Rao and allegedly treated Nithyananda in a rough manner.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">As the allegations against the doctors surround, they are said to have advised the doctors conducting the test on him to inject a drug in to his private parts in order to get positive results.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Nithyananda further stated that he had also suffered a cardiac issue earlier at the time of the tests.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">On the other hand, the doctors from the Victoria Hospital who had conducted the potency test of Nithyananda have denied the allegations and have said that the report will be ready in coming few days.</span></p>]]></description>
			<dc:creator>Written by Charnamrit Sachdeva</dc:creator>
			<pubDate>Mon, 15 Sep 2014 10:01:35 -0600</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.newsx.com/cities/item/26709-i-will-sue-the-doctors-for-forcefully-showing-me-porn-says-god-man-nithyananda</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Govt should de-regulate diesel prices, Raghuram Rajan says</title>
			<link>http://www.newsx.com/national/business/item/26708-govt-should-de-regulate-diesel-prices-raghuram-rajan-says</link>
			<description><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/acaf83b6f74a3f0290880362c865c40f_Generic.jpg"><img align="right" border="0" src="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/acaf83b6f74a3f0290880362c865c40f_S.jpg" alt="govt-should-de-regulate-diesel-prices-raghuram-rajan-says" /></a><font color="#ff3300"><b>Featured</b></font><p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">New Delhi: RBI Governor Raghuram Rajan on Monday said that its time that the government should de-regulate the diesel prices in the wake of falling global crude oil prices.</span></p>

<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">He also said that the falling inflation is consistent with Reserve Bank of India forecast.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Rajan also said there was a need to change the management appointment process in public sector banks to make it more transparent.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The central bank is in talks with the government to improve governance in public sector banks, Rajan told a banking conference. He said problems that have emerged in recent bank scandals were due to outsourced project evaluation.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Rajan also said that India's macroeconomic indicators are improving and inflation has been coming down consistent with the central bank's forecast, but Indian economy needs investment growth to pick up.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Meanwhile, as the fall in international oil rates brings domestic diesel retail price at par with cost, the oil ministry has not yet moved Cabinet for deregulation of the nation's most consumed fuel.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The NDA government has continued with the previous UPA regime policy of raising diesel rates by up to 50 paise a litre every month to bridge the gap between cost and retail prices.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Under-recovery or the gap between retail selling price and the cost of imports, this month dipped to an all-time low of 8 paise a litre, helped by the monthly increases and softening in international oil rates.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The cut in diesel prices will not only help consumers with diesel-powered cars, but will also help bring down inflation in the economy.</span></p>]]></description>
			<dc:creator>Edited by Kirti Dwivedi | Updated: 3:25 IST</dc:creator>
			<pubDate>Mon, 15 Sep 2014 09:57:13 -0600</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.newsx.com/national/business/item/26708-govt-should-de-regulate-diesel-prices-raghuram-rajan-says</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title> 2G Scam: SC asks Prashant Bhushan to disclose identity who offered him information on the visitors list at the CBI Chief’s residence</title>
			<link>http://www.newsx.com/national/top-stories/item/26707-2g-scam-sc-asks-prashant-bhushan-to-disclose-identity-who-offered-him-information-on-the-visitors-list-at-the-cbi-chiefs-residence</link>
			<description><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/a7627ed6c009225d051076494554701a_Generic.jpg"><img align="right" border="0" src="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/a7627ed6c009225d051076494554701a_S.jpg" alt="2g-scam-sc-asks-prashant-bhushan-to-disclose-identity-who-offered-him-information-on-the-visitors-list-at-the-cbi-chiefs-residence" /></a><font color="#ff3300"><b>Featured</b></font><p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">NEW DELHI: Supreme Court on Monday asked advocate and Aam Aadmi Party (AAP) leader Prashant Bhushan to disclose the name of the whistleblower who had given the information regarding the ‘undesired visitors’ at the residence of CBI Director, Ranjit Sinha.</span></p>

<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The next hearing in the matter is scheduled for September 24.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">On the other hand, Ranjit Sinha has denied all charges of offenses on his front and has said that he already filed the file notings sealed cover as making them public shall only aid those accused in the 2G scam case.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">On September 12, the CBI head had filed an affidavit in the Supreme Court in acquiescence of the order of the apex court which on September 8 had directed him to act in response to the accusations made against him, believing that they were ‘serious’ in nature.</span></p>
<p><iframe src="//www.youtube.com/embed/dMctrOKajsg" frameborder="0" width="684" height="415" allowfullscreen="true" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"></iframe></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The court had asked the Chief to file the affidavit stating, “Whatever you want to tell us, tell us in black and white.”</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The bench in the last hearing had taken serious objection to the disinclination of Sinha to register an affidavit on merits of the allegations and had directed him to file his answer on an appeal for a direction to the Centre to take steps for his removal and for ordering an SIT investigation against him for allegedly abusing his authority.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The bench had taken on record an entry list or guest list register at the CBI Chief’s residence which was handed over by advocate Prashant Bhushan in a sealed envelope. Bhushan had put forwards names of some unknown people who had visited the residence of CBI Head.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Bhushan after submitting the documents appealed to the court to keep the documents in safe custody as they might be destroyed.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The bench had also taken on record a list of 23 ITBP officials and four CBI constables, who were manning the gate of the director's residence at 2, Janpath here.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">According to Prashant Bhushan, several accused and officials of accused companies in the 2G scam and other cases have been regular visitors to Sinha’s residence.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Bhushan further said that Sinha was initiating to protect some names accused in the scam and demanded his removal from the post.</span></p>]]></description>
			<dc:creator>Written by Charnamrit Sachdeva</dc:creator>
			<pubDate>Mon, 15 Sep 2014 08:28:16 -0600</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.newsx.com/national/top-stories/item/26707-2g-scam-sc-asks-prashant-bhushan-to-disclose-identity-who-offered-him-information-on-the-visitors-list-at-the-cbi-chiefs-residence</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>DMK, AIADMK pay tributes to Anna on 106th birth anniversary</title>
			<link>http://www.newsx.com/regional/tamil-nadu/item/26706-dmk-aiadmk-pay-tributes-to-anna-on-106th-birth-anniversary</link>
			<description><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/e674f2b1f9636710408cb711605a0f94_Generic.jpg"><img align="right" border="0" src="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/e674f2b1f9636710408cb711605a0f94_S.jpg" alt="dmk-aiadmk-pay-tributes-to-anna-on-106th-birth-anniversary" /></a><font color="#ff3300"><b>Featured</b></font><p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Chennai: Veteran Dravidian leader and former chief minister CN Annadurai was remembered in the state on the occasion of his 106th birth anniversary.</span></p>

<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">DMK president M Karunanidhi, accompanied by senior leaders including MK Stalin, paid floral tributes to the portrait of Annadurai, fondly addressed as Anna by his followers.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">AIADMK leaders also paid tributes to the leader under party's Presidium Chairman E Madhusudhanan.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">MDMK leader Vaiko and DMDK founder Vijayakanth also paid floral tributes to Annadurai. In Delhi, Principal Resident Commissioner of Tamil Nadu House, Jasbir Singh Bajaj, garlanded a statue of Anna.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Annadurai, founder of DMK, ushered in the first non-Congress government in Tamil Nadu. His party had unseated the Congress government in 1967 and he became the Chief Minister.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">A veteran Dravidian leader, he is respected across party lines.</span></p>]]></description>
			<dc:creator>Edited by Devendra Singh || Updated 13:46 IST</dc:creator>
			<pubDate>Mon, 15 Sep 2014 08:13:35 -0600</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.newsx.com/regional/tamil-nadu/item/26706-dmk-aiadmk-pay-tributes-to-anna-on-106th-birth-anniversary</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Chandrababu holds meeting of AP &quot;eCabinet&quot;</title>
			<link>http://www.newsx.com/regional/andhra-pradesh/item/26705-chandrababu-holds-meeting-of-ap-ecabinet</link>
			<description><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/3b5322d3a40ec3e07f7f0c763c756db0_Generic.jpg"><img align="right" border="0" src="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/3b5322d3a40ec3e07f7f0c763c756db0_S.jpg" alt="chandrababu-holds-meeting-of-ap-ecabinet" /></a><font color="#ff3300"><b>Featured</b></font><p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Hyderabad: Taking a step further in eGovernance, the Andhra Pradesh state Cabinet has now gone paperless.</span></p>

<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Wielding iPads in their hands, Chief Minister N Chandrababu Naidu and his Council of Ministers today conducted a meeting of what is being called "eCabinet", a first-of-its-kind initiative in the country.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">It was a regular meeting of the state Cabinet, but the uniqueness this time was that it is paperless, with the government switching over to the electronic format in conducting the proceedings.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The agenda and the minutes of the meeting were all electronically recorded while power-point presentation was made on important subjects for elaborate discussion, sources in the Chief Minister's Office said.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The Andhra Pradesh government, during Chandrababu's previous stint as Chief Minister between 1995 and 2004, had been a pioneer in launching various eGovernance initiatives.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Now, during his current tenure, the Chief Minister is making use of the advances in technology like Cloud to further eGovernance and the eCabinet is a "momentous" initiative, the CMO sources pointed out.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">For the eCabinet, a new file-sharing system has been put in place using the FileCloud tool for ministers and top bureaucrats.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">After a recent trial run, the new system has been used for the first time today and is expected to become a permanent feature of the Cabinet meetings from now on.</span></p>]]></description>
			<dc:creator>Edited by Devendra Singh || Updated 12:57 IST</dc:creator>
			<pubDate>Mon, 15 Sep 2014 07:18:01 -0600</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.newsx.com/regional/andhra-pradesh/item/26705-chandrababu-holds-meeting-of-ap-ecabinet</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>You must know the rules that keep your beloved wife happy!</title>
			<link>http://www.newsx.com/life-style/most-popular/item/26704-you-must-know-the-rules-that-keep-your-beloved-wife-happy</link>
			<description><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/ec6dadfa3d5d20a389394093b28384fd_Generic.jpg"><img align="right" border="0" src="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/ec6dadfa3d5d20a389394093b28384fd_S.jpg" alt="you-must-know-the-rules-that-keep-your-beloved-wife-happy" /></a><font color="#ff3300"><b>Featured</b></font><p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Have you ever thought what keeps your woman or beloved happy? If not, just think and understand what are the main things that keep your wife happy and you must do the same thing for the happiness of your beloved one.</span></p>

<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Everyone knows that a woman expects more love from her life partner. But they never think how it should be presented before a woman.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">You should always show love and respect for her without fail on a single day. Apart from this, you must make her realise that she is the one who you love or care a lot and this is the reason she is the special for you.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Know some important and valuable rules that you must not skip for the happiness of your loved one:</span></strong></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Listen to her:</span></strong></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Your partner must have life to live as she wants to do and you should not be there to stop her at every step. As seen in many relationships, the partners do not listen to each other and impose their own work upon the other. That is wrong! If you can’t give space to your partner, how you will get the same from your beloved. </span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">So, try to listen and know what she wants in her life and let her do whatever she wants. While doing this, the bonding of love, respect and trust will always be strong in your life.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong><span style="font-size: 10pt;" data-mce-mark="1">Forgiveness must be there in relationship:</span></strong></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Like you, she is also a human being, isn’t she? So, let it be, if she makes mistakes. Otherwise, it will come like a major problem in your life and ruin your lovely and beautiful relationship that should never happen in any relationship.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">When you are upset, rather than shouting on your partner, blame her or point fingers you must awake and heal yourself.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">After all, you are not a perfect one who can judge anyone at every point. So, you should never forget to forgive her at the same time while making mistakes.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Make weekend plan for your partner:</span></strong></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">You must make every weekend plan for your partner to make things happy like to watch movie, plan for dinner but you must take care of these things that let her choose the place first.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">These little things can make your beloved happy. As it is said that the more you give, the more you have that is the more you love, the more you get.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Make your partner’s dreams true:</span></strong></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">First you must know the dreams of your beloved wife that must be true. Many a times, we see that mostly women leave their dreams after marriage and they live in the four walls of the house.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">As for example: If your wife wants to do job even after marriage, you should encourage her and help her with full heart and mind so that she never feels alone.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The most important point is that you should know what your partner’s dreams are, and what they mean to her. For making these dreams true, you must take the dreams into consideration together with your lovely partner. Let her fly where she wants and stand with her at every step like a shadow.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Express your feelings before her:</span></strong></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Apart from all the things, you must express your feelings before your partner so that she could be able to know that what the feelings into you are.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">For the complete love, you should make yourself happy only then you can get the same from your so called beloved life partner.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">You should know how to deliver a romantic expression before her. For instance, you can express your feelings by verbal expressions or by non-verbal expressions.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">In verbal expression, you can say ‘I love you’, pay her the best and superb compliment and in non-verbal expression, you can write a love letter, make eye contact, show your feelings with some actions and most importantly and romantic is that you can also show your feelings with a physical touch.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Never forget to follow these rules as everyone wants his woman be happy forever.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">You must be thinking that all these things are easy to say but hard to do. But if you follow these points in your lovely relationship, you will find that your partner will be happier than before.</span></p>]]></description>
			<dc:creator> Written by Alka Sinha</dc:creator>
			<pubDate>Mon, 15 Sep 2014 06:49:51 -0600</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.newsx.com/life-style/most-popular/item/26704-you-must-know-the-rules-that-keep-your-beloved-wife-happy</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Worlds worst video game to be auctioned</title>
			<link>http://www.newsx.com/gadgets/gaming/item/26702-worlds-worst-video-game-to-be-auctioned</link>
			<description><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/23a13c681ee45d19acb9b179c1519acb_Generic.jpg"><img align="right" border="0" src="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/23a13c681ee45d19acb9b179c1519acb_S.jpg" alt="worlds-worst-video-game-to-be-auctioned" /></a><font color="#ff3300"><b>Featured</b></font><p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">WASHINGTON: Hundreds of copies of a video game described as the 'world's worst' are now being auctioned after they were unearthed from a landfill site in the US.</span></p>

<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The vintage video-game called 'ET the Extra-Terrestrial', based on a hit movie and released in 1982, was said to be so bad that Atari games buried a million unsold copies at a New Mexico rubbish dump.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">As many as 1,300 copies of the video game were uncovered in a major dig in April this year, proving that the story was true, and not just an urban myth, 'Sky News' reported.</span><br /><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Now more than half of the vintage video game haul is to be auctioned.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">According to the dig site supervisor, Joe Lewandowski, the excavation was like seeing a "phoenix rising from the desert".</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"It was like the beginning, end, and a new beginning for the video game industry when we found these games," he said.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The games are stored at the New Mexico Museum of Space History in Alamogordo, 321km southeast of Albuquerque. The city plans to keep some of the games as mementos, and the rest of the cartridges will be donated to museums around</span><br /><span style="font-size: 10pt;">the world.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The sale is due to begin in two weeks and will be complete by Christmas.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The video game flopped after being rushed out to coincide with the release of the Steven Spielberg movie, and contributed to collapse of the video game industry in its early years, the report said.</span></p>]]></description>
			<dc:creator>Edited by Devendra Singh || Updated 12:14 IST</dc:creator>
			<pubDate>Mon, 15 Sep 2014 06:40:03 -0600</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.newsx.com/gadgets/gaming/item/26702-worlds-worst-video-game-to-be-auctioned</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Exclusive interview with Congress leader Ghulam Nabi Azad </title>
			<link>http://www.newsx.com/interviews/item/26703-exclusive-interview-with-congress-leader-ghulam-nabi-azad</link>
			<description><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/2467961df49f33f49394f365e4b911c0_Generic.jpg"><img align="right" border="0" src="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/2467961df49f33f49394f365e4b911c0_S.jpg" alt="exclusive-interview-with-congress-leader-ghulam-nabi-azad" /></a><p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Congress leader Ghulam Nabi Azad has exclusively spoken to NewsX.&nbsp;</span></p>

<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Floods in Jammu and Kashmir complete rubbish the valley. Flood was so saviour at the state administrator collapsed completely in the first few hours on this issue we join by leader of opposition Ghulam Nabi Azad.</span>&nbsp;</p>
<p><iframe src="//www.youtube.com/embed/_f-rMYBUqcs" frameborder="0" width="684" height="415" allowfullscreen="true" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"></iframe></p>]]></description>
			<dc:creator>NewsX Bureau</dc:creator>
			<pubDate>Mon, 15 Sep 2014 06:32:39 -0600</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.newsx.com/interviews/item/26703-exclusive-interview-with-congress-leader-ghulam-nabi-azad</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Woman shot at in Muzaffarnagar</title>
			<link>http://www.newsx.com/regional/up/item/26701-woman-shot-at-in-muzaffarnagar</link>
			<description><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/6a55155d7ac18ec3a73e08739b8c72b6_Generic.jpg"><img align="right" border="0" src="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/6a55155d7ac18ec3a73e08739b8c72b6_S.jpg" alt="woman-shot-at-in-muzaffarnagar" /></a><font color="#ff3300"><b>Featured</b></font><p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">A married woman was allegedly shot at when she had gone to collect water from a public hand pump at Kaserwa Khurd village in Shamli district, police said today.</span></p>

<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The incident took place yesterday when Samina had gone to collect water along with one Hina following which a fight broke out over collection of water, they said.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">After a heated argument, Hina's brother Arif shot at Samina, police said.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The victim was seriously injured and shifted to a hospital, they said, adding that the accused is absconding.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">In another incident, a 55-year-old woman was allegedly attacked with sharp weapons by some unidentified persons in the district, police said.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The incident took place yesterday when Ishwari had gone to collect grass from the fields following which some people opposed and attacked her, they said.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Police has registered a case against two persons in this connection and the seriously injured woman has rushed been to a hospital.</span></p>]]></description>
			<dc:creator>Edited by Devendra Singh || Updated 11:45 IST</dc:creator>
			<pubDate>Mon, 15 Sep 2014 06:06:19 -0600</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.newsx.com/regional/up/item/26701-woman-shot-at-in-muzaffarnagar</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Modi to host dinner for Xi on Sabarmati riverfront</title>
			<link>http://www.newsx.com/national/nation/item/26700-modi-to-host-dinner-for-xi-on-sabarmati-riverfront</link>
			<description><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/1288d2ec8e7d8bc4374bc0b68d790914_Generic.jpg"><img align="right" border="0" src="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/1288d2ec8e7d8bc4374bc0b68d790914_S.jpg" alt="modi-to-host-dinner-for-xi-on-sabarmati-riverfront" /></a><font color="#ff3300"><b>Featured</b></font><p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">New Delhi: Prime Minister Narendra Modi will host a private dinner for Chinese President Xi Jinping on Sabarmati riverfront in Ahmedabad on September 17 when he begins his India visit.</span></p>

<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">According to official sources, the private dinner will be attended by limited number of guests from each side. There will be five persons from each side at the dinner which will not be very ostentatious, they said.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The Sabarmati riverfront was selected as a venue for the dinner as President Xi will be visiting Mahatma Gandhi's Sabarmati Ashram near it.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The sources said that Xi, who is scheduled to arrive on September 17 afternoon in Gujarat, will leave for New Delhi soon after the dinner.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">They said everything for Xi's visit was being done "as per the protocol", rejecting reports that there were elaborate arrangements for the dinner.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Modi on Sunday tweeted, "On 17th, President Xi Jinping will be in Gujarat. We look forward to extending a warm welcome to him but there will be no birthday celebrations".</span></p>]]></description>
			<dc:creator>Edited by Devendra Singh || Updated 11:34 IST</dc:creator>
			<pubDate>Mon, 15 Sep 2014 06:03:35 -0600</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.newsx.com/national/nation/item/26700-modi-to-host-dinner-for-xi-on-sabarmati-riverfront</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Deepika Padukone slams popular news portal for showcasing her cleavage</title>
			<link>http://www.newsx.com/showbiz/celebrities/item/26699-deepika-padukone-slams-popular-news-portal-for-showcasing-her-cleavage</link>
			<description><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/e8ae49b4eb1b61c6f3c1c50772971315_Generic.jpg"><img align="right" border="0" src="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/e8ae49b4eb1b61c6f3c1c50772971315_S.jpg" alt="deepika-padukone-slams-popular-news-portal-for-showcasing-her-cleavage" /></a><font color="#ff3300"><b>Featured</b></font><p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Beautiful and gorgeous Bollywood actress Deepika Padukone has slammed and criticized leading daily ‘news update’ for disrespecting her.</span></p>

<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">When the ‘Finding Fanny’ actress had gone through the news titled ‘OMG! Deepika Padukone’s cleavage show’ on twitter, she lost her calm and hit back strongly against the news portal.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">India’s popular news portal targeted the actress and uploaded the content along with a video highlighting Deepika’s cleavage revealing her dress.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">While the actress has showed a quite rigid attitude on such news, she has even bombarded with back-to-back tweets expressing her rage.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">In her first tweet, she seems to be exposing the news site with a picture of the news piece: Supposedly India's 'LEADING' newspaper and this is 'NEWS'!!??</span></p>
<p><img style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;" src="http://www.newsx.com/images/Auto/Lifestyle/deepika_11.png" alt="deepika 11" width="630" height="150" />&nbsp;</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Expressing her rage, she tweeted saying, “YES! I am a Woman.I have breasts AND a cleavage! You got a problem!!??”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 10pt;"><img style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;" src="http://www.newsx.com/images/Auto/Lifestyle/deepika_2.png" alt="deepika 2" width="630" height="352" /></span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;" data-mce-mark="1">In another tweet, she hit back while saying, “Don’t talk about Woman's Empowerment when YOU don't know how to RESPECT Women!”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 10pt;" data-mce-mark="1"><img style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;" src="http://www.newsx.com/images/Auto/Lifestyle/deepika_3.png" alt="deepika 3" width="630" height="352" /></span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The fans of the beautiful dimpled girl have also come out in her support. Almost all Bollywood stars also tweeted in the support of Deepika Padukone.</span></p>]]></description>
			<dc:creator>Written by Alka Sinha</dc:creator>
			<pubDate>Mon, 15 Sep 2014 05:41:45 -0600</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.newsx.com/showbiz/celebrities/item/26699-deepika-padukone-slams-popular-news-portal-for-showcasing-her-cleavage</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Prithviraj Chavan like a patient in ICU, says Shiv Sena</title>
			<link>http://www.newsx.com/regional/maharashtra/item/26698-prithviraj-chavan-like-a-patient-in-icu-says-shiv-sena</link>
			<description><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/d092cce8e5a2479375447cab14c7d489_Generic.jpg"><img align="right" border="0" src="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/d092cce8e5a2479375447cab14c7d489_S.jpg" alt="prithviraj-chavan-like-a-patient-in-icu-says-shiv-sena" /></a><font color="#ff3300"><b>Featured</b></font><p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Mumbai: Shiv Sena on Monday lashed out at Prithviraj Chavan, saying the Maharashtra CM is like a patient in intensive care unit (ICU).</span></p>

<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The party lambasted at the Maharashtra CM after Chavan criticised Shiv Sena president Uddhav Thackeray.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">After the two leaders participated in an event organised by a TV channel here on Saturday, Chavan had said that Uddhav lacked the experience to run government as he wasn't part of the Sena-BJP government which came to power in 1995.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"Chavan says Uddhav didn't have any experience. What experience did he have when he became chief minister ? Because he is finding it tough to get a safe constituency to contest the poll, his mental condition has become unstable like that of a patient in ICU," an editorial in Sena mouthpiece Saamana said here.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Also, did Chavan have the guts to ask a 'loser' like Rahul Gandhi what experience did he have to aspire for PM's post, the edit said.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">What experience certificate did Rajiv Gandhi have when he landed from the plane cockpit onto the prime ministerial chair, it said.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"Chavan warmed the chief ministerial chair and it did not benefit Maharashtra," it added.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The Assembly Elections are due to take place in Maharashtra on October 15.</span></p>]]></description>
			<dc:creator>Edited by Devendra Singh || Updated 11:07 IST</dc:creator>
			<pubDate>Mon, 15 Sep 2014 04:56:57 -0600</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.newsx.com/regional/maharashtra/item/26698-prithviraj-chavan-like-a-patient-in-icu-says-shiv-sena</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Shiv Sena blasts CM Chavan over anti-Uddhav remarks</title>
			<link>http://www.newsx.com/regional/maharashtra/item/26697-shiv-sena-blasts-cm-chavan-over-anti-uddhav-remarks</link>
			<description><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/bfba9567bdc5a8f5d8a5053e6b052203_Generic.jpg"><img align="right" border="0" src="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/bfba9567bdc5a8f5d8a5053e6b052203_S.jpg" alt="shiv-sena-blasts-cm-chavan-over-anti-uddhav-remarks" /></a><font color="#ff3300"><b>Featured</b></font><p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Maharashtra Chief minister Prithviraj Chavan's criticism of Shiv Sena president Uddhav Thackeray has not gone down well with the saffron party, which today blasted the Congress leader.</span></p>

<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">After the two leaders participated in an event organised by a TV channel here on Saturday, Chavan had said that Uddhav lacked the experience to run a government as he wasn't part of the Sena-BJP government which came to power in 1995.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"Chavan says Uddhav didn't have any experience. What experience did he have when he became chief minister ? Because he is finding it tough to get a safe constituency to contest the poll, his mental condition has become unstable like that of a patient in ICU," an editorial in Sena mouthpiece Saamana said here.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The editorial also questioned the experience of Congress leaders Rahul Gandhi and his father Rajiv Gandhi.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"Chavan warmed the chief ministerial chair and it did not benefit Maharashtra," it added.</span></p>]]></description>
			<dc:creator>Edited by Devendra Singh || Updated 10:19 IST</dc:creator>
			<pubDate>Mon, 15 Sep 2014 04:47:45 -0600</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.newsx.com/regional/maharashtra/item/26697-shiv-sena-blasts-cm-chavan-over-anti-uddhav-remarks</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Missing girl's body found in Chanakyapuri park</title>
			<link>http://www.newsx.com/cities/item/26696-missing-girls-body-found-in-chanakyapuri-park</link>
			<description><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/13920a4e565b4fbbd90ed78a1c190cf0_Generic.jpg"><img align="right" border="0" src="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/13920a4e565b4fbbd90ed78a1c190cf0_S.jpg" alt="missing-girls-body-found-in-chanakyapuri-park" /></a><font color="#ff3300"><b>Featured</b></font><p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">New Delhi: Decomposed body of a 22-year-old girl, who had been missing since September 10, was recovered from Buddha Jayanti Park here, police said on Sunday.</span></p>

<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Police said the autopsy report of the girl has revealed that she died due to stabbing.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"Rape has been ruled out in the case," they said.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The body, which was recovered yesterday, remained unidentified for hours. It was identified after the girl's parents were traced through the missing person report lodged by them about the girl.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"The girl's parents said she had left home for some work on Wednesday (September 10) and did not return after that. They had searched for her before filing the missing report with police," Additional Commissioner of Police (New Delhi district) SBS Tyagi said.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The forest area in Buddha Jayanti Park, from where the body was discovered, is close to slums.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The park is located in the backyard of the Presidential Palace.</span></p>]]></description>
			<dc:creator>Edited by Devendra Singh || Updated 09:56 IST</dc:creator>
			<pubDate>Mon, 15 Sep 2014 04:23:29 -0600</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.newsx.com/cities/item/26696-missing-girls-body-found-in-chanakyapuri-park</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>MNS averse to alliance, to contest Assembly elections solo</title>
			<link>http://www.newsx.com/regional/maharashtra/item/26695-mns-averse-to-alliance-to-contest-assembly-elections-solo</link>
			<description><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/1bad7c3b238abbd0322184eaea65b24f_Generic.jpg"><img align="right" border="0" src="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/1bad7c3b238abbd0322184eaea65b24f_S.jpg" alt="mns-averse-to-alliance-to-contest-assembly-elections-solo" /></a><font color="#ff3300"><b>Featured</b></font><p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Mumbai: Raj Thackeray-led Maharashtra Navnirman Sena will contest forthcoming elections on its own without forging any alliance, a senior party leader said today.</span></p>

<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"If political parties truly want to develop Maharashtra, they should contest elections independently and not go in for any kind of alliance. But do these parties have the courage to face the truth and go in without an alliance?.. MNS will contest the elections independently," said senior party leader Bala Nandgaonkar.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Nandgaonkar's statement assumes significance given the political scenario in the state in run-up to elections. MNS recently took help of Congress and NCP to win Mayoral elections in Nashik, after its ally in the Nashik Municipal Corporation, the BJP snapped ties.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">He said that MNS will start interviewing aspiring candidates from Marathwada region for the October 15 polls from tomorrow.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Meanwhile, Raj, who is on a two-day visit to Aurangabad, today interacted with his party workers and will be interviewing aspiring candidates of 46 constituencies in the Marathwada region on Monday.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"We will be interviewing aspiring candidates from 46 constituencies in Marathwada region. We will also be calling candidates from Dhule, Jalgaon and Nandurbar region for interviewing them," Nandgaonkar said.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">He added that "true development" of Maharashtra can happen only when all the parties fight elections on their own, rather than forming an alliance.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Referring to internal fighting between alliance partners like Sena-BJP and Congress-NCP ahead of polls, Nandgaonkar said that such feuds will dent the image of political parties in the minds of voters.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"If Sena is fighting with BJP and Congress with NCP before polls, it will dent their image in the mind of people. People will wonder what kind of development such alliances can give Maharashtra," he said.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">MNS fared poorly in Lok Sabha elections with all its candidates from ten seats losing their deposit. The party polled mere 0.13 per cent votes.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">In 2009 Assembly elections, MNS had contested 143 seats and won 13.</span></p>]]></description>
			<dc:creator>Edited by Devendra Singh || Updated 09:50 IST</dc:creator>
			<pubDate>Mon, 15 Sep 2014 04:19:09 -0600</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.newsx.com/regional/maharashtra/item/26695-mns-averse-to-alliance-to-contest-assembly-elections-solo</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>BJP will form Delhi govt in 'fully democratic way', says Ram Madhav</title>
			<link>http://www.newsx.com/regional/delhi/item/26694-bjp-will-form-delhi-govt-in-fully-democratic-way-says-ram-madhav</link>
			<description><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/9838b943928ae993c2ddf03d29776adf_Generic.jpg"><img align="right" border="0" src="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/9838b943928ae993c2ddf03d29776adf_S.jpg" alt="bjp-will-form-delhi-govt-in-fully-democratic-way-says-ram-madhav" /></a><font color="#ff3300"><b>Featured</b></font><p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Varanasi: Brushing aside AAP's allegations of horse-trading, BJP general secretary Ram Madhav on Sunday said his party would form the government in Delhi in "fully democratic way".</span></p>

<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Asserting that his party was not in favour of forming the government through undemocratic means, Madhav said "had there been such things (horse-trading) then BJP might have formed the government six months ago".</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Slamming the Arvind Kejriwal-led party for levelling "baseless allegations" against BJP, Madhav said, "AAP doesn't have anything else to do other than creating controversies and making such baseless allegations... They ran away from running the government and now they are demanding re-elections."</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Asked about the Delhi Lieutenant Governor's move to invite BJP to form the government, he said "whatever the democratic methods are will be followed and a suitable decision will be taken by LG on this issue".</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"Whosoever forms the government it will be formed in fully democratic way," he added.</span></p>]]></description>
			<dc:creator>Edited by Devendra Singh || Updated 09:34 IST</dc:creator>
			<pubDate>Mon, 15 Sep 2014 03:54:43 -0600</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.newsx.com/regional/delhi/item/26694-bjp-will-form-delhi-govt-in-fully-democratic-way-says-ram-madhav</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Don't celebrate my birthday, help in J&amp;K relief work instead: PM Modi</title>
			<link>http://www.newsx.com/national/nation/item/26693-dont-celebrate-my-birthday-help-in-jkk-relief-work-instead-pm-modi</link>
			<description><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/ea827e7172d4e2e600827f5988caf23b_Generic.jpg"><img align="right" border="0" src="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/ea827e7172d4e2e600827f5988caf23b_S.jpg" alt="dont-celebrate-my-birthday-help-in-jkk-relief-work-instead-pm-modi" /></a><font color="#ff3300"><b>Featured</b></font><p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">New Delhi: As the rescuers battles to save thousands of people in the flood-ravaged Jammu and Kashmir, Prime Minister Narendra Modi on Sunday made a humble request to the people to not celebrate his birthday which is due on September 17.</span></p>

<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Modi in one of his tweet on the micro-blogging website wrote that he's hearing about various programmes and event that are being planned by his friends and well-wishers and said “do not celebrate my birthday”.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">He instead appealed to the people to dedication themselves towards the relief and rescue work in Jammu and Kashmir through their time and resources.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">“The need of the hour is to stand shoulder to shoulder with our sisters and brothers of Jammu and Kashmir(sic),” read his another tweet.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">PM Modi had earlier this week appealed to all Indians to come forward and donate generously to the PM's National Relief Fund for the flood-affected people in Jammu and Kashmir.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">In his appeal, Modi said, "My fellow citizens, you are all aware that unprecedented floods have caused havoc in the state of Jammu and Kashmir. A large number of persons have died or have been temporarily displaced.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">As per the official figures, over two lakh trapped people have been rescue by the Armed forces and National Disaster Relief Force as the operations entered the 13th day today.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Meanwhile, reportedly over one lakh people are still marooned after the worst floods in the state in a century unleashed a trail of death and destruction, claiming at least 250 lives.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Union Health Minister Harsh Vardhan took a detailed review of the health-related relief measures at a meeting with Chief Minister Omar Abdullah here and senior officials and said all assistance will be provided to the state authorities to tackle any possible epidemic.</span></p>]]></description>
			<dc:creator>Edited by Devendra Singh || Updated 09:23 IST</dc:creator>
			<pubDate>Mon, 15 Sep 2014 03:52:00 -0600</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.newsx.com/national/nation/item/26693-dont-celebrate-my-birthday-help-in-jkk-relief-work-instead-pm-modi</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title> #RightToHide: CIC puts 6 political parties on notice</title>
			<link>http://www.newsx.com/national/top-stories/item/26692-righttohide-cic-puts-6-political-parties-on-notice</link>
			<description><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/51145c98a24378770d6f698e423835c8_Generic.jpg"><img align="right" border="0" src="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/51145c98a24378770d6f698e423835c8_S.jpg" alt="righttohide-cic-puts-6-political-parties-on-notice" /></a><font color="#ff3300"><b>Featured</b></font><p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">New Delhi: The Central Information Commission (CIC) has issued notices to six political parties for failing to comply with its order which brought them under the ambit of the Right to Information (RTI) law.</span></p>

<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The CIC issued notices to the Bharatiya Janata Party (BJP), Congress party, Nationalist Congress Party, Communist Party of India (Marxist), Communist Party of India and the Bahujan Samaj Party. The CIC has also issued showcause notices to BJP president Amit Shah and Congress chief Sonia Gandhi on the issue. “…a notice is issued to show cause within four weeks as to why an inquiry should not be initiated in the matter of non-compliance of the Commission’s order dated June 3, 2013, under Section 18 of the RTI Act, 2005,” the order dated 10 September, said.</span></p>
<p><iframe src="//www.youtube.com/embed/iv5dYvp44nw?list=UUytSP0M0Jdnw6qIy3Y-nTig" frameborder="0" width="684" height="415" allowfullscreen="true" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"></iframe></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">“Take further notice that if you fail to respond within prescribed time, the matter will be processed on the strength of material on record, in accordance with law,” the notice added. The notice was made public by Subhash Chandra Agrawal, Right to Information (RTI) activist and applicant in the case on Sunday. In June 2013, the transparency watchdog had declared the political parties as public authorities and brought them under the RTI Act.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">It also asked them to appoint appellate bodies to answer RTI queries. In February, the CIC followed up the matter with the parties. CIC is a quasi-judicial body with the powers of a civil court. It can impose penalties on defaulting bodies under the RTI Act.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">“We make all our submissions of our finances to the Income Tax department and the Election Commission (EC) and all the norms of the EC are being complied with. As a political party, we are accountable to the people of India and we feel that a bringing it under RTI would be restrictive,” Sanjay Jha, a spokesperson of the Congress, said. He, however, added that he was not aware if the notice was received by the party or not.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">A senior BJP leader said the party would respond only after studying the order. The CIC had said that parties receive financial aid from the government including land.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The development office of the ministry of urban development had “alloted large tracts of land” either free or at concessional rates to them. The commission also said that they get total exemption under Section 13A of the Income-Tax Act for all their income and get free air time on All India Radio and Doordarshan during elections. All these aspects, the commission concluded, made them public authorities, bringing them under the purview of RTI law.</span></p>]]></description>
			<dc:creator>Edited by Devendra Singh || Updated 09:16 IST</dc:creator>
			<pubDate>Mon, 15 Sep 2014 03:41:37 -0600</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.newsx.com/national/top-stories/item/26692-righttohide-cic-puts-6-political-parties-on-notice</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Aamir Khan would consider Rajya Sabha nomination</title>
			<link>http://www.newsx.com/showbiz/celebrities/item/26691-aamir-khan-would-consider-rajya-sabha-nomination</link>
			<description><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/25ee95956d7cc9ab7d3f3635027ba990_Generic.jpg"><img align="right" border="0" src="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/25ee95956d7cc9ab7d3f3635027ba990_S.jpg" alt="aamir-khan-would-consider-rajya-sabha-nomination" /></a><font color="#ff3300"><b>Featured</b></font><p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Actor Aamir Khan said that if he is offered a nomination to the Rajya Sabha, he will “think” about it.</span></p>

<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Asked whether he would like to be nominated to the Rajya Sabha like cricketer Sachin Tendulkar and actress Rekha, Aamir said, “I won’t comment on what they are doing. They are my friends. But if such opportunity arises, I will think whether I can contribute to society at that point of time in a better way or not. If that happens, I will be there everyday.”</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The 49-year-old ‘Dhoom 3’ star was speaking at the Panchayat AajTak programme organised by the India Today Group here.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Asked what he thought about Prime Minister Narendra Modi’s attempts to centralise power, Aamir said, “I don’t know whether he is doing the right thing. You know better.”</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Answering a question about the portrayal of women in Hindi films, Aamir said, “I admit that Hindi films have been irresponsible in terms of portrayal of women.”</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">“It sends out a very wrong message. Songs like ‘Tu Cheez Badi Hai Mast Mast’ (from Mohra) and ‘Khambe Jaisi Khadi Hai’ (from Dil which featured Aamir) are not good. We should respect sentiments of women. I accept my own hand in it, but I will try not to do this now. I will take this up with my friends and be sensitive henceforth,” Aamir said.</span></p>]]></description>
			<dc:creator>Edited by Devendra Singh || Updated 08:58 IST</dc:creator>
			<pubDate>Mon, 15 Sep 2014 03:25:04 -0600</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.newsx.com/showbiz/celebrities/item/26691-aamir-khan-would-consider-rajya-sabha-nomination</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Secret to long life may lie in your waist!</title>
			<link>http://www.newsx.com/life-style/health/item/26690-secret-to-long-life-may-lie-in-your-waist</link>
			<description><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/2bbf65607d5324668180dfab8742592e_Generic.jpg"><img align="right" border="0" src="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/2bbf65607d5324668180dfab8742592e_S.jpg" alt="secret-to-long-life-may-lie-in-your-waist" /></a><font color="#ff3300"><b>Featured</b></font><p><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The key to a long life is having a waist no bigger than half your height, a new study has claimed.</span></p>

<p><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Researchers said the rule applied regardless of a person's age, ethnicity or gender.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Dr Margaret Ashwell, co-author of the study, said that the evidence was so strong that it should provide the basis for a simple global health check, which anybody could perform with a piece of string if they did not have a tape measure: "Keep your waist circumference to less than half your height."</span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The study by Ashwell and researchers from City University London's Cass Business School analysed 20 years of British medical records and measured the impact on life expectancy of obesity, as measured by the ratio between your waist and height, 'The Sunday Times' reported.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Researchers found that a 30-year-old man who is 5ft 10in tall, should have a waist of no more than 35in - but if that expands to 42in, or 60 per cent of his height, he will lose 1.7 years.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 10pt;">His female counterpart, who is 5ft 4in tall, will die 1.4 years prematurely if she lets her waist expand from half her height, 32in, to 60 per cent of her height, 38.4in.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 10pt;">A man aged 30, of average height and a 56in waist, can expect to lose 20.2 years, while an obese woman of 30 with a waist of 51in will die 10.6 years early.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 10pt;">However, only 0.2 per cent to 0.3 per cent of that age group are so excessively overweight, researchers said.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The study demonstrated that Body mass index (BMI) is particularly poor at predicting early death from obesity for women, while waist to height provides accurate estimates for both sexes.</span></p>]]></description>
			<dc:creator>Edited by Devendra Singh || Updated 08:52 IST</dc:creator>
			<pubDate>Mon, 15 Sep 2014 03:22:09 -0600</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.newsx.com/life-style/health/item/26690-secret-to-long-life-may-lie-in-your-waist</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Mamata Banerjee benefited the most from Saradha scam, says BJP MP</title>
			<link>http://www.newsx.com/regional/west-bengal/item/26689-mamata-banerjee-benefited-the-most-from-saradha-scam-says-bjp-mp</link>
			<description><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/2427b0deb69391b3775f8eed67d1f427_Generic.jpg"><img align="right" border="0" src="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/2427b0deb69391b3775f8eed67d1f427_S.jpg" alt="mamata-banerjee-benefited-the-most-from-saradha-scam-says-bjp-mp" /></a><font color="#ff3300"><b>Featured</b></font><p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Mumbai: Targetting West Bengal Chief Minister Mamata Banerjee, BJP today alleged that she has benefited the most from the multi-crore Saradha Chit Fund scam, in which thousands of investors were allegedly duped.</span></p>

<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"People, who have been arrested (in Saradha chit fund case) are saying that West Bengal Chief Minister benefited the most from the scam," BJP MP from Asansol (West Bengal) Babul Supriyo told reporters here.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"Those arrested are even divulging the amount of money that Mamataji and (TMC general secretary) Mukul Roy received in this scam."</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The Saradha scam had come to light in April 2013 after the group downed shutters without repaying lakhs of investors, who had parked their hard-earned money in the group's companies, lured by the promise of astronomically-high returns. The Supreme Court had later directed the CBI to probe the Saradha scam.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Supriyo added that the charges against Rajya Sabha member Ahmed Hassan Imran allegedly playing a key role in getting huge funds from Bangladesh-based terror outfit Jamaat-e-Islami secretly transferred across the border to help TMC win the 2011 Assembly polls, were "not merely allegations, but are facts".</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"These facts were brought out in the public domain by the media," the singer-turned-MP said.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"Mamata didi nominated Imran for the post of Rajya Sabha member. Was she not aware of his background? (Home Minister) Rajnath Singh has rightly said that his role is being probed very seriously, and the truth will be out very soon. But Imran has no right to be a Rajya Sabha member now," he said.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">When asked about Rahul Gandhi's role in the October 15 Maharashtra Assembly elections, Supriyo said the Congress Vice President should take a break from politics.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"One who is an original star can be a star campaigner. Rahul Gandhi has got the stardom from his family. Looking at him it seems that he is not interested in politics. So he should quit politics for a few years and divert his attention elsewhere," he said.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">According to Supriyo, the BJP is working towards uniting all the Bengalis in Maharashtra and explain to them that voting for a BJP is important "for a better future."</span></p>]]></description>
			<dc:creator>Edited by Devendra Singh || Updated 08:15 IST</dc:creator>
			<pubDate>Mon, 15 Sep 2014 02:42:50 -0600</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.newsx.com/regional/west-bengal/item/26689-mamata-banerjee-benefited-the-most-from-saradha-scam-says-bjp-mp</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Australia contributing planes for anti-IS campaign</title>
			<link>http://www.newsx.com/world/others/item/26688-australia-contributing-planes-for-anti-is-campaign</link>
			<description><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/94a29aff3a5e4ccce152254c9c78abe3_Generic.jpg"><img align="right" border="0" src="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/94a29aff3a5e4ccce152254c9c78abe3_S.jpg" alt="australia-contributing-planes-for-anti-is-campaign" /></a><font color="#ff3300"><b>Featured</b></font><p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Canberra: Terrorists will use Australia's deployment of troops and war planes to the Middle East as an excuse to target Australians, Prime Minister Tony Abbott warned today.</span></p>

<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Australia is preparing to contribute 600 troops and up to 10 military aircraft to the increasingly aggressive campaign against the Islamic State extremists in Syria and Iraq, the government announced yesterday.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">While Abbott expected extremists to react to Australia's military deployment to the United Arab Emirates, he noted that 88 Australians were among 202 people killed by bombers on the Indonesian island of Bali in 2002 before Australia went to war in Iraq.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"There is no doubt that those who wish us harm will cite things like this as an excuse, but it's not the reason," Abbott told Australian Broadcasting Corp television.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"The reason why we are targeted is not because of anything that we've done, but because of who we are and how we live," he said.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"This death cult targets everyone and anyone who does not conform to its particular ideology," he added, referring to the Islamic State movement.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Taufik Andrie, a terrorism researcher at Jakarta's Institute for International Peace Building, told ABC that Indonesian extremists were again talking about targeting Westerners in response to recent US air strikes in Iraq. There have been no major attacks on Westerns in Indonesia since July 17, 2009, when the JW Marriot and Ritz-Carlton hotels were bombed, killing eight and injuring 53.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Australia's military deployment is in response to a formal request from the United States for specific contributions to the international coalition.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">President Barack Obama announced the more aggressive military campaign last week. Scores of US airstrikes have been launched at select targets in Iraq, and US planes and drones will be gathering intelligence on targets before launching airstrikes in Syria.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Abbott drew a distinction between the current Iraq campaign and 2003 when Australia sent 2,000 troops to back the US and British forces in the Iraq invasion.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"It's not President George W Bush, it is President Obama, a very different president ... Who is rightly and properly slow to reach for the gun and he has put together an extensive coalition including about 10 Middle Eastern countries," Abbott told Nine Network television.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Australia will prepare up to eight F/A18 combat aircraft, an E-7A Wedgetail Early Warning and Control aircraft and a KC-30A Tanker and Transport aircraft to be deployed to the United Arab Emirates.</span></p>]]></description>
			<dc:creator>Edited by Devendra Singh || Updated 08:09 IST</dc:creator>
			<pubDate>Mon, 15 Sep 2014 02:35:14 -0600</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.newsx.com/world/others/item/26688-australia-contributing-planes-for-anti-is-campaign</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>No comment, Says Manmohan Singh on former CAG Vinod Rai's criticism</title>
			<link>http://www.newsx.com/national/nation/item/26687-no-comment-says-manmohan-singh-on-former-cag-vinod-rais-criticism</link>
			<description><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/7b4ee79a4e6ad8f1cc928b23733b79cf_Generic.jpg"><img align="right" border="0" src="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/7b4ee79a4e6ad8f1cc928b23733b79cf_S.jpg" alt="no-comment-says-manmohan-singh-on-former-cag-vinod-rais-criticism" /></a><font color="#ff3300"><b>Featured</b></font><p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Former prime minister Manmohan Singh, who is under fire from the former CAG Vinod Rai over the 2G spectrum scam and Coalgate, on Sunday said he has done his "duty" and refused to respond to charges levelled against him.</span></p>

<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"I, indeed, did my duty. Well, I do not want to comment on other people what they have written," Singh told reporters on the sidelines of an event in New Delhi to celebrate the publication of a book titled 'Strictly Personal: Manmohan and Gursharan', authored by his daughter Daman Singh.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Singh was asked about the scathing criticism by Rai who held the former PM responsible for the controversial decisions to allocate 2G spectrum on first-cum-first serve basis and coal blocks without auction.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Interestingly, Daman skirted questions about the ex-CAG's comments.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"Actually, I do not know anything about that. So I cannot comment. I have no idea about that. I have not heard what they have said. I cannot say anything. I really do not know and I have not heard what they have said. So, there is no point in saying anything," she said.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Daman charts the journey of her parents in her book providing new insights into the couple but keeps away from the last 10 years when Singh was heading the UPA government.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The function was attended among others by former Deputy Planning Commission chairman Montek Singh Ahluwalia and ex-minister Shashi Tharoor.</span></p>]]></description>
			<dc:creator>Edited by Devendra Singh || Updated 08:00 IST</dc:creator>
			<pubDate>Mon, 15 Sep 2014 02:27:51 -0600</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.newsx.com/national/nation/item/26687-no-comment-says-manmohan-singh-on-former-cag-vinod-rais-criticism</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>#FloodPolitics: Subramanian Swamy suggests president rule for J&amp;K, Opposition slams</title>
			<link>http://www.newsx.com/national/top-stories/item/26686-floodpolitics-subramanian-swamy-suggests-president-rule-for-jk-opposition-slams</link>
			<description><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/7652b4aa659e6079a448accdb10f8529_Generic.jpg"><img align="right" border="0" src="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/7652b4aa659e6079a448accdb10f8529_S.jpg" alt="floodpolitics-subramanian-swamy-suggests-president-rule-for-jk-opposition-slams" /></a><font color="#ff3300"><b>Featured</b></font><p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">New Delhi: Making a point about holding Assembly elections in Jammu and Kashmir amid flooding and ongoing rescue operations, the BJP's senior leader Subramanian Swamy on Sunday suggested that President's rule should be imposed in the state for a year.</span></p>

<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Swamy, who is known for speaking his mind, said that for one year J&amp;K should be under President's rule and the elections should be held later.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Panthers Party chief Bhim Singh on Sunday said the motive behind Bharatiya Janata Party (BJP) leader Subramanian Swamy's suggestion that President's rule should be imposed in Jammu and Kashmir is to support Prime Minister Narendra Modi's 'mission-44 plan' to win majority in the state and form government there.</span></p>
<p><iframe src="//www.youtube.com/embed/IfbBjca1juU" frameborder="0" width="684" height="415" allowfullscreen="true" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"></iframe></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Singh, however, added that it is a distant dream of the BJP.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"I think that Subramanian Swamy's slogan is to support Prime Minister Modi's 'formula 44' which is a distant dream at least in 21st century. Unfortunately, Subramanian Swamy does a U turn every time. This time he should have understood that there is no provision of the President rule in Jammu and Kashmir because of Article 370," Singh told ANI here.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"We in Jammu and Kashmir have a separate Constitution, the Governor of Jammu and Kashmir cannot impose Governor's rule beyond six months. There is a provision in the Section 92 of J and K Constitution, the Governor of Jammu and Kashmir has a power to take over the administration of the state but that cannot go beyond six months. It needs ratification from the state assembly," he added</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Swamy earlier in the day said President's rule should be imposed in flood-hit Jammu and Kashmir for a year and the elections should be held later.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Over 1,42,000 people have been rescued so far from the flood-ravaged parts of Jammu and Kashmir.</span></p>]]></description>
			<dc:creator>Edited by Devendra Singh || Updated 07:50 IST</dc:creator>
			<pubDate>Mon, 15 Sep 2014 02:19:36 -0600</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.newsx.com/national/top-stories/item/26686-floodpolitics-subramanian-swamy-suggests-president-rule-for-jk-opposition-slams</guid>
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
