<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet href="http://www.newsx.com/components/com_obrss/assets/xsl/atom-to-html.xsl" type="text/xsl"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
	<channel>
		<title>rss</title>
		<description><![CDATA[RSS Feed]]></description>
		<link>http://www.newsx.com/</link>
		<lastBuildDate>Sat, 13 Sep 2014 16:05:54 -0600</lastBuildDate>
		<generator>FeedCreator 1.8.3 (obRSS 1.9)</generator>
		<atom:link href="http://www.newsx.com/index.php?option=com_obrss&amp;task=feed&amp;id=2:rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
		<image>
			<url>http://www.newsx.com/images/</url>
			<title>rss</title>
			<link>http://www.newsx.com/</link>
			<description>RSS Feed</description>
		</image>
		<item>
			<title>J&amp;K floods: Mobile services partially restored, Centre allows free talk time on BSNL</title>
			<link>http://www.newsx.com/national/top-stories/item/26641-jk-floods-mobile-services-partially-restored-centre-allows-free-talk-time-on-bsnl</link>
			<description><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/884dbdc6b3321cdfbbf6c7781013205a_Generic.jpg"><img align="right" border="0" src="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/884dbdc6b3321cdfbbf6c7781013205a_S.jpg" alt="jk-floods-mobile-services-partially-restored-centre-allows-free-talk-time-on-bsnl" /></a><font color="#ff3300"><b>Featured</b></font><p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">New Delhi: Mobile services have been "somewhat" restored in flood-hit Jammu and Kashmir, except in Poonch, Union Telecom Minister Ravi Shankar Prasad said here Saturday.</span></p>

<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"The central government has worked a lot to restore communication in the valley. There are 12,306 base transceiver stations (BTS) in the region, out of which 6,811 got submerged under the flood water," Prasad told reporters here.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"I am happy to say 1,208 BTS are restored," the minister said.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">He said state-run Bharat Sanchar Nigam Limited (BSNL) was allowing free calls for one week and private telecom players were allowing 60 minutes free talk time every day.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Inter-circle roaming has been permitted for 15 days. "Any operator can use the tower of another operator to help the flood victims," the minister said.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"Apart from this in Srinagar airport we have constructed five PCOs, which can be accessed free," he added.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Around 8,000 landlines have started working in the Kashmir Valley.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"Except Poonch, mobile services are somewhat available everywhere," he said.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Over 200 people have died and nearly 1,30,000 people have been rescued in the flood-ravaged state so far.</span></p>]]></description>
			<dc:creator>Edited by Kirti Dwivedi | Updated: 8:35 IST</dc:creator>
			<pubDate>Sat, 13 Sep 2014 16:01:21 -0600</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.newsx.com/national/top-stories/item/26641-jk-floods-mobile-services-partially-restored-centre-allows-free-talk-time-on-bsnl</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title> Story Unfolds: J&amp;K tragedy unfolds</title>
			<link>http://www.newsx.com/component/k2/item/26640-story-unfolds-jk-tragedy-unfolds</link>
			<description><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/d7143c6ca3eba5c94e67a49b23952483_Generic.jpg"><img align="right" border="0" src="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/d7143c6ca3eba5c94e67a49b23952483_S.jpg" alt="story-unfolds-jk-tragedy-unfolds" /></a><font color="#ff3300"><b>Featured</b></font><p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Jammu and Kashmir is battling one of the worst floods in decades with rivers in the region in spate due to days of incessant rain.</span></p>

<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Over 200 people have died and thousands are stranded across the state, including Srinagar.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The Army, IAF and NDRF are doing a massive round-the-clock rescue and relief operation, with 86 aircrafts and 30,000 troops.</span></p>
<p><iframe src="//www.youtube.com/embed/Z8FI5kBbT0I" frameborder="0" width="684" height="415" allowfullscreen="true" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"></iframe></p>]]></description>
			<dc:creator>NewsX Bureau</dc:creator>
			<pubDate>Sat, 13 Sep 2014 15:47:52 -0600</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.newsx.com/component/k2/item/26640-story-unfolds-jk-tragedy-unfolds</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Ferro Chrome plant of Tata Steel in Odisha to start by March 2015</title>
			<link>http://www.newsx.com/national/business/item/26639-ferro-chrome-plant-of-tata-steel-in-odisha-to-start-by-march-2015</link>
			<description><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/c22135fe088ee78c5db56284015d23b2_Generic.jpg"><img align="right" border="0" src="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/c22135fe088ee78c5db56284015d23b2_S.jpg" alt="ferro-chrome-plant-of-tata-steel-in-odisha-to-start-by-march-2015" /></a><font color="#ff3300"><b>Featured</b></font><p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Mumbai: Tata Steel is setting up a 55,000 tonne per annum (TPA) ferro chrome plant at Gopalpur in Ganjam district of Odisha and its first unit is expected to start operations by March 2015.</span></p>

<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"With Gopalpur project being a top priority for the company, we are currently setting up a 55,000 TPA Ferro Chrome plant. We have recently filed documents seeking environment clearance for another ferro chrome plant at the site," Tata Steel Gopalpur Project Vice President Arun Misra said.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Anchor investments of Rs 800 crore proposed to be made by Tata Steel at the Gopalpur Industrial Park include the ferro chrome plant, which is under construction after all the statutory clearances.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The plant is expected to be commissioned by March 2015 with an employment opportunity for about 400 persons, both directly and indirectly, a company statement said. The steel major has already got in-principle approvals from the designated authorities to set up an industrial park at the same location.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Spanning over 2,970 acres of land, the industrial park includes a multi-product SEZ over 2,570 acres and an anchor project by Tata Steel over 400 acres. Tata Steel group is among the leading steel manufacturers in the world with an annual crude steel capacity of over 26.5 million tonnes per annum (mtpa).</span></p>]]></description>
			<dc:creator>Edited by Kirti Dwivedi | Updated: 8:15 IST</dc:creator>
			<pubDate>Sat, 13 Sep 2014 15:35:30 -0600</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.newsx.com/national/business/item/26639-ferro-chrome-plant-of-tata-steel-in-odisha-to-start-by-march-2015</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Left Front massive rally on Sep 22 against Saradha scam</title>
			<link>http://www.newsx.com/regional/west-bengal/item/26638-left-front-massive-rally-on-sep-22-against-saradha-scam</link>
			<description><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/eb0f8bdfd0b5da07f03f7c8c66c1a785_Generic.jpg"><img align="right" border="0" src="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/eb0f8bdfd0b5da07f03f7c8c66c1a785_S.jpg" alt="left-front-massive-rally-on-sep-22-against-saradha-scam" /></a><font color="#ff3300"><b>Featured</b></font><p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Kolkata: Left Front will take out a 'massive' rally in the city on September 22 to protest against the multi crore Sardha ponzi scheme scam in West Bengal.</span></p>

<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"We have decided that Left Front will organize a massive rally on Sep 22 agaisnt the chit fund scam, which has duped lakhs of people in the state. The people of Bengal want an answer, they want justice, they want their money back," Left Front Chairman Biman Bose said today.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"If the real culprits are not arrested soon, we will organise massive movements in the state... There are reports that money from Saradha ponzi scheme has been siphoned off to Bangladesh to fund terror."</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Claiming that democracy is being throttled in the state by the ruling Trinamool Congress regime, he said, "Democracy has been replaced by autocracy and goondaism."</span></p>]]></description>
			<dc:creator>Edited by Kirti Dwivedi | Updated: 7:45 IST</dc:creator>
			<pubDate>Sat, 13 Sep 2014 15:29:42 -0600</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.newsx.com/regional/west-bengal/item/26638-left-front-massive-rally-on-sep-22-against-saradha-scam</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Govt run special buses for school students poorly maintained, DMK says</title>
			<link>http://www.newsx.com/regional/tamil-nadu/item/26637-govt-run-special-buses-for-school-students-poorly-maintained-dmk-says</link>
			<description><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/d8b411670b3054c59639e4a3f2b978ef_Generic.jpg"><img align="right" border="0" src="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/d8b411670b3054c59639e4a3f2b978ef_S.jpg" alt="govt-run-special-buses-for-school-students-poorly-maintained-dmk-says" /></a><font color="#ff3300"><b>Featured</b></font><p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Puducherry: Opposition DMK today demanded that the Directorate of School Education frequently inspect buses run by it for transporting school children and ensure that fleet operators from whom the vehicles are outsourced maintained them properly.</span></p>

<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Convenor of the local unit of DMK Dr M A S Subramanian said in a release here that the directorate was operating the buses for benefit of the students by outsourcing the vehicles from the private sector. On most occasions the 'ill maintained buses' pose threat to students' safety. There were also instances of drunk driving by the drivers, he said.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">He alleged that bus operators who want to skip paying toll on the highways ensure that the vehicles are taken through alternative routes which also pose insecurity to students.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">To overcome these, the Directorate together with Transport authorities should deploy road inspectors and check the vehicles and also ascertain if the drivers had the necessary licences and take action against defaulters, he said.</span></p>]]></description>
			<dc:creator>Edited by Kirti Dwivedi | Updated: 6:55 IST</dc:creator>
			<pubDate>Sat, 13 Sep 2014 15:11:29 -0600</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.newsx.com/regional/tamil-nadu/item/26637-govt-run-special-buses-for-school-students-poorly-maintained-dmk-says</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Human trafficking: Delhi High Court refuses to quash trial against former IFS officer</title>
			<link>http://www.newsx.com/national/nation/item/26636-human-trafficking-delhi-high-court-refuses-to-quash-trial-against-former-ifs-officer</link>
			<description><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/8678d84438e5f181b98dd63d87319bfd_Generic.jpg"><img align="right" border="0" src="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/8678d84438e5f181b98dd63d87319bfd_S.jpg" alt="human-trafficking-delhi-high-court-refuses-to-quash-trial-against-former-ifs-officer" /></a><font color="#ff3300"><b>Featured</b></font><p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">New Delhi: The Delhi High Court has refused to drop criminal proceedings in a trial court against a former IFS officer in a case of alleged corruption and trafficking of 8 people to Germany in 2005, saying it would be inappropriate to quash the trial in the midway for want of valid sanction.</span></p>

<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The high court said that the issue of validity of the sanction to prosecute accused Rakesh Kumar, former Director General (DG) of Indian Council for Cultural Relations (ICCR), would be decided by the trial court.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Justice VP Vaish passed the order while referring to a Supreme Court decision in a similar matter in which it was held that "interdicting" a criminal proceeding mid-course on ground of invalidity of the sanction order will not be appropriate unless the court can also reach the conclusion that failure of justice had been occasioned.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The apex court has also held that failure of justice can be established not at the stage of framing of charge but only after the trial has commenced and evidence has been led, the high noted in its 9-page order.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The high court directed the lower court to expedite the trial which has been pending since 2006.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"It is a settled law that any error, omission or irregularity in the grant of sanction will not affect any finding, sentence or order passed by a competent court unless in the opinion of the court a failure of justice has been occasioned.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"In view of the dictum of the Supreme Court of India in Rajmangal Ram's case, this Court is of the view that it is not appropriate to quash proceedings on the ground of invalidity of the sanction during mid-course of the trial proceedings.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The same will be considered by the trial court after the evidence is adduced by both the parties," the court said.</span></p>]]></description>
			<dc:creator>Edited by Kirti Dwivedi | Updated:  6:45 IST</dc:creator>
			<pubDate>Sat, 13 Sep 2014 14:54:15 -0600</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.newsx.com/national/nation/item/26636-human-trafficking-delhi-high-court-refuses-to-quash-trial-against-former-ifs-officer</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Cover Story by Priya Sahgal: Madeleine Albright former secy. Of sate, US</title>
			<link>http://www.newsx.com/cover-story-by-priya-sahgal/item/26635-cover-story-by-priya-sahgal-madeleine-albright-former-secy-of-sate-us</link>
			<description><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/1d4c94325b3fb84e4846bc0c912414dd_Generic.jpg"><img align="right" border="0" src="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/1d4c94325b3fb84e4846bc0c912414dd_S.jpg" alt="cover-story-by-priya-sahgal-madeleine-albright-former-secy-of-sate-us" /></a><font color="#ff3300"><b>Featured</b></font><p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Cover Story by Priya Sahgal, Madeleine Albright former secy. Of sate, US, Breaking News, Video, News, News update, NewsX</span></p>

<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><iframe src="//www.youtube.com/embed/7PbLfu7S7Bo" frameborder="0" width="684" height="415" allowfullscreen="true" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"></iframe></p>]]></description>
			<dc:creator>NewsX Bureau</dc:creator>
			<pubDate>Sat, 13 Sep 2014 14:46:05 -0600</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.newsx.com/cover-story-by-priya-sahgal/item/26635-cover-story-by-priya-sahgal-madeleine-albright-former-secy-of-sate-us</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Former CAG Vinod Rai criticising Manmohan unacceptable: V Narayanasamy</title>
			<link>http://www.newsx.com/national/nation/item/26634-former-cag-vinod-rai-criticising-manmohan-unacceptable-v-narayanasamy</link>
			<description><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/9f2afbceba78570bef0baeb1309fbf0a_Generic.jpg"><img align="right" border="0" src="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/9f2afbceba78570bef0baeb1309fbf0a_S.jpg" alt="former-cag-vinod-rai-criticising-manmohan-unacceptable-v-narayanasamy" /></a><font color="#ff3300"><b>Featured</b></font><p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Puducherry: Former Minister of State in PMO and senior Congress leader V Narayanasamy on Saturday termed as "untenable" and "unacceptable" ex-CAG Vinod Rai's criticism against former Prime Minister Manmohan Singh in allocations of coal block and the 2G spectrum.</span></p>

<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Speaking to reporters here, he said the erstwhile UPA government had only followed procedures and norms adopted by the previous NDA rule at the Centre in 2G allocation.</span><br /><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Rai's remarks on the role of Manmohan Singh in 2G and coal blocks allocations is absolutely untenable and unacceptable, he said.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">He charged Vinod Rai with indulging in 'double speak' as he had not made such comments while holding the post of CAG.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"It has become a practice on the part of most retired officials and politicians to bring out books and air their views that are contrary to the truth," Narayanasamy said.</span><br /><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Rai, who is writing a book on his days as head of Comptroller and Auditor General of India, had in an interview criticised Singh.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">He said he felt Singh was part of the decisions to allocate 2G telecom spectrum on first-cum-first serve basis and coal blocks without auction.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Narayanasamy also alleged that the Narendra Modi headed government at the Centre was only 'publicity centric' and that issues affecting the people, including inflation, have not been tackled.</span></p>]]></description>
			<dc:creator>Edited by Kirti Dwivedi | Updated: 6:05 IST</dc:creator>
			<pubDate>Sat, 13 Sep 2014 14:44:42 -0600</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.newsx.com/national/nation/item/26634-former-cag-vinod-rai-criticising-manmohan-unacceptable-v-narayanasamy</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Security forces hit hard by J&amp;K floods; hundreds of rifles and bombs still submerged</title>
			<link>http://www.newsx.com/national/nation/item/26633-security-forces-hit-hard-by-jk-floods-hundreds-of-rifles-and-bombs-still-submerged</link>
			<description><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/6adff0c788d4e0027b8472ea9043954e_Generic.jpg"><img align="right" border="0" src="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/6adff0c788d4e0027b8472ea9043954e_S.jpg" alt="security-forces-hit-hard-by-jk-floods-hundreds-of-rifles-and-bombs-still-submerged" /></a><font color="#ff3300"><b>Featured</b></font><p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">SRINAGAR: When calamity strikes, it does not discriminate. This was on ample display when floods ravaged Kashmir.</span></p>

<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Along with civilian population, security forces deployed here from various parts of the country were also hit badly. They lost their belongings and their weapons were damaged or left useless after water entered their camps across the Kashmir valley.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Hundreds of AK rifles, INSAS rifles and SLR rifles, along with their ammunition, are still submerged at various places across the Kashmir valley, so are bombs, hand grenades etc.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Some reports said 26 AK rifles from an Army camp have been washed away in the floods. In the area of Gogji Bagh in uptown Srinagar, one of the worst hit parts of the valley, about 400 personnel of a central paramilitary force had to leave their camp after gushing waters engulfed it last Sunday night.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"We got orders to leave everything and save our lives," said one of them, explaining how weapons remained in the submerged building complex.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">With water level receding somewhat, they are now make rounds of their complex to locate the weapons.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"Rifles can made reusable again by oiling and servicing as also the ammunition. However, bombs and hand grenades would be of no use now," said another security man on condition of anonymity as they are not authorised to speak to media.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Similar was the fate of Army camps in other places in the valley.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">However, as they come to terms with what happened, their colleagues work almost round-the-clock to save marooned civilians and deliver relief material to those who refuse to come out of their submerged houses for fear of theft and looting.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"We start our operations to help the marooned people at 4am every day and halt at midnight. Between midnight and 4am, the boats are serviced," said subedar honorary Lt S P Singh of 103 Engineers Regiment, which is based in Jalandhar and was rushed here five days back to help in rescue and relief operations.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">He, along with his colleagues Naik Nachitra Singh, Naik V D Bhonsle and Naik O P Patel, make rounds of various colonies of Rajbagh, Jawahar Nagar and Nowgam, in boats to ferry the marooned people as well as those evacuees who want to visit their homes.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"Our priority is to save children, women and unwell people," he says, while estimating that their regiment must have rescued at least 10,000 people so far.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Major Ashish Sharma, leading their operations, says about 250-300 people are rescued every day by them.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Besides rescue, they are also engaged in delivering food, medicines and other essentials to people who are marooned but do not want to leave their houses.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Indian Air Force, on its part, has pressed into service 35 aircraft and equal number of helicopters to bring in relief supplies and evacuate people from the valley. These include heavy lift five C-130J and three C-17 aircraft, according to an IAF spokesman.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Relief material is brought from various places including Delhi and Chandigarh, and stranded people are taken to places where arrangements are made for their onward journey to their destinations, the spokesman said.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">He said while initially the thrust was on rescuing people from marooned areas, now it has shifted to providing relief material.</span></p>]]></description>
			<dc:creator>Edited by Kirti Dwivedi | Updated: 6:05 IST</dc:creator>
			<pubDate>Sat, 13 Sep 2014 13:02:37 -0600</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.newsx.com/national/nation/item/26633-security-forces-hit-hard-by-jk-floods-hundreds-of-rifles-and-bombs-still-submerged</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>India-US military training exercise starts Sep 17</title>
			<link>http://www.newsx.com/national/defence/item/26632-india-us-military-training-exercise-starts-sep-17</link>
			<description><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/1ffcdf44597201a25aa031a84d2a7f55_Generic.jpg"><img align="right" border="0" src="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/1ffcdf44597201a25aa031a84d2a7f55_S.jpg" alt="india-us-military-training-exercise-starts-sep-17" /></a><font color="#ff3300"><b>Featured</b></font><p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">New Delhi: The combined India-US military training exercise "Yudh Abhyas 2014" will be conducted from September 17 to September 30, a Defence Ministry statement said on Friday.</span></p>

<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">This is part of the ongoing defence cooperation between the two countries.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"The training exercise will be conducted in the foothills of the Himalayas in Uttarakhand under the aegis of Garud Division and Surya Command," the statement said.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">It added that Indian troops and their US counterparts will hone their skills in the exercise which is the 10th in the series of combined military training exercises between the two countries.</span></p>]]></description>
			<dc:creator>Edited by Kirti Dwivedi | Updated: 5:45 IST</dc:creator>
			<pubDate>Sat, 13 Sep 2014 12:43:27 -0600</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.newsx.com/national/defence/item/26632-india-us-military-training-exercise-starts-sep-17</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>16 killed as bus falls into gorge in Uttarakhand</title>
			<link>http://www.newsx.com/regional/other-states/item/26631-16-killed-as-bus-falls-into-gorge-in-uttarakhand</link>
			<description><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/0f1ec37c5295cb8fc6693bc0739df9ae_Generic.jpg"><img align="right" border="0" src="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/0f1ec37c5295cb8fc6693bc0739df9ae_S.jpg" alt="16-killed-as-bus-falls-into-gorge-in-uttarakhand" /></a><font color="#ff3300"><b>Featured</b></font><p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">DEHRADUN: Sixteeen people were killed and seventeen injured today when a bus in which they were travelling fell into a gorge in Tehri district of Uttarakhand.</span></p>

<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">A total of 33 persons were on board the bus when it fell into a 300 ft deep gorge near Juyalgarh, Tehri superintendent of police Mukhtar Mohsin said.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Nearly half of the bus was submerged in a local stream, which joins River Alaknanda, after the accident, he said.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The bus was going from Haridwar to Karnaprayag. The mishap occurred as the driver tried to overtake another vehicle, he said.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">16 bodies have been recovered and 17 persons were rescued alive from the mangled remains of the bus, Moshin said on phone.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Tehri is about 120 km from here. All the injured were admitted to Srinagar base hospital from where two of them who had sustained minor injuries were discharged after first aid.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Rest of them are undergoing treatment. Expressing deep shock at the loss of lives in the accident, Chief Minister Harish Rawat announced a compensation of Rs 1 lakh each to the next of kin of the deceased and Rs 50,000 each for the injured.</span></p>]]></description>
			<dc:creator>Edited by Kirti Dwivedi | Updated: 5:45 IST</dc:creator>
			<pubDate>Sat, 13 Sep 2014 12:30:30 -0600</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.newsx.com/regional/other-states/item/26631-16-killed-as-bus-falls-into-gorge-in-uttarakhand</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title> BCCI Constitution amended for Arun Jaitley not Srinivasan, says Manohar</title>
			<link>http://www.newsx.com/national/nation/item/26630-bcci-constitution-amended-for-arun-jaitley-not-srinivasan-says-manohar</link>
			<description><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/a20e4ea05462641d61ab8bc250ca9ea0_Generic.jpg"><img align="right" border="0" src="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/a20e4ea05462641d61ab8bc250ca9ea0_S.jpg" alt="bcci-constitution-amended-for-arun-jaitley-not-srinivasan-says-manohar" /></a><font color="#ff3300"><b>Featured</b></font><p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">New Delhi: Former BCCI president Shashank Manohar said on Saturday that the amendment of the BCCI constituition in 2012 regarding president's post was done to ensure that BJP heavyweight Arun Jaitley became board chief in 2014 instead of N Srinivasan going for a second term.</span></p>

<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">In 2012, BCCI constituition was amended wherein an incumbent from a different zone can become president if his name is proposed and seconded by the zone which has the turn to elect the chief.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"I believe that the members decided in favour of amendment of the constituition so that decks are cleared for Mr Arun Jaitley (erstwhile DDCA president and BCCI vice-president) to become the BCCI president from East Zone.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"It was specifically done for Mr Jaitley as he was the unanimous choice of the members," Manohar told PTI in an interview on Saturday.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The Nagpur-based lawyer, one of the most respected voices in BCCI during his time, made it clear that he has no intentions of taking up any post in the world's richest cricket body.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"Let me make it very clear. I am not contesting any elections nor will I ever make a comeback in any capacity in BCCI during my lifetime. I was the BCCI president and I have played my innings. I would like to keep it like that. I have no intentions of making a comeback. Yes, if my help is required, I am ready to offer my expertise," Manohar gave a straightforward reply.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Asked if there are suitable people to become BCCI president, Manohar answered, "There are plenty of people who are capable enough. I would have loved to see Mr Jaitley take over. I will not be able to comment, if he is in a position to take up the job. Mr Sharad Pawar and Mr Jagmohan Dalmiya have also been BCCI presidents earlier and are capable to handle the top job."</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The 56-year-old Manohar also termed BCCI's move to postpone the Annual General Meeting as "unconstitutional".</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"The BCCI has Constitution has been flouted. Article 16(i) of BCCI Constitution clearly states that the BCCI AGM has to be held on or before September 30. There will be a constitutional crisis since the AGM will not be held in the scheduled period," Manohar, a legal expert himself, gave his opinion.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"The Annual Budget is put for approval at the AGM. As per rules, it can't passed at any other forum. BCCI's functions can be hampered," he said.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Why isn't the BCCI members then are raising questions, Manohar said,"I don't know why as I don't attend board meetings. You need to ask those members, who attend board meetings."</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Will it mean that the selection committee technically ceases to exist from October 1 as the West Indies series starts from October 8.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"All committees are named at the AGM. We can cross that bridge when it comes but to avoid constitutional crisis, they can obviously name the Indian squad before September 30," Manohar concluded.</span></p>]]></description>
			<dc:creator>Edited by Kirti Dwivedi | Updated:5:35 IST</dc:creator>
			<pubDate>Sat, 13 Sep 2014 12:22:08 -0600</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.newsx.com/national/nation/item/26630-bcci-constitution-amended-for-arun-jaitley-not-srinivasan-says-manohar</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>BJP president Amit Shah congratulates ABVP on its victory in DUSU polls</title>
			<link>http://www.newsx.com/national/nation/item/26629-bjp-president-amit-shah-congratulates-abvp-on-its-victory-in-dusu-polls</link>
			<description><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/91053bc7af7f7b090f324cabc377df31_Generic.jpg"><img align="right" border="0" src="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/91053bc7af7f7b090f324cabc377df31_S.jpg" alt="bjp-president-amit-shah-congratulates-abvp-on-its-victory-in-dusu-polls" /></a><font color="#ff3300"><b>Featured</b></font><p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">New Delhi: BJP President Amit Shah on Saturday congratulated the Akhil Bhartiya Vidyarthi Parishad for sweeping the Delhi University Students' Union elections by winning all the four posts after a gap of 18 years.</span></p>

<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"I congratulate ABVP for winning all 4 panels in DUSU elections. The students &amp; karyakartas of DU deserve the credit," tweeted Shah, who is in Madhya Pradesh.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">BJP Secretary Shrikant Sharma termed the ABVP's stunning victory a result of the "positive approach" of the party.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">He said this indicates that the youth of the country are in favour of the BJP policies.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">He added that the youth were the future of the country and the dream of 'Ek Bharat, Shreshta Bharat' would be achieved through them.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The ABVP, the students' wing of the BJP, won all posts of president, vice president, secretary and joint secretary, bettering last year's performance when it had lost one of the seats to the National Students Union of India (NSUI).</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Mohit Nagar was elected president of DUSU while Pravesh Malik won the elections for vice president's post. Kanika Shekhawat and Ashutosh Mathur have been elected as secretary and joint secretary respectively.</span></p>]]></description>
			<dc:creator>Edited by Kirti Dwivedi | Updated: 5:05 IST</dc:creator>
			<pubDate>Sat, 13 Sep 2014 12:09:00 -0600</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.newsx.com/national/nation/item/26629-bjp-president-amit-shah-congratulates-abvp-on-its-victory-in-dusu-polls</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Virbhadra rules out mid-term election in Himachal, says his govt stable</title>
			<link>http://www.newsx.com/regional/other-states/item/26628-virbhadra-rules-out-mid-term-election-in-himachal-says-his-govt-stable</link>
			<description><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/dbbe7c2c7ceaf2f1f5d81c1506b1392e_Generic.jpg"><img align="right" border="0" src="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/dbbe7c2c7ceaf2f1f5d81c1506b1392e_S.jpg" alt="virbhadra-rules-out-mid-term-election-in-himachal-says-his-govt-stable" /></a><font color="#ff3300"><b>Featured</b></font><p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Hamirpur: Asserting that his government was firm and stable, Himachal Pradesh Chief Minister Virbhadra Singh on Saturday ruled out mid term assembly polls in the state.</span></p>

<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"My government enjoys absolute majority and would complete its five year term. BJP leaders, who are spreading canards regarding the stability of my government, would be disappointed," he said while talking to mediapersons here.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Singh also ruled out any reshuffle in his cabinet and said all ministers were functioning well.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The ministers have been given complete freedom to work the way they want, but once the cabinet takes a decision it is binding on all the ministers, he said.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"I am not a dictator. I am concerned about the well-being and welfare of the masses but the decisions taken in the state cabinet are binding on all ministers and no one should have an impression that he is above the cabinet," he added.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Hitting out at BJP leaders, especially former Chief Minister Prem Kumar Dhumal and his MP son Anurag Thkaur, for "unleashing a vilification campaign against him", Singh said their nefarious designs would never succeed.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"The previous BJP governments led by Dhumal had tried to implicate me in false cases but thanks to God, I got clean chit from courts and came out unscathed," he said.</span></p>]]></description>
			<dc:creator>Edited by Kirti Dwivedi | Updated: 4:45 IST</dc:creator>
			<pubDate>Sat, 13 Sep 2014 12:04:12 -0600</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.newsx.com/regional/other-states/item/26628-virbhadra-rules-out-mid-term-election-in-himachal-says-his-govt-stable</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Movie Review: Finding Fanny</title>
			<link>http://www.newsx.com/showbiz/reviews/item/26627-movie-review-finding-fanny</link>
			<description><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/508edbf9396be360d9a34e6ea7d7e63b_Generic.jpg"><img align="right" border="0" src="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/508edbf9396be360d9a34e6ea7d7e63b_S.jpg" alt="movie-review-finding-fanny" /></a><font color="#ff3300"><b>Featured</b></font><p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;"><strong>Star Cast</strong>: Deepika Padukone, Arjun Kapoor, Nasseruddin Shah, Dimple Kapadia, Pankaj Kapoor</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;"><strong>Director</strong>: Homi Adajania</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;"><strong>Genre</strong>: Comedy</span></p>

<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;"><strong>Review</strong>:</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">‘Finding Fanny’ movie surrounds the five most fantastic characters: Ferdie (Naseeruddin Shah), the very emotional and trustworthy man who has lost the woman whom he loved. Rosie (Dimple Kapadia), the overbearing woman, who always hides her helplessness. Don Pedro (Pankaj Kapoor), an original painter who paints with fake charm. The beautiful and gorgeous Angie (Deepika Padukone) is widow in this movie and gets emotionally attached to Savio (Arjun Kapoor).</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">But look beyond this and there are things which cannot leave you without admiring; that is Angie, who lives with her mother-in-law Rosie and the two lovely women lives without their men in their life.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Homi Adajania’s film is set in the village of Goa called Pocolim where life is too simple. The journey starts when Ferdie finding a letter which was written by him to Fanny (Anjali Patil) 46 years ago. But, unfortunately, the letter was never delivered to her and therefore, he could never express his feelings towards her.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The gorgeous and dimpled girl Angie decides to help the old man Ferdie to find his lost love. Now, the journey starts of ‘Finding Fanny’. There is no destination of this journey but it does not matter as it is the journey of five characters that are totally different.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Savio, the old friend of Angie, who loved her for while now, agrees to help Angie to find Ferdie’s lost love.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Don Pedro, the painter, is mostly overdone flourish who finds his inspiration in Angie’s mother-in-law Rosie’s figure.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The most important role in this movie is of Ferdie (Naseeruddin Shah) who plays a very different role and we can undoubtedly term it is ‘Classic’.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">While Homi Adajania’s film is so slow and simple, the best thing is that the director has made this flick for the fun loving generation. There are some scenes in this film that will leave you in the confusion and splits.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Apart from this, it can be said that all the top five actors has acted very well and displayed their best talent in this amazing movie.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;"><strong>NewsX Verdict</strong>: If you want to watch something different, go and watch Homi Adajania’s film ‘<strong>Finding Fanny</strong>’ that is completely different from other movies. Must watch this movie for a different experience that leaves you in a light and cheery mood!</span></p>]]></description>
			<dc:creator>Written By Alka Sinha</dc:creator>
			<pubDate>Sat, 13 Sep 2014 11:39:17 -0600</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.newsx.com/showbiz/reviews/item/26627-movie-review-finding-fanny</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Is India okay with Pre-Marital Sex; You know it’s a taboo when it’s real!</title>
			<link>http://www.newsx.com/life-style/most-popular/item/26626-is-india-okay-with-pre-marital-sex-you-know-its-a-taboo-when-its-real</link>
			<description><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/5ae0e084deb195c7573a6da04f8e8444_Generic.jpg"><img align="right" border="0" src="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/5ae0e084deb195c7573a6da04f8e8444_S.jpg" alt="is-india-okay-with-pre-marital-sex-you-know-its-a-taboo-when-its-real" /></a><font color="#ff3300"><b>Featured</b></font><p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">After an astronomical amount of buzz created by an influential poster designed by one of the online student newspaper platforms in New Delhi, the audiences have yet again opened their arms to welcome the discussions of pre-marital sex.</span></p>

<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The poster showed the silhouette of a middle aged woman tagged along with the words - “Stay away from boys until we force you to sleep with one.”</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">India is considered to be one such culturally rich country which has been stealing the eyeballs of many through the vibrancy of its colourful heritage. Yet, some of the shady corners are still meant to be put light on which according to a lot of its citizens are accepted to be overshadowed under the aura of mere ‘culture’.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Almost 62% of the people living in India have come out of the nutshell believing sex before marriage to be a healthy and prudent habit practised by the adults, leaving a considerable amount still considering it as just another ‘ irresponsible western mantra’ residing as a taboo in the Indian society.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">There are a handful of instances where we can encounter how the word ‘sex’ itself is known to be a restricted term in our everyday lives and the mere usage of the word means scandalizing and reddening the colours of some of the thickest cheeks with the noses wiggling upside down as if someone has threatened them to blend them all in a drink!</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The most important root triggering the characteristics of this ‘taboo-centric-word’ lies in the fact of how the society sees a woman. No matter what the evens or the odds are, a woman is never expected to do the math alone.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The society never expects her to raise her child alone. Statistically, more than half of the country considers a woman to be emotionally and physically vulnerable in critical conditions like delivery of or raising up a child. A woman is expected to need someone in this rigorous and extremely important step of her life. Having sex before marriage, at times clearly clear up this space for her and may put her into the circle of raising a child alone.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">A child who has been brought by a single mother is nonetheless a taboo himself. The virtues, the chastity, the financial expenses are such poisonous and mythical barriers which restrict his mother to let him walk to his school alone.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">“I want to save my virginity for someone special” is what they want all of the countrymen to believe in. But is it really so? Are we so engrossed and obsessed with the whole concept of virginity that the actual sanctity of sex seems to be a forgettable term?</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Contrary to what many boys and girls are taught since their first day on the planet, sex is, was and will be the most inevitable and beautiful thing that could happen to this world. Not just it makes the world go, but it also helps a person to revive his/her relationships and blooming love. The way the idea of sex and virginity has been fenced within the boundaries and implications of marriage and institutions are commendably sad.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">How can something which is one of the most realistic concepts in the world fall into the category of taboo cards, one may never know! You know it’s a taboo, when it’s real, maybe.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Scientifically, sex has a lot of advantages of its own. Not only does it promote good communication, it also helps in building a good foundation of a relationship. Generosity encouragement, greater alacrity of affection and feel good factors are all kith and kin with sex. Why should it be confined with the ‘ideal concept’ of marriage?</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Can’t sex speak for itself? Can’t virginity be talked about more often? Can’t those biology classes be a little more descriptive? Can’t the youngsters be aware of how to differentiate between healthy and unhealthy sex? Shouldn’t the adolescents know about the basic sex rights? Shouldn’t a mentally and physically strong woman be empowered with the responsibility of raising her child alone if she really wants to?</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">These questions can never be answered if all that comes in the box is a prescription to cross a particular age and marry someone after bathing in gold and riches of our ‘culturally-thick-landscape’. It’s time to get loose with that string which seems to have been placed at a distant place, but is nonetheless something you can definitely touch, show and talk about.</span></p>]]></description>
			<dc:creator>Written by Ayushree Nandan</dc:creator>
			<pubDate>Sat, 13 Sep 2014 11:14:40 -0600</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.newsx.com/life-style/most-popular/item/26626-is-india-okay-with-pre-marital-sex-you-know-its-a-taboo-when-its-real</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Distressing video exposes the brutality of the militants</title>
			<link>http://www.newsx.com/national/nation/item/26625-chilling-video-shows-alleged-gnla-militants-thrashing-police-informers</link>
			<description><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/a61a4f86178a2feec7067c83897b5fa5_Generic.jpg"><img align="right" border="0" src="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/a61a4f86178a2feec7067c83897b5fa5_S.jpg" alt="chilling-video-shows-alleged-gnla-militants-thrashing-police-informers" /></a><font color="#ff3300"><b>Featured</b></font><p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Shillong: A disturbing video has come out in the front from Meghalaya which shows alleged militants of the Garo National Liberation Army (GNLA) cruelly battering supposed ‘police informers’.</span></p>

<p><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The video has been released by the Meghalaya police and as per the reports; police approved the authenticity of the video and explains that it was taken via a mobile phone on September 4.</span></p>
<p><iframe src="//www.youtube.com/embed/rAUiDEMRYUg" frameborder="0" width="684" height="415" allowfullscreen="true" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"></iframe></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">&nbsp;</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The video was found in the mobile of one of the GNLA militants, K Marak killed in an encounter with police on September 10 at Pakregre village, informed Davies N Marak, East Garo Hills superintendent of police to a daily.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The video exposes the mercilessness of the militants as the beat the villagers with canes until they went unconscious. Some of the villagers were even beaten up by four to five men together.</span></p>]]></description>
			<dc:creator>Written by Charnamrit Sachdeva`</dc:creator>
			<pubDate>Sat, 13 Sep 2014 11:03:13 -0600</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.newsx.com/national/nation/item/26625-chilling-video-shows-alleged-gnla-militants-thrashing-police-informers</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Minor allegedly gang-raped in UP</title>
			<link>http://www.newsx.com/regional/up/item/26624-minor-allegedly-gang-raped-in-up</link>
			<description><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/2a3e0b4d3ca926edc80d6bb3f45fd529_Generic.jpg"><img align="right" border="0" src="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/2a3e0b4d3ca926edc80d6bb3f45fd529_S.jpg" alt="minor-allegedly-gang-raped-in-up" /></a><font color="#ff3300"><b>Featured</b></font><p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Badaun (UP): A 13-year-old girl was allegedly kidnapped and gang-raped by four persons in Jareefnagar area here, following which two of them have been arrested, police said on Saturday.</span></p>

<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The incident took place last night when the victim, who was sleeping on the terrace of her house, was kidnapped and raped by the four, SSP Santosh Kumar Singh said.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The accused have been identified as Amit, Muktiyaar, Bhola Pandit, and Dannu, he said.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Amit and Muktiyaar have been arrested following a complaint by the girl's father while Bhola and Dannu are absconding, police said.</span></p>]]></description>
			<dc:creator>Edited by Kirti Dwivedi | Updated: 4:45 IST</dc:creator>
			<pubDate>Sat, 13 Sep 2014 10:49:24 -0600</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.newsx.com/regional/up/item/26624-minor-allegedly-gang-raped-in-up</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Never said BJP should form government in Delhi: Sheila Dikshit</title>
			<link>http://www.newsx.com/national/nation/item/26623-never-said-bjp-should-form-government-in-delhi-sheila-dikshit</link>
			<description><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/880a027b2b5788ded6a3cc38a8d20d19_Generic.jpg"><img align="right" border="0" src="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/880a027b2b5788ded6a3cc38a8d20d19_S.jpg" alt="never-said-bjp-should-form-government-in-delhi-sheila-dikshit" /></a><font color="#ff3300"><b>Featured</b></font><p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">New Delhi: Former Delhi Chief Minister Sheila Dikshit on Saturday defended herself saying that she never backed the Bharatiya Janata Party to form government in the national capital.</span></p>

<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"I never said BJP should form Delhi government. All I said was that if they have numbers they should form the government," she said.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Sheila Dikshit had on Thursday stirred a controversy by saying that BJP should be given an opportunity to form government in Delhi as it will be good for the people.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"In a democracy, elected governments are always good as they represent the people. If BJP has reached such a situation that it can form government, it is good for Delhi," Dikshit had said.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The Delhi chief minister for 15 years has also ruled herself out of the race for power in Delhi. She said, "I rule myself out of Delhi completely. I am not interested. Let the young generation take over."</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">She also said that she was pressured to step down as Kerala governor. "The way a bureaucrat called me asking me to quit was not right. Governor is a constitutional position. I suggest that Parliament should come out with a law that when new government comes in, old governor should automatically resign. Look how they treated Kamla Beniwal. Why should transfers to North east be seen as punishment postings," Dikshit said.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">She also defended former prime minister Manmohan Singh and slammed former CAG Vinod Rai for making stinging allegations against him in the 2G spectrum case. "No one has the right to blame him. Why didn't Vinod Rai raise it earlier," she questioned.</span></p>]]></description>
			<dc:creator>Edited by Kirti Dwivedi | Updated: 4:25 IST</dc:creator>
			<pubDate>Sat, 13 Sep 2014 10:45:05 -0600</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.newsx.com/national/nation/item/26623-never-said-bjp-should-form-government-in-delhi-sheila-dikshit</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Judicial independence not negotiable, says CJ Lodha</title>
			<link>http://www.newsx.com/national/nation/item/26621-judicial-independence-not-negotiable-says-cj-lodha</link>
			<description><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/e5b020d106b0dd019776f131b2e1b753_Generic.jpg"><img align="right" border="0" src="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/e5b020d106b0dd019776f131b2e1b753_S.jpg" alt="judicial-independence-not-negotiable-says-cj-lodha" /></a><font color="#ff3300"><b>Featured</b></font><p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">New Delhi: Chief Justice RM Lodha on Saturday said that India has already arrived at a stage where nobody can tinker with the independence of the judiciary, but exhorted that to strengthen the role of law, the judiciary will have to ensure that it was completely corruption-free.</span></p>

<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"The independence of the judiciary is not negotiable. I can say with confidence that judicial independence has come to stay and no effort will succeed in taking it away.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"By and large, people understand that judicial independence is something which cannot be touched," said Chief Justice Lodha in his inaugural address at a conference organised by the Bar Association of India here.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The chief justice said that judicial independence will be upheld.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">He also said that as long as there is judicial independence, the rule of law will be strengthened.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The chief justice said that judicial independence gives confidence to the people that there is an independent judiciary that will come to their rescue if any wrong is done to them.</span></p>]]></description>
			<dc:creator>Edited by Kirti Dwivedi | Updated: 3:55 IST</dc:creator>
			<pubDate>Sat, 13 Sep 2014 10:22:51 -0600</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.newsx.com/national/nation/item/26621-judicial-independence-not-negotiable-says-cj-lodha</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Sheikh Hasina and Narendra Modi to meet in US</title>
			<link>http://www.newsx.com/world/asia/item/26620-sheikh-hasina-and-narendra-modi-to-meet-in-us</link>
			<description><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/5d32f32c7e5b8fad6b1b74422155f32c_Generic.jpg"><img align="right" border="0" src="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/5d32f32c7e5b8fad6b1b74422155f32c_S.jpg" alt="sheikh-hasina-and-narendra-modi-to-meet-in-us" /></a><font color="#ff3300"><b>Featured</b></font><p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Dhaka: Bangladesh Prime Minister Sheikh Hasina and her Indian counterpart Narendra Modi are scheduled to meet in New York this month during the UN General Assembly (UNGA), media reported Saturday.</span></p>

<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">This would be the first meeting between Modi and Hasina after the BJP came to power in India in May, bdnews 24 reported.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Permanent representative of Bangladesh to the United Nations, Abulkalam Abdul Momen, said that the two leaders will meet Sep 27.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"Narendra Modi will be the sixth speaker while Sheikh Hasina is the eighth at the General Assembly Sep 27. They will meet after their speeches are over," said Momen.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Hasina will arrive in New York Sep 22 to attend the 69th UN General Assembly.</span></p>]]></description>
			<dc:creator>Edited by Kirti Dwivedi | Updated: 3:35 IST</dc:creator>
			<pubDate>Sat, 13 Sep 2014 10:07:35 -0600</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.newsx.com/world/asia/item/26620-sheikh-hasina-and-narendra-modi-to-meet-in-us</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>'PM Narendra Modi should share power with states for real success'</title>
			<link>http://www.newsx.com/national/nation/item/26619-pm-narendra-modi-should-share-power-with-states-for-real-success</link>
			<description><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/e77fbcdf0fdb1f12bf4739b374d7d171_Generic.jpg"><img align="right" border="0" src="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/e77fbcdf0fdb1f12bf4739b374d7d171_S.jpg" alt="pm-narendra-modi-should-share-power-with-states-for-real-success" /></a><font color="#ff3300"><b>Featured</b></font><p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Hyderabad: If Prime Minister Narendra Modi and Chinese President Xi Jinping have to really succeed they will have to share power with state-level leaders and work with them, feels an American political scientist.</span></p>

<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">William J Antholis, managing director and senior fellow in Governance Studies at The Brookings Institute, an influential US think tank, believes Modi will work with the state-level leaders as he himself served as the chief minister of Gujarat.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">He said the Indian prime minister also stated in his Independence Day address that he believes in empowering chief ministers.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The American political scientist feels though the Modi government enjoys majority in Lok Sabha, it will still have to work with regional parties in the upper house of the Parliament.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"We have powerful leaders in both India and China. There is paradox of their power. There is something they can do centrally but for real success to happen they have to share power with state level leaders or work them," he said in an interaction with a select group of journalists here.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Antholis is the author of "Inside Out, India and China: Local Politics Go Global" published last year in which he explores how country-sized provinces and states in both the countries are increasingly becoming global players.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Antholis, who plans to release the book in India in a couple of weeks with a new preface, believes that state level leaders in India have started seizing responsibility that comes with elected authority where as in the past they let the bureaucracy take the power and dissipate.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The analyst, who met Modi and several state-level leaders before writing the book, said Modi was not elected because of nationalism but because of his economic message. He pointed out that some prominent Muslim Indian writers like MJ Akbar embraced his candidacy.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"There can be a bad side of his nationalism and there can be a good side," he said and pointed out that he has shown good side by reaching out to Pakistan and also by mooting inter-communal truce for 10 years. "Although we hope for a permanent peace treaty," he said.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"If he goes out of way to pick up fight with Pakistan or foment inter-communal violence, people will not be happy. Americans will be enthusiastic about the initial signs he has given," he said.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Antholis compared Modi to former US president Ronald Reagan. He said like Reagan, Modi is a nationalist and also stands for free market.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">He said one should not set high expectations from Modi's upcoming visit to US. "This is a turning point for India and in all its bilateral relations not just with US but with Japan, Australia, China, Bhutan and Pakistan...," he said.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">He believes Modi had an opportunity to lay down for President Obama the things that are important from his side of relations. He said the strengths in India-US relations which were taken for granted are the people to people connection. He stressed on working on those strengths for long-time relationship and not just for making few announcements.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">On Chinese President Xi Jinping's visit to India, he said good trading relations were crucial for both the countries. He said China needed innovative economy which India can teach it and India needed hard Chinese investments.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">He, however, said security concerns were real on border, in oceans and even in cyber side as Chinese hackers can be very disruptive. "It is important that India make clear that it is not going to be pushed around."</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"US and Japan are eager to work with India. This will be a little bit threat to China as it will feel encircled by US and Japan but for all three countries it is important to make sure that China doesn't stumble into trouble unintentionally," he said and pointed out that as it grows its economy China is thirsty for oil and energy.</span></p>]]></description>
			<dc:creator>Edited by Kirti Dwivedi | Updated: 3:15 IST</dc:creator>
			<pubDate>Sat, 13 Sep 2014 09:43:21 -0600</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.newsx.com/national/nation/item/26619-pm-narendra-modi-should-share-power-with-states-for-real-success</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>ABVP sweeps DUSU polls after 18 years</title>
			<link>http://www.newsx.com/national/nation/item/26618-abvp-sweeps-dusu-polls-after-18-years</link>
			<description><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/9b2604d81efcb24b547f0985e035cb55_Generic.jpg"><img align="right" border="0" src="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/9b2604d81efcb24b547f0985e035cb55_S.jpg" alt="abvp-sweeps-dusu-polls-after-18-years" /></a><font color="#ff3300"><b>Featured</b></font><p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">After a gap of 18 years, BJP's student wing Akhil Bhartiya Vidyarthi Parishad today swept Delhi University students' union elections, trouncing Congress' NSUI to bag all four positions and credited the triumph to "Modi wave".</span></p>

<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The ABVP won posts of president, vice president, secretary and joint secretary by comfortable margins, bettering last year's performance when it had lost one of the seats to the National Students' Union of India (NSUI).</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Mohit Nagar was elected president of DUSU while Pravesh Malik won the elections for vice president's post. Kanika Shekhawat and Ashutosh Mathur have been elected as secretary and joint secretary respectively.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Chief Election Officer for the DUSU polls DS Rawat said Nagar polled 20,718 votes defeating Gaurav Tushir of NSUI who polled 19,804 votes for the post of president. The margin of defeat was 914.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Last year ABVP had won the posts of president, vice-president and joint secretary while NSUI had managed to capture only secretary's post.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"Expectations of people have gone up after Modi government came to power. The ABVP fulfilled its promises of scrapping the four-year undergraduate (FYUP) programme. We won because of the Modi wave," said Rohit Chahal, National Secretary, ABVP.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">BJP national president Amit Shah took to twitter to congratulate ABVP on their victory.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"I congratulate ABVP for winning all 4 panels in DUSU elections. The students &amp; karyakartas of DU deserve the credit," he tweeted.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Parvesh Malik, who polled 21,935 votes, defeated NSUI's candidate Mona Chodhary with the margin of 7,859 votes. Chodhary got 15,649 votes, Rawat said.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">He said Shekhawat defeated NSUI's Amit Sidhu Teema by 3022 votes. Shekhawat polled 18,671 votes while Teema polled 15,649 votes.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">ABVP joint secretary candidate Ashutosh Mathur polled 23,133 votes while NSUI's Abhishek Choudhary got only 12,065 votes. Mathur defeated Choudhary by 11,068 votes, which is the highest margin among all the winning candidates.</span></p>]]></description>
			<dc:creator>Edited by Priyanka Kukreja || Updated: 14:50 IST</dc:creator>
			<pubDate>Sat, 13 Sep 2014 09:03:43 -0600</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.newsx.com/national/nation/item/26618-abvp-sweeps-dusu-polls-after-18-years</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Photographers boycott Salman's 'Bigg Boss' event</title>
			<link>http://www.newsx.com/showbiz/celebrities/item/26617-photographers-boycott-salmans-bigg-boss-event</link>
			<description><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/79bd39004177a41c21ee2bfaaeae65c5_Generic.jpg"><img align="right" border="0" src="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/79bd39004177a41c21ee2bfaaeae65c5_S.jpg" alt="photographers-boycott-salmans-bigg-boss-event" /></a><font color="#ff3300"><b>Featured</b></font><p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Photographers, who have decided to boycott Salman Khan's events after their alleged scuffle with his bouncers, were missing during a press conference for 'Bigg Boss 8'.</span></p>

<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Salman, 48, had only a handful of photographers for the event.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"It is a lovely stand they have taken. I respect that. It is, in fact, my loss. They are taking pictures of all but me so it is not even their loss. I haven't banned them, they have boycotted me," the actor said.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">When asked if he would like to make peace with the photographers, Salman said they need to make peace with themselves first.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"I am fine with them, I am open to getting clicked but if one wants to take pictures then it has to be done respectfully. It can't become like a fish market," the 'Dabangg' star said.</span></p>]]></description>
			<dc:creator>Edited by Priyanka Kukreja || Updated: 14:30 IST</dc:creator>
			<pubDate>Sat, 13 Sep 2014 08:45:17 -0600</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.newsx.com/showbiz/celebrities/item/26617-photographers-boycott-salmans-bigg-boss-event</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Saddal hamlet wiped out in few terrifying moments</title>
			<link>http://www.newsx.com/national/nation/item/26616-saddal-hamlet-wiped-out-in-few-terrifying-moments</link>
			<description><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/78bd52dae91ff192f91342e468584ee1_Generic.jpg"><img align="right" border="0" src="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/78bd52dae91ff192f91342e468584ee1_S.jpg" alt="saddal-hamlet-wiped-out-in-few-terrifying-moments" /></a><font color="#ff3300"><b>Featured</b></font><p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">In less than one minute, Yash Pal's life changed forever as a whole mountain came crashing down devouring this hamlet following torrential rains and buried his family of six.</span></p>

<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">There is no trace of nine members of Sunku Ram's family too as their house is buried under a big boulder, which the rescuers are finding difficult to remove manually. The landslide on September7 killed at least 41 villagers, including children, women and elderly, in Panchari Hills in Jammu and Kashmir.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Rescuers have so far recovered just 10 bodies. As the operation advanced today, a child's slate with illegible scrawls was peeking from the rubble. Clothes, shoes and severd body parts were retrieved as the personnel continued with the heartbreaking process.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Unlike Yash and Sunku Ram, another villager Panch Kartar Singh was lucky. He escaped along with his family from the massive landslide that has changed the topography of the area where Punjar-Saddal village once thrived.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The stunned survivors say they will never forget the horrifying moments when the tragedy struck.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Kartar, who is still in trauma, said, "In just less than a minute all was finished. The mountain crumbled before my eyes. There was no sign that Punjar-Saddal ever existed.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"I cannot forget that I am still alive. It was all before my eyes. There were heavy rains and we were about to leave. Few stones were rolling intermittently. Suddenly there was this loud sound and the mountain came crumbling down in just less than a minute."</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Kartar and his five family members narrowly escaped as big boulders and mud slides struck a few meters from his house.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"There was not a minute left for us to get out. My entire family was buried in this tomb," said an inconsolable Yash.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Like him, Ganesh Singh recalls the last phone call to his brother, who told him that they were in danger due to cracks in their house.</span></p>]]></description>
			<dc:creator>Edited by Priyanka Kukreja || Updated: 14:00 IST</dc:creator>
			<pubDate>Sat, 13 Sep 2014 08:16:56 -0600</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.newsx.com/national/nation/item/26616-saddal-hamlet-wiped-out-in-few-terrifying-moments</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Soldiers defeat Islamic fighters in north Nigeria</title>
			<link>http://www.newsx.com/world/others/item/26615-soldiers-defeat-islamic-fighters-in-north-nigeria</link>
			<description><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/8c1adc144a6068346b752379a11a93ac_Generic.jpg"><img align="right" border="0" src="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/8c1adc144a6068346b752379a11a93ac_S.jpg" alt="soldiers-defeat-islamic-fighters-in-north-nigeria" /></a><font color="#ff3300"><b>Featured</b></font><p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Soldiers killed scores of Islamic extremists in a rare victory as the insurgents advanced on a town near the northeast city of Maiduguri, an officer and other witnesses said.</span></p>

<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">One officer said a feared Boko Haram commander known only as Amir was among some 200 militants killed in a battle yesterday in Konduga town, 35 kilometres (22 miles) from Maiduguri, the capital of Borno state and birthplace of the extremist group.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Also killed was a Boko Haram video journalist and a suicide bomber, he said.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">There were no military casualties, according to the officer and a civilian self-defense group that fights alongside the soldiers. Both spoke on condition of anonymity because they are not authorized to speak to reporters.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Boko Haram in recent weeks has taken a string of towns stretching over 200 miles (320 kilometres) alongside Nigeria's northeast border with Cameroon in a new campaign to create an Islamic caliphate, mimicking the IS group in Syria and Iraq.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The extremists also have attacked a town and villages across the border in Cameroon, but that country's state radio said Cameroonian troops beat them off and forced them back across the border into Nigeria.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The US said last week it is about to launch a major border security program for Nigeria and its neighbors, but gave no details.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Thousands of civilians have been forced from their homes in the latest offensive, joining more than 1.5 million other Nigerians who are refugees within their country or across borders in Niger, Cameroon and Chad, according to UN figures.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Extremists who have taken other towns have told residents that their next target is Maiduguri, the headquarters of the military campaign in the northeast.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Boko Haram has attacked the city several times, with suicide and car bombs that have killed scores. In December they launched a bold attack on an air force base on the outskirts in which they destroyed five aircraft and in February an assault on the main military barracks in the city in which they freed hundreds of detainees. The soldiers killed hundreds of unarmed detainees in the aftermath of that last attack, mostly civilians accused of belonging or supporting the insurgency. Amnesty International put the number of civilians killed by the soldiers at nearly 700.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Nigeria's military is accused of massive human rights abuses in the fight against the extremists, including the deaths of thousands of illegally detained people.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The United States has said it is launching a major border security project for Nigeria.</span></p>]]></description>
			<dc:creator>Edited by Priyanka Kukreja || Updated: 13:40 IST</dc:creator>
			<pubDate>Sat, 13 Sep 2014 08:01:55 -0600</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.newsx.com/world/others/item/26615-soldiers-defeat-islamic-fighters-in-north-nigeria</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>My autobiography will ruffle few feathers in industry: Naseer</title>
			<link>http://www.newsx.com/showbiz/celebrities/item/26614-my-autobiography-will-ruffle-few-feathers-in-industry-naseer</link>
			<description><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/1182f28442054e5ecc07f55471b5f44e_Generic.jpg"><img align="right" border="0" src="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/1182f28442054e5ecc07f55471b5f44e_S.jpg" alt="my-autobiography-will-ruffle-few-feathers-in-industry-naseer" /></a><font color="#ff3300"><b>Featured</b></font><p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Naseeruddin Shah's memoir "And Then One Day" is a candid recount of almost four decades of his life and the actor is happy that it is being appreciated though he says it may ruffle a few feathers in the film industry.</span></p>

<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">One of the most formidable actors in Hindi cinema, Shah started writing about his life in 2002 but was not sure about its quality so he kept postponing it.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"It is gratifying... The reaction that I am getting for the book. A lot of people who have read the book have liked it including Shyam Benegal, Girish Karnad, Ramchandra Guha and my brothers. So I am happy if that is the case.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"Though I suspect it will ruffle a few feathers in the film industry but that is not of any concern to me. It has never been my concern," Shah told PTI in an interview.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">When asked why he was hesitant to release the book, he said he was not sure that anyone would be interested in reading his life story.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"I did not think that it would of any interest to anybody. I needed another opinion so I gave it to Guha... He encouraged me very much and I took that seriously because he himself is a very good writer. I have read his books on cricket and Gandhi. They are superb.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"I thought if someone like him is finding my book readable then others will also like to read it. That's why I completed it."</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The 64-year-old actor said he is not sure whether he will come up with the second part of the story.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"I am not planning anything. I did not plan this one either. I am not promising a second one but I don't know," he said.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Shah is currently on screens playing a quirky, hopelessly- in-love role of a Goan village postman Ferdie who embarks on a trip to find out his childhood love in Homi Adajania's "Finding Fanny".</span></p>]]></description>
			<dc:creator>Edited by Priyanka Kukreja || Updated: 13:20 IST</dc:creator>
			<pubDate>Sat, 13 Sep 2014 07:42:48 -0600</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.newsx.com/showbiz/celebrities/item/26614-my-autobiography-will-ruffle-few-feathers-in-industry-naseer</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Campus Connect: Who decides moral boundaries for women?</title>
			<link>http://www.newsx.com/shows/specials/item/26613-campus-connect-who-decides-moral-boundaries-for-women?</link>
			<description><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/0654ec63d1d6b0f180668b2995fa9835_Generic.jpg"><img align="right" border="0" src="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/0654ec63d1d6b0f180668b2995fa9835_S.jpg" alt="campus-connect-who-decides-moral-boundaries-for-women?" /></a><p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">In this exclusive episode of Campus Connect, we are in yet another college that is IP college for women of Delhi University.</span></p>

<p style="text-align: justify;">&nbsp;</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The question, we are putting out today, is, whom is to be blamed for moral boundaries for women and who decides the moral boundaries for women?</span></p>
<p><iframe src="//www.youtube.com/embed/z08ZGTaWrH0" frameborder="0" width="684" height="415" allowfullscreen="true" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"></iframe></p>]]></description>
			<dc:creator>NewsX Bureau</dc:creator>
			<pubDate>Sat, 13 Sep 2014 07:36:15 -0600</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.newsx.com/shows/specials/item/26613-campus-connect-who-decides-moral-boundaries-for-women?</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Obama's war plan rattles Senate nominees</title>
			<link>http://www.newsx.com/world/us/item/26612-obamas-war-plan-rattles-senate-nominees</link>
			<description><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/82595a3a60cfaf8ba2f58f24247660e8_Generic.jpg"><img align="right" border="0" src="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/82595a3a60cfaf8ba2f58f24247660e8_S.jpg" alt="obamas-war-plan-rattles-senate-nominees" /></a><font color="#ff3300"><b>Featured</b></font><p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">President Barack Obama's plan to strike Islamic State militants is ruffling the usual left-right politics in several races that will decide control of the US Senate in mid-term elections on November 4.</span></p>

<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Republicans who have criticised the president on a variety of issues for months have tamped down their rhetoric and, frequently, are avoiding taking a clear stand on his proposal. Some of the nation's most endangered incumbent Senate Democrats, meanwhile, have expressed skepticism to portions of Obama's plan, saying they fear a new plunge into a new Middle East war where supposed allies can become enemies.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Others want to talk about something else, or are trying to avoid talking about the issue at all.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The complexities, leading to mixed and cautious responses from both sides, mean the issue might not matter much at all come Election Day, when Republicans need a net gain of six seats to take control of the Senate.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The Nov. 4 vote is called a midterm election because it falls halfway through a president's four years in office.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The vote will take place in a political climate that is deadlocked in partisanship worse than at any time in modern American history.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"I'm having a hard time seeing this as a game-changer," said William A. Galston, a Brookings Institution scholar and former Clinton White House adviser. "A lot of people who would have said 'hell no' to the president's speech were cheering him on."</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Republicans have made attacking Obama and his policies the cornerstone of their Senate campaign, especially as they target Democrats in states the president lost in 2012.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">They had in recent days stepped up their attacks on the president's foreign policy, hoping to further tie vulnerable Democrats to an unpopular leader.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Despite that rhetoric, several Republican Senate candidates appear wary of taking detailed positions on the president's proposal to fight Islamic State militants with air strikes and US-armed Syrian rebels, but not American ground troops, since he laid it out in a televised speech Wednesday night.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">New Hampshire Republican Senate nominee Scott Brown, a former senator from Massachusetts, sharply criticised Obama's leadership in an interview yesterday. But he declined to say whether he would vote to authorize more military intervention in the Mideast.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"I would need to listen to the generals on the ground and get their input and guidance as I have in the past," he said. "When you're ... Making a decision to send people into harm's way, you need to have all the facts and I don't have those facts.</span></p>]]></description>
			<dc:creator>Edited by Priyanka Kukreja || Updated: 12:20 IST</dc:creator>
			<pubDate>Sat, 13 Sep 2014 06:35:31 -0600</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.newsx.com/world/us/item/26612-obamas-war-plan-rattles-senate-nominees</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Jammu-Srinagar NH remains closed for traffic</title>
			<link>http://www.newsx.com/national/nation/item/26610-jammu-srinagar-nh-remains-closed-for-traffic</link>
			<description><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/bb89930705a5c5a62efa069d6cb8c27b_Generic.jpg"><img align="right" border="0" src="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/bb89930705a5c5a62efa069d6cb8c27b_S.jpg" alt="jammu-srinagar-nh-remains-closed-for-traffic" /></a><font color="#ff3300"><b>Featured</b></font><p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The Jammu-Srinagar National Highway remained closed for the tenth consecutive day today due to landslides and sinking of road at various places, with hundreds of vehicles stranded on the route.</span></p>

<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The traffic was suspended on the 300-km-long crucial road link due to landslides, washing of road patches and flooding at various places on September 4.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Hundreds of passenger and commercial vehicles were stranded on the highway at various place in Banihal, Ramban, Batote, Kud, Patnitop, Chenani, Udhampur and Jammu due to closure of the road, police officials said.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The Border Roads Organisation (BRO) has intensified operations to clear the highway as soon as possible, they said, adding that BRO pressed into service its men and machines and launched a massive clearance and repair operation to reopen the highway for traffic.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Authorities were focusing on reopening of the highway so that more rescue material could reach Kashmir by road.</span></p>]]></description>
			<dc:creator>Edited by Priyanka Kukreja || Updated: 11:50 IST</dc:creator>
			<pubDate>Sat, 13 Sep 2014 06:21:58 -0600</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.newsx.com/national/nation/item/26610-jammu-srinagar-nh-remains-closed-for-traffic</guid>
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
