<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet href="http://www.newsx.com/components/com_obrss/assets/xsl/atom-to-html.xsl" type="text/xsl"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
	<channel>
		<title>rss</title>
		<description><![CDATA[RSS Feed]]></description>
		<link>http://www.newsx.com/</link>
		<lastBuildDate>Sun, 14 Sep 2014 16:00:11 -0600</lastBuildDate>
		<generator>FeedCreator 1.8.3 (obRSS 1.9)</generator>
		<atom:link href="http://www.newsx.com/index.php?option=com_obrss&amp;task=feed&amp;id=2:rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
		<image>
			<url>http://www.newsx.com/images/</url>
			<title>rss</title>
			<link>http://www.newsx.com/</link>
			<description>RSS Feed</description>
		</image>
		<item>
			<title>Uma Bharti assures clean Ganga in 3 years</title>
			<link>http://www.newsx.com/national/nation/item/26681-uma-bharti-assures-clean-ganga-in-3-years</link>
			<description><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/da592acfb32ec0ba7951acc370c1b895_Generic.jpg"><img align="right" border="0" src="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/da592acfb32ec0ba7951acc370c1b895_S.jpg" alt="uma-bharti-assures-clean-ganga-in-3-years" /></a><font color="#ff3300"><b>Featured</b></font><p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">New Delhi: Union Minister Uma Bharti today reiterated her commitment to clean India's longest river Ganga and promised to do so in three years while also asserting that she would not entertain any questions in this regard before the task was achieved.</span></p>

<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"I am being asked many questions on the cleaning of Ganga, but I am not going to speak anything. I believe in action and I am going to make Ganga continuous and serene in the next three years.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"The questions are not going to affect me," she said at a felicitation ceremony of teachers organised by the Coordination Committee of Public Schools (CCPS) here.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Bharti, who is the Minister of Water Resources, River Development and Ganga Rejuvenation, also emphasised on the role of the teachers in students' life and credited her own success to her teachers.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">She also congratulated all the teachers who were felicitated in the programme, and asked all teachers to become 'real gurus' and students to become better human beings rather than grow professionally.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Speaking at the occasion, BJP Delhi unit president Satish Upadhayay hailed Prime Minister Narendra Modi for "giving imagination" to the country and reigniting hopes of people.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"A trust deficit was created in the country. People had lost hopes that the country would progress. But thanks to the efforts of Modiji that the lost hopes are being brought back once again. He has given imagination to the country. The nation now believes that everything is possible," Upadhayay said.</span></p>]]></description>
			<dc:creator>Edited by Kirti Dwivedi | Updated: 9:55 IST</dc:creator>
			<pubDate>Sun, 14 Sep 2014 15:45:08 -0600</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.newsx.com/national/nation/item/26681-uma-bharti-assures-clean-ganga-in-3-years</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>China set to pump billions of dollars in India, outwit Japan</title>
			<link>http://www.newsx.com/world/asia/item/26680-china-set-to-pump-billions-of-dollars-in-india-outwit-japan</link>
			<description><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/3c21076bdd843c3dc7c26e8268625d37_Generic.jpg"><img align="right" border="0" src="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/3c21076bdd843c3dc7c26e8268625d37_S.jpg" alt="china-set-to-pump-billions-of-dollars-in-india-outwit-japan" /></a><font color="#ff3300"><b>Featured</b></font><p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">BEIJING: Cash-rich China is looking to outwit rival Japan by pledging to invest billions of dollars in India's railway, manufacturing and infrastructure projects during President Xi Jinping's maiden visit to the country this week.</span></p>

<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">As Xi's visit to India scheduled for September 17 draws close, Chinese officials are becoming increasingly vocal about Beijing's decision to scale up investments in India regarded widely as the most safe investment destination, especially after Japan made a splash with commitment to invest $35 billion during Prime Minister Narendra Modi's visit to Tokyo.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">With growing outbound direct investment (ODI) which last year crossed $90 billion, China's investments in India, which so far remained a paltry $400 million, mostly in Gujarat, are now expected to surpass Japan.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">China's foreign exchange reserves, the largest in the world, reached a record $3.95 trillion in March and it plans to invest around $500 billion overseas in the next five years, a large share of which is expected to find India's way.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">China is positively considering investing in India's ambitious plan to build high-speed railways, including bullet trains.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Chinese officials say that China would be committing anywhere between $100 billion to $300 billion in the modernisation of Indian railways by replacing existing tracks to increase the speed, station development, establishing industrial parks as well as invest in mega infrastructure projects.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The improvement of tracks could push the average train speeds from 160kmph to 180kmh, Indian officials say.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">China is also asking India to hand over certain railway corridors for it to build, develop and maintain high speed railway lines.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">While Japan bagged the Mumbai-Ahmedabad first bullet train project, Chinese officials have evinced interest in Chennai and Bangalore and Bangalore-Mumbai corridors to build high-speed trains.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">India has already invited China to modernize railway stations.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">During Xi's visit, China is set to announce two industrial parks, one each in Gujarat and Maharastra to begin a host of manufacturing and energy units.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The investments are aimed at addressing India's concern of mounting trade deficit which averaged $35 billion in the total $66.4 billion trade last year.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Xi's visit will focus on economic and trade development, Hu Shisheng, a research fellow at the state-run China Institutes of Contemporary International Relations, told PTI.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Hu said Beijing looks to invest in mega infrastructure projects just like the way Japan did in the last two decades in China developing its infrastructure despite political rivalry.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"We can invest far bigger amounts than Japan and finish projects in India far cheaper and faster as we have a proven record in this record in this regard," he said adding that China could be committing far higher than Japan's $35 billion.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Hu said Chinese leadership is not ruffled by Modi's Japan visit and his close rapport with Japanese Prime Minister Shinzo Abe as they knew Modi well before he came to power and interacted with him closely when he was the Gujarat chief minister.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">He said China would be guided by Modi's assurance to attach top priority to China-India relations.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Hu said if Japan steps up investments in India, it could lead to trilateral approach to increase focus on development despite the rivalry.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">He said the border issue will not stand in the way of bilateral cooperation to be enhanced during Xi's visit.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">After 17 rounds of talks, India and China have moved forward to resolve the vexed issue, he said.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">What is left for experts and special representatives of borders talks is to find ways to demarcate the line of actual control (LAC) and exchange maps which could happen under Modi and Xi's leadership as both are regarded as strong leaders, Hu said.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">India asserts that the border dispute covered about 4,000km, while China claims that it confined to about 2,000km to the area of Arunachal Pradesh, which it refers as Southern Tibet.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"For the first time the two countries have strong leaders. It is the right time to reach a solution," Hu said.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">For the time, during Xi's visit, China is seriously considering to open a new route for Indian pilgrims to take part in Kailash and Mansarovar yatra which will be good for ties, he added.</span></p>]]></description>
			<dc:creator>Edited by Kirti Dwivedi | Updated: 9:55 IST</dc:creator>
			<pubDate>Sun, 14 Sep 2014 15:30:34 -0600</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.newsx.com/world/asia/item/26680-china-set-to-pump-billions-of-dollars-in-india-outwit-japan</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Don't celebrate my birthday, instead help in J&amp;K relief work, says PM Modi</title>
			<link>http://www.newsx.com/national/nation/item/26679-dont-celebrate-my-birthday-instead-help-in-jk-relief-work-says-pm-modi</link>
			<description><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/de97c40275cb369ae9dd9d39f59c45da_Generic.jpg"><img align="right" border="0" src="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/de97c40275cb369ae9dd9d39f59c45da_S.jpg" alt="dont-celebrate-my-birthday-instead-help-in-jk-relief-work-says-pm-modi" /></a><font color="#ff3300"><b>Featured</b></font><p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">New Delhi: Prime Minister Narendra Modi on Sunday appealed to friends and well-wishers not to celebrate his birthday and instead dedicate time and resources towards relief work in this hour of need for flood-ravaged Jammu and Kashmir.</span></p>

<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Modi's appeal came amid plans to celebrate his birthday on September 17 across the country, including in Gujarat where he will be present that day. "I am hearing from different places that friends &amp; well-wishers are planning various programmes and events for my birthday. My humble request - do not celebrate my birthday.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"Instead, dedicate yourselves towards relief work in Jammu and Kashmir through your time and resources. The need of the hour is to stand shoulder to shoulder with our sisters and brothers of Jammu and Kashmir," Modi said ahead of his 64th birthday.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Modi, who will be in Gujarat on September 17, will start his day by taking blessings of his 95-year-old mother Hiraba following which celebrations by state administration and BJP have been planned to mark his birthday.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">But the Prime Minister said "there will be no birthday celebrations". "On 17th, President Xi Jinping will be in Gujarat. We look forward to extending a warm welcome to him but there will be no birthday celebrations," Modi said.</span></p>]]></description>
			<dc:creator>Edited by Kirti Dwivedi | Updated: 8:45 IST</dc:creator>
			<pubDate>Sun, 14 Sep 2014 15:23:40 -0600</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.newsx.com/national/nation/item/26679-dont-celebrate-my-birthday-instead-help-in-jk-relief-work-says-pm-modi</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>TCS opens Saudi Arabia's first all-female BPO centre</title>
			<link>http://www.newsx.com/national/business/item/26678-tcs-opens-saudi-arabias-first-all-female-bpo-centre</link>
			<description><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/518550ea3d6d7359b998496247dac6c1_Generic.jpg"><img align="right" border="0" src="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/518550ea3d6d7359b998496247dac6c1_S.jpg" alt="tcs-opens-saudi-arabias-first-all-female-bpo-centre" /></a><font color="#ff3300"><b>Featured</b></font><p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Mumbai: India's largest software exporter TCS on Sunday said that it has opened Saudi Arabia's first all-female business process centre, which will provide employment to up to 3,000 women in three years.</span></p>

<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Saudi Aramco and GE are the centre's first customers, TCS said in a statement. Both the clients have already surpassed their target of recruiting 100 women each, while the total number of those employed at the centre stands at 300, it said.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The Riyadh-based 3,200-sq mt facility will offer customers specialised finance and accounting, human resources, materials supply and office services to improve their operational efficiency, it said.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The centre was announced in September last year. Saudi Arabia's Commerce and Industry Minister Tawfiq bin Fawzan Al Rabiah, Deputy Governor of Saudi Arabian General Investment Authority Prince Saud bin Khalid, Saudi Aramco's President and Chief Executive Khalid Al Falih and GE's Vice Chairman John Rice, were present on the occasion, the statement said.</span></p>]]></description>
			<dc:creator>Edited by Kirti Dwivedi | Updated: 8:25 IST</dc:creator>
			<pubDate>Sun, 14 Sep 2014 14:58:24 -0600</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.newsx.com/national/business/item/26678-tcs-opens-saudi-arabias-first-all-female-bpo-centre</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Red carpet welcome awaits PM Narendra Modi in US</title>
			<link>http://www.newsx.com/national/nation/item/26677-red-carpet-welcome-awaits-pm-narendra-modi-in-us</link>
			<description><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/24fab757bae3aa233b2d9bf5b25f2a87_Generic.jpg"><img align="right" border="0" src="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/24fab757bae3aa233b2d9bf5b25f2a87_S.jpg" alt="red-carpet-welcome-awaits-pm-narendra-modi-in-us" /></a><font color="#ff3300"><b>Featured</b></font><p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Washington: The Obama Administration is leaving no stone unturned to woo Prime Minister Narendra Modi during his maiden visit to the US which is expected to take the strategic bilateral relationship to the next level and unleash the potential of economic and trade ties.</span></p>

<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The administration here is gearing up to give a red carpet welcome to Prime Minister Modi when he arrives in Washington on September 29 from New York where he would attend the annual General Assembly session of the United Nations.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The discussion between Modi and Obama over two days in Washington is expected to result in taking the bilateral relationship to the next level in terms of defense and strategic ties, co-operation in the field of space and counter-terrorism and unleash the potential of economic and trade ties, sources familiar with the preparations said. On September 29, Obama is likely to host Modi for a small working dinner, which is rarely accorded to a visiting foreign leader.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The maiden meeting between the two leaders on September 29 would help Obama and Modi to know each other and prepare the ground for the next day's meeting at the White House. Soon after his electoral victory, Obama had called Modi to congratulate him and invited him to visit Washington.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Thereafter the two leaders have not spoken over phone, but there has been an exchange of letters between the two. Obama, who of late has been tied up on the foreign policy front over developments in the Middle East -- Syria, Iraq, Iran, Israel-Palestine and Ukraine -- is looking forward to meeting Modi and exchange views on international issues of concern.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Encouraged by the steps taken by the Modi government in its first 100 days, the Obama Administration sees an India that is of great strategic significance and can act as a stabilising force in the entire Asia Pacific region.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">A strong and prosperous India, US officials argue, is in the best interest of the United States. India, US officials say, under Modi would play a key role not only in South Asia, but also in South East Asia.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">In fact, India-US relationship has been identified as one of the top four priorities by both Obama and Secretary of State John Kerry this year, officials said. Kerry and Defense Secretary Chuck Hagel met Modi in New Delhi in quick succession this summer. The meetings generated excitement in the US as well.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"The two leaders will discuss a range of issues of mutual interest in order to expand and deepen the US-India strategic partnership. They will discuss ways to accelerate economic growth, bolster security cooperation, and collaborate in activities that bring long-term benefits to both countries and the world," the White House had said in a statement earlier while formally announcing the visit.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"They will also focus on regional issues, including current developments in Afghanistan, Syria and Iraq, where India and the United States can work together with partners towards a positive outcome," the White House had said adding that Obama looks forward to working with Modi to fulfill the promise of the US-India strategic partnership for the benefit of both their citizens and the world.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">After a dinner on September 29, the two leaders are scheduled to meet at the White House for a substantive talk on September 30. "The fact that there will be interactions over two days is a signal of the importance we place on the US-India relationship," said Caitlin Hayden, Spokesperson of the National Security Council.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">While Modi's Joint Address to the US Congress could not happen due to the November elections, a large number of lawmakers are believed to have requested a meeting with the Prime Minister.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Organisers of Modi's trip are having a tough time in scheduling these meetings.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Modi has also received a request for meetings from the top American business community both in New York and Washington DC.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">With economic development his key priority, Modi is expected to interact with the American business community in both New York and Washington DC. The visit will mark Modi's first trip to the US since his party swept to victory in general elections in May. In 2005, the US State Department had revoked a visa that Modi had for travelling to the US in the wake of the 2002 riots in Gujarat. He never applied for an American visa after the move.</span></p>]]></description>
			<dc:creator>Edited by Kirti Dwivedi | Updated: 8:45 IST</dc:creator>
			<pubDate>Sun, 14 Sep 2014 14:48:16 -0600</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.newsx.com/national/nation/item/26677-red-carpet-welcome-awaits-pm-narendra-modi-in-us</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>IAF choppers 'only hope' of survival for people in J&amp;K mountains</title>
			<link>http://www.newsx.com/national/nation/item/26676-iaf-choppers-only-hope-of-survival-for-people-in-jk-mountains</link>
			<description><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/103e89e3e6df9058c7fecfcfdd981634_Generic.jpg"><img align="right" border="0" src="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/103e89e3e6df9058c7fecfcfdd981634_S.jpg" alt="iaf-choppers-only-hope-of-survival-for-people-in-jk-mountains" /></a><font color="#ff3300"><b>Featured</b></font><p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Sungari: "Our house is gone, household goods have perished and all our animals killed. We did not have anything to eat," said Chamail Singh of Rajouri district while showering praise on Indian Air Force for air-dropping food items and other relief material.</span></p>

<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Singh, a resident of Sungari hamlet which has been ravaged by flash floods and landslides triggered by heavy rains, said, ""IAF choppers have become the only lifeline for us. They brought food and other relief material for us."</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Like Singh, other people in the hamlet, which was totally cut off after the flash floods and landslides, were being supplied food by a small Army group for the past few days, before the IAF chopper delivered rations and ready-to-eat food packets to them.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Similar sentiments were echoed by the residents of Chasana belt of Reasi district too. "Twice they (IAF choppers) brought relief material after landslides badly destroyed our houses," Anwar Din of flood-hit Chasana said.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Five people have died in Chasana belt of the district in landslides triggered by flash floods last week when the entire area, housing over 2,000 families, was cut off from the rest.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Battered and uprooted by floods and landslides triggered by heavy rains, for thousands of mountain dwellers in the Jammu region IAF rescue helicopters are the "only hope" of their survival.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">As the helicopters fly over the mountain hamlets and remote areas with relief material, they offered the best hope of relief to the stranded people many of whom had been stuck without food and shelter for the past few days.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Choppers of the Jammu IAF station, popularly known as condors, have been carrying out rescue and relief operations in 41 mountainous and remote belts of Poonch, Rajouri, Reasi, Udhampur, Ramban, Kishtwar, Doda, Jammu and Samba districts in Jammu region for the past 10 days.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The IAF choppers are engaged in distributing food items in flood-ravaged areas and evacuating stranded people.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Panch Kartar Singh of Udhampur termed the IAF choppers as the "messiah" to the people living in his Saddal village, which has been wiped out in flood and landslides on September 7, when 41 people were killed.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"They carried Army unit, NDRF and Police for operation to trace bodies and also supplied relief material to over 100 people, most of them survivals of Saddal landslide," Kartar said, adding that they also carried some to hospital.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Most of them were angry with the state government for its failure to reach out to the people in distress and patted the efforts of the IAF and Army, who reached to them with help, food and relief.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Air Officer Commanding (AoC), Air Commodore P E Patange of Jammu IAF Station told PTI that the entire fleet of choppers, Airmen and officers have been engaged in rescue and relief operation.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"We have carried out rescue and relief operations in 45 areas in Jammu division braving weathers conditions, rains and difficult terrains," he said, adding that some of the most difficult areas included Chasana, Nawapanchi, Poonch, Rajouri and other belts.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">IAF Station Jammu carried out 269 sorties of aircraft and helicopters and airlifted 8,623 people, besides carrying 427 tonnes of relief material during the period, Air Commodore Patange said.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"First, we ferried food and medicines to the affected areas and then blankets and tents for sheltering the people," he said. "The moral of our personnel is very high though we are on the 10th day of the operation," he said.</span></p>]]></description>
			<dc:creator>Edited by Kirti Dwivedi | Updated: 7:35 IST</dc:creator>
			<pubDate>Sun, 14 Sep 2014 14:31:53 -0600</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.newsx.com/national/nation/item/26676-iaf-choppers-only-hope-of-survival-for-people-in-jk-mountains</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>AI plane buy: Patel shouldn't shy away from probe, Subramanian Swamy says</title>
			<link>http://www.newsx.com/national/nation/item/26675-ai-plane-buy-patel-shouldnt-shy-away-from-probe-subramanian-swamy-says</link>
			<description><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/d9ed5fa3de1480ead21828b261d2e96b_Generic.jpg"><img align="right" border="0" src="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/d9ed5fa3de1480ead21828b261d2e96b_S.jpg" alt="ai-plane-buy-patel-shouldnt-shy-away-from-probe-subramanian-swamy-says" /></a><font color="#ff3300"><b>Featured</b></font><p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">New Delhi: Former civil aviation minister Praful Patel should have no hesitation in facing an inquiry over the large-scale purchase of aircraft by Air India if his conscience is clear in the matter, BJP's Subramanian Swamy said on Sunday in light of claims in that regard by ex-CAG Vinod Rai.</span></p>

<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"There is no doubt about Rai's sincerity. I would say he (Patel) is defending himself by saying he had not taken the decision alone... So, he should not hesitate from an inquiry," Swamy said.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Rai has claimed he was under pressure to drop the name of Patel from the auditor's report on the purchase of aircraft for the public carrier. Rai had stated that Patel had nudged Air India to go in for large-scale purchase of aircraft.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The former CAG claimed that all hell broke loose when the draft CAG report reached the ministry and bureaucrats tried to prompt him to drop the word "nudge".</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Refuting the charge, Patel had said, "Air India Board took the decision and it was the Empowered Group of Ministers headed by P Chidambaram which decided on the number of aircraft (to be purchased) and this was approved by the Union Cabinet."</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Meanwhile, on another CAG report, which has accused political leaders of misusing public money for excursions, Swamy said, "More than the loss of money... It is absolutely wrong and immoral. We have to set an example for the rest of society that we are the trustees of the funds. We should minimise expenditure."</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">He was speaking on the sidelines of a day-long conference on 'Action Plan for National Renaissance' here.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">On reports of stone-pelting at armed forces in flood-hit Jammu and Kashmir, Swamy said, "I have been saying it from the beginning that Kashmir should be kept under President's Rule for a year and then elections should be conducted there. The debate over Art. 370 can be taken forward and I would say it should be abolished."</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Asked about reports of rift between Shiv Sena and BJP in Maharashtra over seat-sharing and the chief ministerial candidate, Swamy said, "There are minor differences in a family; It's not a big issue."</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">On reported incursions by Chinese in Ladakh, Swamy said, "We will have to check it. There has been no incident for the past 5-6 years. But in Aksai Chin, we have heard that their people cross over and stay on our territory for a short while. If those people come and settle in our region then it's a grave matter. But if they are not settling and just cross over by mistake, then it is not an issue."</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The BJP leader also said that some former MPs who have not vacated their official residences till now must do so at the earliest.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"It's been over four months since the NDA government came to power. Usually the municipal authorities give a month to vacate. And it doesn't befit former MPs to continue (occupying the residence) after they are served a notice to leave the accommodation," he said.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Asking the youth to come forward and join public life, Swamy said, "We need a very large infusion of educated youngsters in politics. We want educated people to stand on their feet. What are the qualities in educated people to participate in politics? Manmohan Singh is a very highly educated person, but he is spineless. We need a 'viraat hindustani'."</span></p>]]></description>
			<dc:creator>Edited by Kirti Dwivedi | Updated: 6:55 IST</dc:creator>
			<pubDate>Sun, 14 Sep 2014 14:17:12 -0600</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.newsx.com/national/nation/item/26675-ai-plane-buy-patel-shouldnt-shy-away-from-probe-subramanian-swamy-says</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Maharashtra polls: 'BJP workers don't want seat-sharing talks with Sena'</title>
			<link>http://www.newsx.com/regional/maharashtra/item/26674-maharashtra-polls-bjp-workers-dont-want-seat-sharing-talks-with-sena</link>
			<description><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/479fe68f42ab9d5fbb36477dbb34da1f_Generic.jpg"><img align="right" border="0" src="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/479fe68f42ab9d5fbb36477dbb34da1f_S.jpg" alt="maharashtra-polls-bjp-workers-dont-want-seat-sharing-talks-with-sena" /></a><font color="#ff3300"><b>Featured</b></font><p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Mumbai: Angry over Shiv Sena chief Uddhav Thackeray's comments to allegedly "demean" Prime Minister Narendra Modi, the Maharashtra BJP unit on Sunday said its workers do not want any further seat-sharing talks between the two alliance partners for the next month's Assembly polls.</span></p>

<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"The comments made by him (Uddhav Thackeray) were to demean Narendra Modi. Maharashtra BJP has strongly criticised and condemned the comments made by him. Our workers are insisting and pressurising the leadership to stop the talks between the two parties and find our own way now," BJP state unit spokesperson Madhav Bhandari told reporters here.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Uddhav had in a TV interview yesterday said the Modi wave had failed to show up in several states and that the BJP's victory in the recent Lok Sabha polls should be attributed not only to Modi, but its alliance partners as well.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">In the Lok Sabha polls, Uddhav said, people voted for a 'face' (Modi) for a change and Shiv Sena's contribution in the victory in Maharashtra cannot be ignored.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"Did the Modi wave show in Tamil Nadu, Punjab, Orissa and West Bengal? It depends on alliance partners as well. Modi is Prime Minister of our alliance," he had said.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Bhandari alleged that this was not the first time the Sena chief had made "derogatory" comments about Prime Minister Modi and remarked that it is the grassroot workers who make the leadership take final decisions.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"The workers want all talks to end...And leadership finally listens to its grassroot workers because it is they who do all the ground work.. All our leaders have evolved from workers," he said.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Bhandari expressed confidence that the next government in the state will be formed under the BJP's leadership.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"The next government in Maharashtra post elections will be formed under the leadership of the BJP. Our national president (Amit Shah) had made this very clear while on his trip to Mumbai. And his decision is final," he said.</span></p>]]></description>
			<dc:creator>Edited by Kirti Dwivedi | Updated: 6:35 IST</dc:creator>
			<pubDate>Sun, 14 Sep 2014 14:11:47 -0600</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.newsx.com/regional/maharashtra/item/26674-maharashtra-polls-bjp-workers-dont-want-seat-sharing-talks-with-sena</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>J&amp;K: Harsh Vardhan reviews floods situation, assures all-out healthcare assistance</title>
			<link>http://www.newsx.com/regional/j-k/item/26673-jk-harsh-vardhan-reviews-floods-situation-assures-all-out-healthcare-assistance</link>
			<description><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/2090e095f676cce70be0b3e6541553e5_Generic.jpg"><img align="right" border="0" src="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/2090e095f676cce70be0b3e6541553e5_S.jpg" alt="jk-harsh-vardhan-reviews-floods-situation-assures-all-out-healthcare-assistance" /></a><font color="#ff3300"><b>Featured</b></font><p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Srinagar: Union Health Minister Harsh Vardhan on Sunday reviewed the situation in flood-hit Jammu and Kashmir and affirmed that all assistance would be provided to the state health authorities to tackle any possible epidemic in the aftermath of the devastating floods.</span></p>

<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Vardhan visited the Valley today and met Chief Minister Omar Abdullah and senior officers at Hari Niwas to review the ongoing relief operations in the state, an official spokesman said.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Before leaving for the flood-battered state, the Union Minister tweeted, "Leaving for Srinagar. Worried with medical shortage reports. Will meet all authorities there to find answer to logistical problems &amp; issues."</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">And followed it up with: " Thanks to wide social media support, Health Min, Army+Para mil lots of relief reaching Kashmir. Going to Srinagar. Need last mile solutions."</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">After taking a detailed review of the health related relief measures Vardhan also took stock of essential medicines and other health care facilities provided.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The Chief Minister sought central assistance to restore the health infrastructure affected due to floods and also to carry out an extensive measles vaccination programme for vulnerable age group of 0 to 15 years.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">He also informed that almost 50 lakh chlorine tablets have been received in the state and mobile purification plants are being used to provide safe drinking water to the people.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The authorities have been directed to press into service more pumps for dewatering and taking appropriate preventive? measures to check any epidemic outbreak, Omar said.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Vardhan was also apprised that supplies of emergency medicines have been dispatched to various district hospitals.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The Health Minister assured the state of all possible assistance and asked authorities to press medical teams to various affected areas so that much needed health care facilities is provided to the public.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">He said it is important to inform the people about the water purification methods and other vaccinations to check diseases.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">It was also informed in the meeting that general public should be sensitized that about one to two tablets of chlorine can purify about 20 litres of water.</span></p>]]></description>
			<dc:creator>Edited by Kirti Dwivedi | Updated: 6:15 IST</dc:creator>
			<pubDate>Sun, 14 Sep 2014 13:09:31 -0600</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.newsx.com/regional/j-k/item/26673-jk-harsh-vardhan-reviews-floods-situation-assures-all-out-healthcare-assistance</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>India will oust China as top cotton producer this year, USDA says</title>
			<link>http://www.newsx.com/national/business/item/26672-india-will-oust-china-as-top-cotton-producer-this-year-usda-says</link>
			<description><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/0c45bbf3054d5ab7f429d7edcff5ccdd_Generic.jpg"><img align="right" border="0" src="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/0c45bbf3054d5ab7f429d7edcff5ccdd_S.jpg" alt="india-will-oust-china-as-top-cotton-producer-this-year-usda-says" /></a><font color="#ff3300"><b>Featured</b></font><p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Beijing/Washington: India is all set to beat China and become the top cotton producer this year, ousting the communist nation from the number 1 position for the first time in over 30 years, the US has said in a report.</span></p>

<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The US Department of Agriculture (USDA) data suggest that India will produce 30 million bales of cotton in the season starting August 1 while China will produce 29.5 million bales. The USDA increased its prediction of Indian production from 29 million bales last month, while China's remained unchanged.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The reduction is largely due to the fewer incentives farmers are getting for planting cotton in China's eastern provinces, the report said. Total area in China is projected to decline 11 per cent to 4.35 million hectares, with a record yield forecast at 1,477 kg per hectare.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">While for India, the late monsoon will likely benefit cotton; some area originally expected to be devoted to alternative crops-with an earlier planting window-is now projected to move to cotton.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Meanwhile in Beijing, China's Ministry of Agriculture has admitted to the decline in the country's cotton output. The relatively low profitability of cotton on the government's decision to abolish its "temporary purchasing policy" to prop up prices, said Pan Xiufen, a senior agronomist at MoA.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Pan expected the growing area of cotton in China to continue its declining trend in the next few years, state-run Xinhua News Agency reported. China will remain a big consumer of cotton due to its large population, growing incomes and increasing export demand, the MoA said, adding that the shrinking growing area would result in a big supply gap in the cotton market.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Observers say that this could create big demand for India to step up its cotton and yarn to China which already amounted to few billion US dollar. The MoA report said the cotton growing area in the Yangtze River Basin and the Yellow River Basin went down by about 12.1 per cent and 14.5 per cent, respectively.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Hebei and Jiangsu provinces, two of the country's major cotton regions, saw their growing areas decline at 16.4 per cent and 20 per cent respectively, the MoA officials said. In Jiangxi Province, another important cotton growing region, cotton cultivation areas has fallen by at least 10 per cent, and some major cotton growers have cut their planting areas by nearly half.</span></p>]]></description>
			<dc:creator>Edited by Kirti Dwivedi | Updated: 5:15 IST</dc:creator>
			<pubDate>Sun, 14 Sep 2014 12:43:20 -0600</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.newsx.com/national/business/item/26672-india-will-oust-china-as-top-cotton-producer-this-year-usda-says</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Delhi court raps DTC for penalising conductors</title>
			<link>http://www.newsx.com/national/nation/item/26671-delhi-court-raps-dtc-for-penalising-conductors</link>
			<description><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/500254cc6b50cd37f693c5e9a2b12ede_Generic.jpg"><img align="right" border="0" src="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/500254cc6b50cd37f693c5e9a2b12ede_S.jpg" alt="delhi-court-raps-dtc-for-penalising-conductors" /></a><font color="#ff3300"><b>Featured</b></font><p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Edited by Kirti Dwivedi | Updated: Sep 13 9:35 IST</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">New Delhi: A city court has struck down Delhi Transport Corporation (DTC)'s order of imposing fine on its conductors in an event of ticket-less travellers being found in its buses.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The court also noted that the DTC's decision to "discipline its conductors" was taken in a meeting which lacked quorum and termed it as "illegal, unreasonable and non-est" in the eyes of the law.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The DTC had in December last year introduced the rule increasing the penalty for the conductors to Rs 75 per ticket-less passenger from earlier Rs 10, stating that it will keep its errant employees in discipline and generate revenue.</span></p>

<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Rapping DTC for its decision, Civil Judge Kishore Kumar said, "The stand taken by the defendants (DTC) that to generate finance from the erring conductors by way of increment of penalty to Rs 75 is something unusual to the service conditions and also unusual to the Labour Laws." Although the Tis Hazari civil court's order came on August 2 last month, the DTC is still prosecuting conductors with a fine of Rs 75, alleged DTC Employees Congress, an umbrella body of corporation employees.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">In its order, court also said, "Such order are illegal, unreasonable and non-est in the eyes of law and hereby declared as null and void. "The defendants (DTC) are permanently restrained from acting on these office orders."</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The court also added that "The DTC's counsel had no answer as to where it is provided in the rules/regulations or in the law that out of seven directors if, only five or for that matter four were available, they made a corum and were competent to bring in changes or amendments in the penalties for regulating the conduct of the employees."</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The DTC's employee association alleged that DTC has been violating the court's order. "DTC has been imposing penalty on conductors, which is in clear violation of court's order. We have in possession several show cause notices with regard to deducting such amount from conductors' salaries.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"If a conductor is fined five times a month, how can he run his family," DTC Employees Congress president Ramesh Vats said. DTC's CMD Debashree Mukherjee and spokesperson RS Minhas did not respond to queries on the matter despite several attempts.</span></p>]]></description>
			<dc:creator>Edited by Kirti Dwivedi | Updated:5:35 IST	</dc:creator>
			<pubDate>Sun, 14 Sep 2014 12:30:44 -0600</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.newsx.com/national/nation/item/26671-delhi-court-raps-dtc-for-penalising-conductors</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Tamil Nadu: Jaya charges BJP with double standards on fishermen issue</title>
			<link>http://www.newsx.com/regional/tamil-nadu/item/26670-tamil-nadu-jaya-charges-bjp-with-double-standards-on-fishermen-issue</link>
			<description><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/4a7c534bd7fec6e86930887ef14f3cb3_Generic.jpg"><img align="right" border="0" src="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/4a7c534bd7fec6e86930887ef14f3cb3_S.jpg" alt="tamil-nadu-jaya-charges-bjp-with-double-standards-on-fishermen-issue" /></a><font color="#ff3300"><b>Featured</b></font><p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Tuticorin: Charging BJP with adopting 'double-standards' on the fishermen issue, AIADMK supremo and Tamil Nadu Chief Minister Jayalalithaa on Sunday said that voting for the national party will not benefit the people of her state.</span></p>

<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Campaigning for her party's Tuticorin Mayor candidate for the September 18 bypolls, Jayalalithaa said besides her party, a 'national party' (BJP) and some independents alone were in the fray.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">She said that voting for the national party in the civic polls will be of no use since they have different leadership at the Central and state levels. So are the stands on issues, she said, campaigning for AIADMK candidate APR Anthony Gracy.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Tuticorin has a large fishermen population, Jayalalithaa said while raising the issue of repeated arrests and attacks on fishermen from the state by Sri Lankan navy pointing out that she has been pressing Prime Minister Narendra Modi for ensuring a lasting solution on the matter.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Arrested fishermen were being released after she takes up the matter with Modi through letters even as she had raised the issue in person with him, the Chief Minister said.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"What is the stand of the state unit of the BJP? The BJP (members) in Tamil Nadu are saying that there should be a permanent solution to the matter. But another leader of the same party is going against the Tamil Nadu fishermen," she said in an apparent reference to Subramanian Swamy.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Swamy had recently earned the ire of fishermen and political parties in the state following his reported remarks that he had advised Sri Lanka against the release of boats of Indian fishermen even if they were set free. Jayalalithaa had also taken exception to this with Modi, hoping it was not the stand of Centre or BJP.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Referring to the remarks made by Swamy on the issue of release of boats, she said his party's state unit had not even 'condemned' it while "Centre was keeping mum." "Voting for such a party with double standards will not be of any use for the people of Tamil Nadu. Therefore, by voting for BJP you will not get any benefit," Jayalalithaa said.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">AIADMK was the only party committed to welfare of the poor, voicing its concerns on matters like fishermen issue, inter-state water disputes and inflation, she said, recalling her government had approached Supreme Court on many issues. Her government was implementing various price-mitigation schemes against the backdrop of Centre's 'wrong economic policies,' including low-cost 'Amma Canteens', among others.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Load shedding had been done away with since June 1 and out of the 105 days since then, 96 days were free of any power cuts, she said.</span></p>]]></description>
			<dc:creator>Edited by Kirti Dwivedi | Updated: 4:55 IST</dc:creator>
			<pubDate>Sun, 14 Sep 2014 11:49:46 -0600</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.newsx.com/regional/tamil-nadu/item/26670-tamil-nadu-jaya-charges-bjp-with-double-standards-on-fishermen-issue</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Pilot turns Malaysia Airlines flight to India around after auto-pilot defect</title>
			<link>http://www.newsx.com/world/asia/item/26669-pilot-turns-malaysia-airlines-flight-to-india-around-after-auto-pilot-defect</link>
			<description><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/216737e26b0b494845a10be88067e2f0_Generic.jpg"><img align="right" border="0" src="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/216737e26b0b494845a10be88067e2f0_S.jpg" alt="pilot-turns-malaysia-airlines-flight-to-india-around-after-auto-pilot-defect" /></a><font color="#ff3300"><b>Featured</b></font><p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">KUALA LUMPUR: An India-bound flight of Malaysia Airlines was forced to return due to an auto-pilot defect, landing safely in Kuala Lumpur, said the carrier already hit by the twin tragedies this year.</span></p>

<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Flight MH198 from Kuala Lumpur to Hyderabad departed at 10.20pm on Saturday night but the Boeing 737-800 turned back due to an auto-pilot defect and landed safely at the Kuala Lumpur International Airport at 2.01am on Sunday, it said in a statement.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"The defect did not have any impact on the safety of the aircraft or passengers, however, as a precautionary measure, the operating captain decided to turn back," the airline said.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">It refuted reports on social media that the aircraft caught fire. Initial reports had said that the plane had to make an emergency landing due to "burning fuel".</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The airline said that upon arrival, passengers and crew disembarked safely and were given accommodation at nearby hotels.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The flight has been rescheduled to operate as MH198D and will depart Kuala Lumpur at 12pm on Sunday.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The airline said it regretted the disruption to its guests' travel plans but reiterated that safety of its passengers was its priority.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Malaysia Airlines Flight MH370 with 239 people aboard lost contact on March 8. No trace of any wreckage has been found so far.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Another flight MH17 was shot down by a missile over eastern Ukraine on July 17, killing all 289 people aboard.</span></p>]]></description>
			<dc:creator>Edited by Kirti Dwivedi | Updated: 4:55 IST</dc:creator>
			<pubDate>Sun, 14 Sep 2014 11:25:08 -0600</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.newsx.com/world/asia/item/26669-pilot-turns-malaysia-airlines-flight-to-india-around-after-auto-pilot-defect</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Madrassas 'teaching terrorism', BJP MP Sakshi Maharaj from Unnao says</title>
			<link>http://www.newsx.com/national/top-stories/item/26668-madrassas-teaching-terrorism-bjp-mp-sakshi-maharaj-from-unnao-says</link>
			<description><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/15e63659f010d457b9f4435bca641171_Generic.jpg"><img align="right" border="0" src="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/15e63659f010d457b9f4435bca641171_S.jpg" alt="madrassas-teaching-terrorism-bjp-mp-sakshi-maharaj-from-unnao-says" /></a><font color="#ff3300"><b>Featured</b></font><p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">LUCKNOW: BJP MP Sakshi Maharaj on Sunday alleged that madrassas were giving "education of terrorism".</span></p>

<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"Education of terrorism is being given in madrassas. They (madrassas)... are making them terrorists and jihadis....It is not in national interest," the MP from Unnao constituency told reporters in Nademau in Kannauj district, 120 km from here.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">He alleged that students were not being taught about nationalism in the religious schools.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"Tell me about one madrassa where tricolour is hoisted even on August 15 and January 26," he said.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The Unnao MP said madrassas "which have no connection with nationalism" are being given government aid.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"Most of our schools do not take the aid but it is being given to madrassas having no connection with nationalism," he said.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Recently another BJP MP Yogi Adityanath was pulled up by the Election Commission for hate speech during campaigning for UP bypolls.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Yogi Adityanath courted controversy in Noida when he equated the rise in communal violence in western UP with the increasing population of a particular community.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The Samajwadi Party denounced Sakshi's "hate speech", saying it was an attempt to create division among communities.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"Sakshi has given a hate speech which is aimed towards creating differences in the society," SP spokesman Rajendra Chaurdhary said.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Earlier, during a programme in Etah on September 7, Sakshi had reportedly labelled madrassas as "hub of terror" and alleged that 'love jihad' prospers through such institutions.</span></p>]]></description>
			<dc:creator>Edited by Kirti Dwivedi | Updated: 4:35 IST</dc:creator>
			<pubDate>Sun, 14 Sep 2014 11:06:01 -0600</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.newsx.com/national/top-stories/item/26668-madrassas-teaching-terrorism-bjp-mp-sakshi-maharaj-from-unnao-says</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Indo-China border dispute solution: China prefers status quo, says book</title>
			<link>http://www.newsx.com/national/nation/item/26667-indo-china-border-dispute-solution-china-prefers-status-quo-says-book</link>
			<description><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/ffb8d090e42fdf09c5069124e6ec0051_Generic.jpg"><img align="right" border="0" src="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/ffb8d090e42fdf09c5069124e6ec0051_S.jpg" alt="indo-china-border-dispute-solution-china-prefers-status-quo-says-book" /></a><font color="#ff3300"><b>Featured</b></font><p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">New Delhi: There are few signs that China is willing to settle the boundary issue unless India completely subscribes to its world view and agrees to remain within its 'red lines' which is unlikely to happen, says a new book.</span></p>

<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The boundary dispute is utilised by China for trying to coerce foreign policy changes by India that often have nothing to do with the dispute itself, the book, 'India-China Boundary Issues: Quest for Settlement' by former diplomat Ranjit Singh Kalha says.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Kalha, a former Secretary in the Ministry of External Affairs Ministry, had led India's negotiating team in the Boundary Sub-Group from 1985 to 1988.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">China has used the threat of intrusions across the LAC- as part of coercive diplomacy- in order to influence decisions in a way most desirable for it. And that is also the principal reason why China does not desire an early conclusion, the book, published by Pentagon Press, says.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Solution of the Sino-Indian border question is not a mere technical matter but rather a political and a strategic issue whose ramifications go well beyond the bilateral field. If the Sino-Indian boundary question was merely a technical matter, it would have been resolved a long time ago, the author says.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Policy changes take place after assessing whether such a change, subtle or otherwise, would lead to greater advantage or it would end in a disadvantage. No policy decisions are taken in isolation or are taken in vacuum.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"In other words, a boundary settlement is only possible if India were to remain within the 'red-lines' drawn by China, the book says.</span></p>]]></description>
			<dc:creator>Edited by Kirti Dwivedi | Updated: 4:15 IST</dc:creator>
			<pubDate>Sun, 14 Sep 2014 10:59:57 -0600</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.newsx.com/national/nation/item/26667-indo-china-border-dispute-solution-china-prefers-status-quo-says-book</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>BJP leader CP Thakur defends Nitish in medicine scam</title>
			<link>http://www.newsx.com/national/nation/item/26666-bjp-leader-cp-thakur-defends-nitish-in-medicine-scam</link>
			<description><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/833e446889cb1e3d5647d15ea2bdcb08_Generic.jpg"><img align="right" border="0" src="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/833e446889cb1e3d5647d15ea2bdcb08_S.jpg" alt="bjp-leader-cp-thakur-defends-nitish-in-medicine-scam" /></a><font color="#ff3300"><b>Featured</b></font><p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Patna: Defying party line, senior BJP leader CP Thakur on Sunday defended former chief minister Nitish Kumar in the medicine scam saying that it was unfair to cast aspersions on the integrity and honesty of the JD(U) leader.</span></p>

<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"I have known Nitish Kumar for decades....He is an upright person known for honesty and integrity in public life," Thakur told reporters here.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">When told that his own party leaders, led by former Deputy Chief Minister Sushil Kumar Modi, have questioned Kumar's role in the multi-crore medicine scam, Thakur said that as far as he was concerned Nitish Kumar was honest to the core and it would be unfair to cast aspersion on him in the scam.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Regretting the ongoing 'letter war' between the former chief minister and his erstwhile deputy over the scam as a "sad development", the senior BJP leader, who was health minister in the Atal Bihari Vajpayee government, said that it must stop at once and the investigating agencies be allowed to probe the matter to bring the culprits to book.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Thakur's remarks defending the former chief minister have assumed significance as Modi has been leading campaign against Nitish Kumar, charging him with presiding over the medicine purchase scam at the time he held the health department after sacking the BJP ministers, a charge that the former chief minister has flatly denied.</span></p>]]></description>
			<dc:creator>Edited by Kirti Dwivedi | Updated: 3:55 IST</dc:creator>
			<pubDate>Sun, 14 Sep 2014 10:16:33 -0600</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.newsx.com/national/nation/item/26666-bjp-leader-cp-thakur-defends-nitish-in-medicine-scam</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Afghanistan's megaflag symbolises 'Hind-Afghan Dosti'</title>
			<link>http://www.newsx.com/world/middle-east/item/26665-afghanistans-megaflag-symbolises-hind-afghan-dosti</link>
			<description><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/0101e2850ea9aba94ff682fc47bd8c46_Generic.jpg"><img align="right" border="0" src="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/0101e2850ea9aba94ff682fc47bd8c46_S.jpg" alt="afghanistans-megaflag-symbolises-hind-afghan-dosti" /></a><font color="#ff3300"><b>Featured</b></font><p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Kabul: Afghanistan has boldly raised its black, red and green megaflag - big enough to drape over a dinosaur - in the heart of the capital here with India's help, a monument that symbolises 'Hind-Afghan Dosti'.</span></p>

<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The 97 by 65 feet flag taller than the Statue of Liberty replica in Las Vegas - was personally presented by External Affairs Minister Sushma Swaraj to Afghan President Hamid Karzai last week during her maiden visit to the country.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The flag was hoisted over Kabul's historic Wazir Akbar Khan hill, next to the empty Communist-era swimming pool once used by the Taliban regime for executions. The monument is being called the Menara Bayraq, or Flag Minaret.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Speaking at the inaugural flag hoisting ceremony, Swaraj said India saw the monument as "a powerful symbol of a unified and independent Afghanistan."</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">She praised the countless Afghan citizens, Mujahideen and soldiers who made the supreme sacrifice to build this country.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The minister also pledged USD 1 million to the Afghan government for development of Wazir Akbar Khan Hill area.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"Hind Afghan Dosti Zindabad," Swaraj said, asserting that India will always be Afghanistan's first strategic partner.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The Rs 2 crore flag was gifted by Flag Foundation, a charitable organisation promoted by industrialist Naveen Jindal.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The 15-tonne flagpole is high enough to make the banner visible from nearly all quarters of Kabul. The pole was flown in from India in segments, then erected to be earthquake-proof by Indian engineers, the New York Times said.</span></p>]]></description>
			<dc:creator>Edited by Kirti Dwivedi | Updated: 3:45 IST</dc:creator>
			<pubDate>Sun, 14 Sep 2014 10:00:10 -0600</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.newsx.com/world/middle-east/item/26665-afghanistans-megaflag-symbolises-hind-afghan-dosti</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Arrest of ISI spies have created panic among people, says M Karunanidhi</title>
			<link>http://www.newsx.com/regional/tamil-nadu/item/26664-arrest-of-isi-spies-have-created-panic-among-people-says-m-karunanidhi</link>
			<description><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/fcf6a20d66875b538654c93cae53aaee_Generic.jpg"><img align="right" border="0" src="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/fcf6a20d66875b538654c93cae53aaee_S.jpg" alt="arrest-of-isi-spies-have-created-panic-among-people-says-m-karunanidhi" /></a><font color="#ff3300"><b>Featured</b></font><p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Chennai: DMK chief M Karunanidhi said the arrest of ISI spies and their activities in Tamil Nadu has created panic among people and asked why no arrests have been made in connection with the May 1 twin bomb blasts in a train at the Central Railway Station in which a woman was killed.</span></p>

<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Referring to the arrest of alleged ISI spy Arun Selvarjan last week by the National Investigation Agency, he said it was not the first time 'such terrorists' had been apprehended during the AIADMK rule.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">He recalled that while one Thameem Ansari was arrested last year from Tiruchirappalli on espionage charges, another operative, Zakir Hussain, was nabbed here along with three of his accomplices early this year.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">All of them had worked at the behest of a Pakistani consular official in Sri Lanka, he said.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"Reports of movement of terrorists and their activities in Tamil Nadu has created panic among people," Karunanidhi said in a statement.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">He also recalled the incident when a 'pipe' bomb, targeting BJP leader LK Advani who was on a tour then, was found and diffused in October 2011 near Madurai.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The DMK chief said his government had taken all steps for maintaining law and order in the state, especially on terror-prevention front.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Two key Naxal leaders wanted for many years were nabbed during his government's tenure between 2006-11 but Chief Minister Jayalalithaa, then opposition leader, had in 2008 flayed the state government on law and order issue, he said.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">She had then even alleged Tamil Nadu had become a 'safe haven' for terrorists, Karunanidhi said.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Referring to her criticism on his continuing in power after the serial blasts in Coimbatore in 1998, he sought the Chief Minister's explanation on why none has been arrested in connection with the May 1 Central station twin bomb blasts.</span></p>]]></description>
			<dc:creator>Edited by Kirti Dwivedi | Updated: 3:15 IST</dc:creator>
			<pubDate>Sun, 14 Sep 2014 09:54:51 -0600</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.newsx.com/regional/tamil-nadu/item/26664-arrest-of-isi-spies-have-created-panic-among-people-says-m-karunanidhi</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Another Lankan arrested for alleged spying for Pak's ISI, security stepped up</title>
			<link>http://www.newsx.com/national/nation/item/26663-another-lankan-arrested-for-alleged-spying-for-paks-isi-security-stepped-up</link>
			<description><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/61b0cc68f0a01a397bd93395f8a381d3_Generic.jpg"><img align="right" border="0" src="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/61b0cc68f0a01a397bd93395f8a381d3_S.jpg" alt="another-lankan-arrested-for-alleged-spying-for-paks-isi-security-stepped-up" /></a><font color="#ff3300"><b>Featured</b></font><p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">New Delhi: With the arrest of another Sri Lankan national for alleged spying for Pakistan's ISI, central security agencies have stepped up surveillance of vital installations including defence and foreign consulates in southern parts of the country, reports said on Sunday.</span></p>

<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">After initial leads from central security agencies, National Investigation Agency (NIA) arrested Arun Selvarajan in Chennai last week and allegedly recovered some incriminating documents including layout plans of country's defence establishment like the Coast Guards complex.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">During preliminary interrogation before being sent to judicial custody, Selvarajan, who is also wanted in Sri Lanka for allegedly supporting banned LTTE terror group, told the officials that he had supplied information about some strategic locations to ISI handlers based in Colombo who were operating from the Pakistan's High Commission, official sources claimed.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">NIA has already approached a court in Chennai and is expected to get his police remand tomorrow.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The sources said that surveillance had been mounted at various points to see whether more such espionage activities were being carried out at the behest of the ISI.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Selvarajan again named Amir Zubair Siddiqui, who was working as Visa Counsellor at Pakistan High Commission based in Colombo till some time back but had to be repatriated to Islamabad after India mounted pressure on Sri Lanka about his alleged activities targeting this country.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Pakistan's Press Attache in Colombo Muhammad Daud Ehtisham has been quoted in some Lankan papers as saying that Siddiqui returned after completing his tenure in the island nation. </span><br /><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The arrested Lankan also named 'Shahjee' as his handler and said that his business had been in shambles when he was approached by the two Pakistani officials for allegedly carrying out espionage activities in India, the sources said.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">He landed in India in 2011 and was helped in setting up an event management company. After organising some road shows in Chennai, Selvarajan's company got an order for organising a function for one of local defence unit guarding India's waters, the sources said.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">After organising the function, Selvarajan sent a detailed outlay of the installation to his Pakistani handlers based in Colombo, the sources claimed.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Siddiqui was not a new name for the Intelligence Bureau as his name had cropped earlier in 2012-13 when security agencies picked up one Tameem Ansari, a frequent flier from Trichy to Colombo. Ansari was arrested after six months of surveillance in 2012.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">India has already sent its request under Mutual Legal Assistance Treaty (MLAT) in this case to Sri Lankan authorities last year to help in questioning and gathering evidence from the Island nation.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Ansari was a small trader who sent, among other things, potatoes and onions to Sri Lanka. After reverses in business, Ansari came in touch with Haji, a Tamil-speaking Muslim from Colombo who is alleged to have introduced him to Siddiqui in the Pakistan mission in Colombo, and his second in command, Shaji.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">After reportedly brainwashing him, Siddiqui roped him to take videos of the Nagapattinam port, the ships that berthed there, the topography and other dimensions as well as Mallipattinam, traditionally a landing point.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">This was followed by arrest of Sri Lankan national -- Sakir Hussain in April this year after a tip off from Intelligence Bureau as the accused had entered India with a mission to allegedly carry out reconnaissance of the US Consulate in Chennai and Israeli Consulate in Banaglore.</span></p>]]></description>
			<dc:creator>Edited by Priyanka Kukreja || Updated: 14:50 IST</dc:creator>
			<pubDate>Sun, 14 Sep 2014 09:05:08 -0600</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.newsx.com/national/nation/item/26663-another-lankan-arrested-for-alleged-spying-for-paks-isi-security-stepped-up</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>President Pranab Mukherjee leaves for Vietnam</title>
			<link>http://www.newsx.com/national/nation/item/26662-president-pranab-mukherjee-leaves-for-vietnam</link>
			<description><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/fd32b8985ce2a8d813539636c43665fe_Generic.jpg"><img align="right" border="0" src="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/fd32b8985ce2a8d813539636c43665fe_S.jpg" alt="president-pranab-mukherjee-leaves-for-vietnam" /></a><font color="#ff3300"><b>Featured</b></font><p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">New Delhi: President Pranab Mukherjee on Sunday embarked on a four-day state visit to strategically important Vietnam during which he will hold talks with top leaders there as the two countries will ink pacts in key areas of oil exploration and air connectivity sectors.</span></p>

<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Vice President Hamid Ansari, Prime Minister Narendra Modi, his cabinet colleagues Rajnath Singh, Sushma Swaraj and Thawar Chand Gehlot, Army Chief General Dalbir Singh Suhag and Navy Chief R K Dhowan gave the President a warm farewell at the Rashtrapati Bhavan.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">During the trip, Mukherjee would be travelling to capital Hanoi and the historic city of Ho Chi Minh and hold discussions with President Truong Tan Sang and Prime Minister Nguyen Tan Dung on issues of international, regional and bilateral importance.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Ahead of his visit, Mukherjee termed security and defence as "major pillars" of cooperation between the two countries and said he was of the view that there was much more potential that can be realised in these areas and both sides are working towards it along with the regional partners.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">An agreement between India's ONGC Videsh Limited (OVL) and Petro Vietnam for exploring oil in the South China Sea blocks are among the number of pacts to be inked during the visit. Oil Minister Dharmendra Pradhan is part of the delegation that is travelling with the President.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The attempt to invite India for drilling operations in the disputed South China Sea is seen by experts as a move by Vietnam to counter China's influence in the region.</span></p>]]></description>
			<dc:creator>Edited by Priyanka Kukreja || Updated: 14:30 IST</dc:creator>
			<pubDate>Sun, 14 Sep 2014 08:46:03 -0600</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.newsx.com/national/nation/item/26662-president-pranab-mukherjee-leaves-for-vietnam</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>PM to deliver speech at UN General Assembly in Hindi</title>
			<link>http://www.newsx.com/national/nation/item/26661-pm-to-deliver-speech-at-un-general-assembly-in-hindi</link>
			<description><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/0bb3869adc26a27ae52fa7d55e4ecffb_Generic.jpg"><img align="right" border="0" src="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/0bb3869adc26a27ae52fa7d55e4ecffb_S.jpg" alt="pm-to-deliver-speech-at-un-general-assembly-in-hindi" /></a><font color="#ff3300"><b>Featured</b></font><p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">NEW DELHI: Prime Minister Narendra Modi will deliver his speech at the UN General Assembly in New York in Hindi, Home Minister Rajnath Singh said today.</span></p>

<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Addressing a function organised on the occasion of Hindi Divas, the Home Minister said Atal Bihari Vajpayee was the first Prime Minister to deliver his speech in the United Nations in Hindi.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">I, as a Minister, once had delivered my speech in the United Nations in Hindi.... Our Prime Minister Narendra Modi will deliver his speech in United Nations in Hindi.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The Prime Minister also speaks Hindi when he meets foreign dignitaries, he said amidst applause at a function organised at Rashtrapati Bhavan. President Pranab Mukherjee was present at the function.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The Prime Minister is expected to address the United Nations General Assembly on September 27.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The Home Minister said 55 per cent population of the country speaks Hindi, while 85 to 90 per cent people in the country understand Hindi even though it is not their mother tongue.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Singh said people like Bal Gangadhar Tilak, Shyama Prasad Mookerjee, Mahatma Gandhi and N Gopalaswami Ayyangar had advocated expansion and popularisation of Hindi even though their mother tongues were different.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Hindi is the common language of the country, he said.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The Home Minister said Sanskrit is the mother of all Indian languages, while Hindi and other regional languages are sisters.</span></p>]]></description>
			<dc:creator>Edited by Priyanka Kukreja || Updated: 14:20 IST</dc:creator>
			<pubDate>Sun, 14 Sep 2014 08:38:24 -0600</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.newsx.com/national/nation/item/26661-pm-to-deliver-speech-at-un-general-assembly-in-hindi</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>CIC issues show-cause notices to Sonia, Amit Shah</title>
			<link>http://www.newsx.com/national/nation/item/26660-cic-issues-show-cause-notices-to-sonia-amit-shah</link>
			<description><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/1c93f87c59d9528243c4b94b5036f29a_Generic.jpg"><img align="right" border="0" src="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/1c93f87c59d9528243c4b94b5036f29a_S.jpg" alt="cic-issues-show-cause-notices-to-sonia-amit-shah" /></a><p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The CIC has issued show-cause notices to BJP President Amit Shah and Congress chief Sonia Gandhi along with the heads of four other political parties asking why an inquiry should not be instituted in the matter of non-compliance of its order to implement the RTI Act.</span></p>

<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Last year, on a plea by activist Subhash Agrawal, the Central Information Commission (CIC) had declared six national parties -- Congress, BJP, NCP, CPI, CPI-M and BSP -- as public authorities, thereby bringing them under the ambit of the Right to Information Act.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">However, none of the parties either contested the decision in courts or followed the instructions of the panel.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The Commission had issued notices on February 7 and March 25 to these political parties seeking their detailed comments on the complaint by Agrawal that they had not complied with the orders of the CIC.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"Therefore, a notice is issued to show cause within four weeks as to why an inquiry should not be initiated in the matter of non-compliance of the Commission's order dated June 3, 2013, under Section 18 of the RTI Act, 2005... Take further notice that if you fail to respond within prescribed time, the matter will be processed on the strength of material on record, in accordance with law," the notice said.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The notice has been sent to the chiefs of Congress, BJP, BSP and NCP and to the general secretaries of CPI and CPI-M.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The move comes close on the heels of a Delhi High Court order which directed the Commission to decide in six months on a complaint against Congress chief Sonia Gandhi regarding the issue of non-compliance with the transparency panel's directions that the party was answerable under the RTI Act.</span></p>]]></description>
			<dc:creator>Edited by Priyanka Kukreja || Updated: 13:10 IST</dc:creator>
			<pubDate>Sun, 14 Sep 2014 07:29:49 -0600</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.newsx.com/national/nation/item/26660-cic-issues-show-cause-notices-to-sonia-amit-shah</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Money laundering: RBI takes action against erring UCBs</title>
			<link>http://www.newsx.com/national/nation/item/26659-money-laundering-rbi-takes-action-against-erring-ucbs</link>
			<description><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/11352a7e391c1d8e3e96ac24749f2a09_Generic.jpg"><img align="right" border="0" src="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/11352a7e391c1d8e3e96ac24749f2a09_S.jpg" alt="money-laundering-rbi-takes-action-against-erring-ucbs" /></a><font color="#ff3300"><b>Featured</b></font><p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Cracking down on money laundering, the Reserve Bank of India (RBI) has closed down six Urban Cooperative Banks (UCBs) which were suspected of being used to route illegal money.</span></p>

<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The central bank has also asked state governments to take stern action against any other erring UCBs after reports emerged that such entities were being used as conduits for money laundering.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The matter of misuse of UCBs, over which there is dual control by central and state governments, was discussed during a recent meeting of the Economic Intelligence Council (EIC) headed by Finance Minister.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">UCBs are inspected annually or once in two years depending on their ratings or classification. About 70 per cent of these urban cooperative banks are subjected to inspection every year. RBI has aggressively pursued the issue and around six UCBs were closed as they were found to be "unviable", according to the minutes of the meeting.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Sources who were present at the meeting said it was found that these banks were lax on regulatory issues and were used as conduits.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"RBI had taken up the issue with the state governments and also advised stringent action against the erring UCBs," it said, but did not disclose the names of the banks.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">On the issue of risk categorisation and compilation or updating of profiles of all their existing customers, the apex bank said their regional officers have been advised to seek compliance from UCBs and submit an update which would be reviewed and any necessary action initiated.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">RBI has been directed by the Chairman, EIC, to block accounts of non-complying customers while keeping the credit option open. The customers would be able to credit money into their accounts but the withdrawal facility would be activated only when the mandated information is furnished.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The action comes after it came to be noticed that the UCBs, which hold deposits of over Rs 2 lakh crore, are being misused for money laundering, causing alarm to the government.</span></p>]]></description>
			<dc:creator>Edited by Priyanka Kukreja || Updated: 12:40 IST</dc:creator>
			<pubDate>Sun, 14 Sep 2014 07:02:52 -0600</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.newsx.com/national/nation/item/26659-money-laundering-rbi-takes-action-against-erring-ucbs</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>India-bound Malaysia Airlines flight return back after defect</title>
			<link>http://www.newsx.com/national/nation/item/26658-india-bound-malaysia-airlines-flight-return-back-after-defect</link>
			<description><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/af034c0c4d34e2cbaf2e9b61136944f4_Generic.jpg"><img align="right" border="0" src="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/af034c0c4d34e2cbaf2e9b61136944f4_S.jpg" alt="india-bound-malaysia-airlines-flight-return-back-after-defect" /></a><p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Kuala Lumpur: An India-bound flight of Malaysia Airlines was forced to return due to an auto-pilot defect, landing safely here on Sunday, said the carrier already hit by the twin tragedies this year.</span></p>

<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Flight MH198 from Kuala Lumpur to Hyderabad departed at 10.20pm last night but the Boeing 737-800 turned back due to an auto-pilot defect and landed safely at the Kuala Lumpur International Airport at 2.01am today, it said in a statement.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"The defect did not have any impact on the safety of the aircraft or passengers, however, as a precautionary measure, the operating Captain decided to turn back," the airline said.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">It refuted reports on social media that the aircraft caught fire. Initial reports had said that the plane had to make an emergency landing due to "burning fuel".</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The airline said that upon arrival, passengers and crew disembarked safely and were given accommodation at nearby hotels.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The flight has been rescheduled to operate as MH198D and will depart Kuala Lumpur at 12pm today.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The airline said it regretted the disruption to its guests' travel plans but reiterated that safety of its passengers was its priority.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Malaysia Airlines Flight MH370 with 239 people aboard lost contact on March 8. No trace of any wreckage has been found so far.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Another flight MH17 was shot down by a missile over eastern Ukraine on July 17, killing all 289 people aboard.</span></p>]]></description>
			<dc:creator>Edited by Priyanka Kukreja || Updated: 12:10 IST</dc:creator>
			<pubDate>Sun, 14 Sep 2014 06:39:59 -0600</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.newsx.com/national/nation/item/26658-india-bound-malaysia-airlines-flight-return-back-after-defect</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Rains lash Kashmir Valley; hampers rescue operations</title>
			<link>http://www.newsx.com/national/top-stories/item/26657-rains-lash-kashmir-valley-hampers-rescue-operations</link>
			<description><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/b5d6f561a9b19b7552adff95fbacffe6_Generic.jpg"><img align="right" border="0" src="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/b5d6f561a9b19b7552adff95fbacffe6_S.jpg" alt="rains-lash-kashmir-valley-hampers-rescue-operations" /></a><font color="#ff3300"><b>Featured</b></font><p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">After few clear days, rains returned to the Kashmir valley on Sunday in bad news for flood victims as it could hamper rescue operations in the submerged areas.</span></p>

<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Rainfall accompanied by thunder and lightning lashed Srinagar and other parts of the Valley. </span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The weather had been clear for the past five days after incessant rains led to unprecedented floods in the Valley. </span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Weather was overcast since early this morning and the rains started around 8:30 AM and the intensity increased.</span></p>
<p><iframe src="//www.youtube.com/embed/cu8KZJDR6ww" frameborder="0" width="684" height="415" allowfullscreen="true" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"></iframe></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">SDM, Srinagar, Syed Abid Rasheed Shah that inclement weather will create problems as many people are still on the roads and without shelter. </span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">At some places, people are putting up in tents which are not waterproof, he said.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">At the same time, Shah said relief operations would continue despite rainfall.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Around 1.5 lakh people are still marooned in many parts of the Valley after the worst floods in the state in a century unleashed a trail of death and destruction.</span></p>]]></description>
			<dc:creator>Edited by Priyanka Kukreja || Updated: 11:45 IST</dc:creator>
			<pubDate>Sun, 14 Sep 2014 06:02:59 -0600</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.newsx.com/national/top-stories/item/26657-rains-lash-kashmir-valley-hampers-rescue-operations</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Happy wife key to happy life for men: study</title>
			<link>http://www.newsx.com/life-style/most-popular/item/26656-happy-wife-key-to-happy-life-for-men-study</link>
			<description><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/c2a6683154cffa17f81ab1c33e675623_Generic.jpg"><img align="right" border="0" src="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/c2a6683154cffa17f81ab1c33e675623_S.jpg" alt="happy-wife-key-to-happy-life-for-men-study" /></a><font color="#ff3300"><b>Featured</b></font><p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">A husband who is unhappy with his marriage is still likely to be happy with his life  if his wife gives their marriage high marks, a new study suggests.</span></p>

<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Older husbands and wives in better marriages are more satisfied with their lives, said Vicki Freedman, a research professor at the University of Michigan Institute for Social Research.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">But overall life satisfaction for an unhappily married man depends on how his wife describes their relationship. If she describes their marriage as higher quality, his life satisfaction is buoyed  even if he gives the marriage a less glowing assessment, said Freedman, a co-author with Rutgers University sociologist Deborah Carr.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The research is among the first to examine the influence of his and her marriage appraisals on psychological well-being among older couples.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Marital quality is an important buffer against the health-depleting effects of later-life stressors such as care-iving, and a critical resource as couples manage difficult decisions regarding their care in later life, Carr said.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Freedman and Carr analysed 2009 data from a sample of 394 couples who were part of the ISR Panel Study of Income Dynamics, a national panel study of a representative sample of US families. At least one spouse in each couple was aged 60 or older.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">They found that life satisfaction and momentary happiness did not differ significantly by gender. Both husbands and wives, on average, rated their general life satisfaction as 5 out of 6 and happiness very close to 5.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">They also found that husbands rated their marriages slightly more positively than wives, on average.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">For both husbands and wives, being in a better-rated marriage was linked to greater life satisfaction and happiness, Carr said.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">But wives assessments of the marriage are more important in some respects than their husbands reports, she said.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The study was published in the Journal of Marriage and Family.</span></p>]]></description>
			<dc:creator>Edited by Priyanka Kukreja || Updated: 11:15 IST</dc:creator>
			<pubDate>Sun, 14 Sep 2014 05:25:09 -0600</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.newsx.com/life-style/most-popular/item/26656-happy-wife-key-to-happy-life-for-men-study</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Ban entry of Muslims in 'Garba' events: Pravin Togadia</title>
			<link>http://www.newsx.com/national/nation/item/26655-ban-entry-of-muslims-in-garba-events-pravin-togadia</link>
			<description><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/1bab055b4602a4863a9be09d2bf5fa2a_Generic.jpg"><img align="right" border="0" src="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/1bab055b4602a4863a9be09d2bf5fa2a_S.jpg" alt="ban-entry-of-muslims-in-garba-events-pravin-togadia" /></a><font color="#ff3300"><b>Featured</b></font><p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Ahmedabad: Echoing the views of a BJP MLA from Madhya Pradesh, firebrand VHP leader Pravin Togadia on Saturday said Muslims must not be allowed inside the Garba events and insisted identity cards of each and every person be checked for participants in and visitors to such events.</span></p>

<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"We must be alert so that not a single Muslim person can enter in our Garba festival. Identity cards of each and every person must be checked at every Garba event," Togadia said in Amreli town in Saurashtra.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">He said "Navratri is the festival of Mother Amba's prayers and worship, so we cannot allow beaf-eaters Muslims to enter into Garba places."</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">BJP MLA in Madhya Pradesh Usha Thakur had recently asked party workers to ensure that Muslim youths are not allowed to enter Garba venues in her constituency, Indore (3), during the upcoming annual Navdurga festival alleging that Hindu girls are lured by them and converted to Islam as part of the love jihad to distort population ratio in the country.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Thakur, who is also state BJP vice-president, had said she would soon be writing to all Garba organisers in her constituency to allow only Hindu men inside the Garba venues by making electoral photo-identity cards mandatory for entry.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Speaking about 'love jihad', Togadia said "we need to be alert about love jihad. If it is love, then where is the need of conversion?" Togadia said.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">On Prime Minister Narendra Modi's offer of relief to flood-affected Pakistan occupied Kashmir (PoK), Vishwa Hindu Parishad (VHP) Togadia today said tanks should be sent there along with relief materials.</span></p>]]></description>
			<dc:creator>Edited by Priyanka Kukreja || Updated: 10:55 IST</dc:creator>
			<pubDate>Sun, 14 Sep 2014 05:06:46 -0600</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.newsx.com/national/nation/item/26655-ban-entry-of-muslims-in-garba-events-pravin-togadia</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Air India set to send pilots to fill shortfall in Express service</title>
			<link>http://www.newsx.com/national/nation/item/26654-air-india-set-to-send-pilots-to-fill-shortfall-in-express-service</link>
			<description><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/e1187cf6c3d3aa377ce6a4b9dd8027af_Generic.jpg"><img align="right" border="0" src="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/e1187cf6c3d3aa377ce6a4b9dd8027af_S.jpg" alt="air-india-set-to-send-pilots-to-fill-shortfall-in-express-service" /></a><font color="#ff3300"><b>Featured</b></font><p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Mumbai: The Air India board has cleared a proposal for sending its pilots on deputation to its budget arm, Air India Express, which has been facing shortage of commanders for some time now, airline sources said on Sunday.</span></p>

<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The move would help Air India, which may face the problem of having excess pilots as the airline's Boeing 777-200 LR fleet is being phased out and shrinking, they said.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Air India used to earlier send its pilots on deputation to Air India Express (AIE), but stopped the practice after the two-month strike by pilots in May-June 2012.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"The Board recently approved the proposal, paving the way for AI pilots to join AIE," a source said here.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Shortage of pilots in AIE has been continuing for a long time and has led to at least three or four machines of its 17-strong aircraft fleet always remaining on ground, they said.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Besides, the Air India and AIE top brass were keen to have in-house talent as a cheaper option rather than going to the market to meet the shortage.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"The idea was mooted several times with the airline management but did not find favour primarily due to the two- month strike by the pilots owing allegiance to the now de-recognised Indian Pilots Guild," they said.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Air India has already sold five of the total eight Boeing 777-200 LRs to Abu Dhabi-based Etihad Airways and has floated tenders to sell the remaining ones.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"The phasing out of these planes is leaving surplus pilots with the carrier who will now be adjusted in AIE. Besides, it will also help Air India pilots in getting command positions earlier than in the parent company. So, the move will benefit Air India and AIE as also the pilots," they said.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">AIE will require around 50 more pilots to operate its entire fleet of 17 aircraft, they said, adding it will be better since the airline was planning to induct eight more Boeing 737-800s in the fleet to get back to the original size of 26 aircraft.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The Kochi-based low-cost subsidiary till a few year back used to operate some 214 flights with 25 planes, seven of them being leased aircraft.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">However, it gradually phased out the leased aircraft and lost one brand new Boeing 737-800 in the Mangalore crash, bringing the fleet strength down to 17.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The airline now operates 165 weekly flights connecting 12 international routes, mostly to the Gulf, and also covers 11 domestic destinations. Of these, 87 flights are from Kerala alone.</span></p>]]></description>
			<dc:creator>Edited by Priyanka Kukreja || Updated: 10:35 IST</dc:creator>
			<pubDate>Sun, 14 Sep 2014 04:55:08 -0600</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.newsx.com/national/nation/item/26654-air-india-set-to-send-pilots-to-fill-shortfall-in-express-service</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Flood fury: Rising water levels in North Kashmir matter of concern, 1.5 lakh people still marooned, says Omar</title>
			<link>http://www.newsx.com/national/nation/item/26653-flood-fury-rising-water-levels-in-north-kashmir-matter-of-concern-15-lakh-people-still-marooned-says-omar</link>
			<description><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/9951d49465136de8da816b14abbac284_Generic.jpg"><img align="right" border="0" src="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/9951d49465136de8da816b14abbac284_S.jpg" alt="flood-fury-rising-water-levels-in-north-kashmir-matter-of-concern-15-lakh-people-still-marooned-says-omar" /></a><font color="#ff3300"><b>Featured</b></font><p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Srinagar: Water levels in North Kashmir are rising which is a matter of concern, Jammu and Kashmir Chief Minister Omar Abdullah said while hoping that it would not be as bad as in the rest of the valley.</span></p>

<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The Chief Minister said the water levels are "receding" in central Kashmir but they are still above the danger mark and the government was waiting for it to go below the danger mark to "plug the breaches" on the banks of river Jhelum.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"Water levels are rising in some parts of North Kashmir. That is a matter of concern. We are hoping that North Kashmir will not be as badly affected as the rest," Abdullah told PTI in an interview.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">He said that as per the figures available with the state government so far, 129 people had lost lives in Jammu region whereas 30-35 people were found dead in Kashmir valley.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">On the number of people rescued by various agencies so far, he said the Army and NDRF know the exact figures but he was aware of 50,000 people having been rescued by the Army and 20,000-30000 by NDRF.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Asked about the extent of loss of lives in the flood, he said "I am hoping and praying that the loss of life will not be as severe as we expect it. Because looking at the situation, the death toll is still remarkably low. I am hoping and praying that it will not be as bad some have been fearing."</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">He said that "within the constraints of (the number of) helicopters, we are doing the best job possible," when asked if the government was able to rescue enough people in the situation.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">On the damage caused to the infrastructure by the floods, Abdullah said officials have already been tasked to assess the damage so that repair and reconstruction activities can be initiated.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"Right now, the focus still remains on rescue operations as 1.5 lakh people are still marooned. Our primary focus is on provision of relief like rations, medicines and supplies they require," he said.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Abdullah identified rice, water, medicines as the items required more than anything else.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">To a query on incidents of stone-pelting and the possibility of involvement of separatists in them, the Chief Minister said "those people are not from Srinagar. They have been coming in from South and North Kashmir and they have been indulging in thefts and law and order situations."</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">On reports about incidents of thefts in marooned houses, he said "it is true".</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Abdullah said such incidents have taken place in other countries also as "even in London, when riots took place, there was looting. I wish Jammu and Kashmir had set a better example. I have asked the police to increase their presence."</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">On the possibility of spread of diseases and epidemic after the flood water recedes, he said Kashmir has a history that lives are not lost in floods but in the aftermath of floods.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"Our focus is on provision of medicines and water- purifying medicines like chlorine and lakhs of chlorine tablets have been distributed. We have asked municipalities to activate the sanitation system. Our primary concern is rescue and provision of food, prevention of diseases and epidemics is our priority," he said.</span></p>]]></description>
			<dc:creator>Edited by Priyanka Kukreja || Updated: 10:15 IST</dc:creator>
			<pubDate>Sun, 14 Sep 2014 04:38:14 -0600</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.newsx.com/national/nation/item/26653-flood-fury-rising-water-levels-in-north-kashmir-matter-of-concern-15-lakh-people-still-marooned-says-omar</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Facebook posts give clues to your personality</title>
			<link>http://www.newsx.com/gadgets/social/item/26652-facebook-posts-give-clues-to-your-personality</link>
			<description><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/ddf0e4827705c72b0936b4235293ea2c_Generic.jpg"><img align="right" border="0" src="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/ddf0e4827705c72b0936b4235293ea2c_S.jpg" alt="facebook-posts-give-clues-to-your-personality" /></a><font color="#ff3300"><b>Featured</b></font><p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Washington: People can accurately detect the personality traits of strangers through Facebook activity, according to a new study.</span></p>

<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">However, changes to the social media site in the past three years could be making it harder to do so, scientists said.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Researchers at The University of Kansas sampled 100 Facebook users, paralleling the demographics of the social networking site, and asked them to fill out a personality survey.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">A group of coders looked at each person's Facebook activity, 53 cues in all, to see whether certain personality types were more likely to do specific activities.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The researchers then had 35 strangers spend 10 to 15 minutes on each of the Facebook users' profile pages to see if they could correctly gauge a person's personality.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The study looked at which cues correlated to personality types and whether the 35 strangers were able to correctly detect personality traits based on those cues.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The research found that extroversion was the easiest personality trait for strangers to interpret followed by agreeableness and openness.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">There was just one cue that pointed to conscientiousness and none that helped detect neuroticism.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">While strangers were able to correctly match certain Facebook activities with personality traits, the researchers believe new algorithms enacted by Facebook could make it harder to detect personality traits.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Since the data was collected in 2011, Facebook has changed how and when users see other people's activity, researchers said.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">At the time data was collected, users saw every action - from likes to changes in personal history - their friends took.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Now, those actions can be viewed in a small box in the upper right-hand corner of the page, making the actions less apparent.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Today, the posts on Facebook's most prominent feature, the newsfeed, are based on an algorithm that takes into account how recent the post is, how many people like it or have commented on it and if the user has frequently interacted with the person making the post.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">That's an important shift for judging personalities because, according to the study, an agreeable person tends to post less often, an open person is less likely to respond to other people's posts but make more political status updates, and a conscientious person agrees more often with what other people post.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">So, if Facebook changes how often users see their friends' posts, users could be forming the wrong impressions of their friends, researchers said.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"If Facebook suddenly starts highlighting people you may not have regularly interacted with and promotes a lot of posts from them, you may no longer think that person is agreeable," said KU doctoral candidate Natalie Pennington.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"It may not be that they post that much, but that your feed has gotten smaller and shows a smaller subset of friends," she said.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The study will be published in the journal New Media &amp; Society.</span></p>]]></description>
			<dc:creator>Edited by Priyanka Kukreja || Updated: 9:15 IST</dc:creator>
			<pubDate>Sun, 14 Sep 2014 03:38:35 -0600</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.newsx.com/gadgets/social/item/26652-facebook-posts-give-clues-to-your-personality</guid>
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
