<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet href="http://www.newsx.com/components/com_obrss/assets/xsl/atom-to-html.xsl" type="text/xsl"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
	<channel>
		<title>rss</title>
		<description><![CDATA[RSS Feed]]></description>
		<link>http://www.newsx.com/</link>
		<lastBuildDate>Sun, 21 Sep 2014 14:40:25 -0600</lastBuildDate>
		<generator>FeedCreator 1.8.3 (obRSS 1.9)</generator>
		<atom:link href="http://www.newsx.com/component/obrss/rss?format=" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
		<image>
			<url>http://www.newsx.com/images/</url>
			<title>rss</title>
			<link>http://www.newsx.com/</link>
			<description>RSS Feed</description>
		</image>
		<item>
			<title>Bihar: Sushil blames Nitish for breaking alliance with NDA</title>
			<link>http://www.newsx.com/regional/other-states/item/26971-bihar-sushil-blames-nitish-for-breaking-alliance-with-nda</link>
			<description><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/68fb9f88d487e17dff0ac68c91a87380_Generic.jpg"><img align="right" border="0" src="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/68fb9f88d487e17dff0ac68c91a87380_S.jpg" alt="bihar-sushil-blames-nitish-for-breaking-alliance-with-nda" /></a><font color="#ff3300"><b>Featured</b></font><p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Patna: Observing that Bihar has missed yet another opportunity to fast track development due to the state government's confrontationist attitude towards the Centre, former deputy chief minister Sushil Kumar Modi on Sunday squarely blamed his erstwhile boss Nitish Kumar for breaking alliance with the NDA.</span></p>

<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"It's due to Kumar's stubborn attitude and his unilateral decision to break alliance with the NDA that Bihar has missed the bus yet again to fast track development," he said in a statement.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Had the senior JD(U) leader not parted ways with the NDA last year, the ruling coalition at the Centre and in Bihar would have been the same and it would have worked wonders for development of the state, Modi said.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Kumar did not stop at breaking alliance with the NDA last year, but went on to resign from the chief minister's post to steer clear of any situation that would have compelled him to greet the Prime Minister Narendra Modi, shake hands with him or to write letter to the Centre, the former deputy chief minister said and regretted that his erstwhile boss left behind a government which was bent on haggling with the Centre on one issue or another.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Modi said that it would have paid rich dividends if the governments at the Centre and in Bihar had been represented by the same coalition parties but the senior JD(U) leader robbed us of such a scenario.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">It has been the misfortune of Bihar and its people that governments at the Centre and in the state over the past few decades were represented by different political parties or coalitions which somehow never shared the same wavelength, he said, adding it has worked to the disadvantage of Bihar.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The senior BJP leader also took a dig at Kumar for his efforts to work out anti-NDA coalition at the national level and said that the former chief minister has compromised with his principles by first aligning with the fodder scam convict and the RJD supremo Lalu Prasad and then meeting with the former Haryana chief minister Om Prakash Chautala, who too has been convicted in a scam.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Stating that it was imperative that Bihar must get a government that can seek cooperation with the Centre and not adopt a confrontationist attitude with it, Modi exuded confidence that the NDA will come to power in next year's Assembly polls and step up development in the state in partnership with the central government.</span></p>]]></description>
			<dc:creator>Edited by Kirti Dwivedi | Updated: 7:00 IST</dc:creator>
			<pubDate>Sun, 21 Sep 2014 14:15:56 -0600</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.newsx.com/regional/other-states/item/26971-bihar-sushil-blames-nitish-for-breaking-alliance-with-nda</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Maha election: Sena likely to decide candidates today, meeting underway in Matoshree</title>
			<link>http://www.newsx.com/national/nation/item/26970-maha-election-sena-likely-to-decide-candidates-today-meeting-underway-in-matoshree</link>
			<description><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/50f8535f329fcdbab4fdf384faf51da9_Generic.jpg"><img align="right" border="0" src="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/50f8535f329fcdbab4fdf384faf51da9_S.jpg" alt="maha-election-sena-likely-to-decide-candidates-today-meeting-underway-in-matoshree" /></a><font color="#ff3300"><b>Featured</b></font><p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Mumbai: While the decision on seat-sharing formula for Maharashtra Assembly polls is yet to be taken, the Shiv Sena is expected to finalise the names of its candidates on Sunday , as per reports.</span></p>

<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The meeting between the top brass of Shiv Sena is underway at Matoshree.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Sena chief Uddhav Thackeray on Sunday offered 119 seats to BJP while keeping 151 seats for his own party.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Addressing his party workers here, Thackeray said there is a tug of war going on in the Shiv Sena-BJP alliance.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"The party workers have given me the authority to take a decision and I will do it with responsibility, keeping everything in mind. We are making the last effort to save the alliance. 151 seats for Shiv Sena, 119 for BJP and the rest 18 for others," he said.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The Shiv Sena supremo further said that seat distribution was a complicated affair.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Asserting that alliance with the Shiv Sena should move in a forward direction, Bharatiya Janata Party (BJP) leader Vinod Tawde on Sunday said the party headed by Uddhav Thackeray should be open to discussions and not rigid on its stand over distribution of seats for the upcoming Maharashtra Assembly polls.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"Uddhav Thackeray may have given us a formula but the feeling in the BJP is that the alliance should go on. And if that is to happen, there can be no `final` formula. Till a final decision is made, discussions can keep on happening," he told ANI here.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Tawde further said that the BJP was only working for the interest of Maharashtra and added that his party did not have the Chief Minister`s post in mind.</span></p>]]></description>
			<dc:creator>Edited by Kirti Dwivedi | Updated: 6:45 IST</dc:creator>
			<pubDate>Sun, 21 Sep 2014 14:10:28 -0600</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.newsx.com/national/nation/item/26970-maha-election-sena-likely-to-decide-candidates-today-meeting-underway-in-matoshree</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>#SenaBJPMahaSplit: PM Modi, Amit Shah attend BJP meet to resolve stand-off</title>
			<link>http://www.newsx.com/component/k2/item/26969-#senabjpmahasplit-pm-modi-amit-shah-attend-bjp-meet-to-resolve-stand-off&amp;Itemid=916</link>
			<description><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/f3148489585bb79a733ccf32b2b548b3_Generic.jpg"><img align="right" border="0" src="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/f3148489585bb79a733ccf32b2b548b3_S.jpg" alt="#senabjpmahasplit-pm-modi-amit-shah-attend-bjp-meet-to-resolve-stand-off" /></a><font color="#ff3300"><b>Featured</b></font><p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">NEW DELHI: The Bharatiya Janata Party has begun its brainstorming session to resolve a crisis with its oldest ally in Maharashtra, the Shiv Sena. Prime Minister Narendra Modi is chairing the party's central election committee meeting to discuss ways to convince the Sena to accept its formula of contesting 135 seats each in next month's assembly election in Maharashtra.</span></p>

<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"The big question is whether the alliance with the BJP will survive," admitted the Shiv Sena chief Uddhav Thackeray today, making yet another "final offer" on seat sharing to the BJP. One that he said was a supreme concession to his ally "for the sake of Maharashtra".</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The Sena made a fresh offer to its partner, but the BJP is not ready to buy it. At a national executive meet of his party, Mr Thackeray said his party was ready to contest 151 of Maharashtra's 288 seats, considerably less than the 169 it had fought the last time. He said the 18 extra seats from the Sena's kitty could be given to their allies in what is called the 'Mahayuti' alliance, leaving 119 for the BJP to contest - exactly the number it had fought in 2009. The BJP, its ally, would not then have to shell out any seats to the smaller allies.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Soon after the BJP indicated that it was not impressed.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"The BJP has a higher percentage of seats it won in comparison to the Shiv Sena," said Eknath Khadse and Vinod Tawde, two of the party's top leaders from Maharashtra. The BJP argues that after its superior performance in the Lok Sabha elections four months ago it cannot be counted as the junior partner in the state anymore and wanted both parties to contest 135 seats each, leaving the rest for smaller allies. The party then even agreed to contest 130 seats, giving the Sena 140.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The BJP said there was a rationale to its formula. "The Shiv Sena has never won on 59 seats, while that number is 19 for the BJP. If these were to be re-allocated then we would all benefit," explained Mr Khadse and Mr Tawde.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The Sena takes that as a huge slight and says its cadres will rebel.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">At stake is the post of chief minister; the partner that will win the most seats will get the post should the BJP-Shiv Sena coalition come to power.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The BJP leaders also told the Sena to, "make offers face-to-face, not through TV".</span></p>]]></description>
			<dc:creator>Edited by Kirti Dwivedi | Updated: 6:35 IST</dc:creator>
			<pubDate>Sun, 21 Sep 2014 13:49:07 -0600</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.newsx.com/component/k2/item/26969-#senabjpmahasplit-pm-modi-amit-shah-attend-bjp-meet-to-resolve-stand-off&amp;Itemid=916</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Muslim intellectuals welcomes PM Modi's statement on community</title>
			<link>http://www.newsx.com/national/nation/item/26968-muslim-intellectuals-welcomes-pm-modis-statement-on-community</link>
			<description><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/52faeedb0197393417f2be00a03b6a29_Generic.jpg"><img align="right" border="0" src="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/52faeedb0197393417f2be00a03b6a29_S.jpg" alt="muslim-intellectuals-welcomes-pm-modis-statement-on-community" /></a><font color="#ff3300"><b>Featured</b></font><p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Aligarh: A body of Muslim intellectuals on Sunday welcomed Prime Minister Narendra Modi's statement lauding the patriotism of Muslims in the country.</span></p>

<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The Forum for Muslim Studies and Analysis (FMSA) today passed a resolution stating that by acknowledging and accepting the positive contribution to the nation by this vital segment of the country's populace, the PM has tried to assuage the collective hurt undergone by the Muslim community recently because of some vitriolic utterances by some of his own party members.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The Forum in its resolution has urged the PM to now take remedial steps for ensuring that those of his party members who are persisting with their divisive communal agenda are not permitted to do so.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"This is the only way that he can ensure that the country's development plans can bear fruit," it said.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The resolution stressed that Muslim community was second to none in its patriotism and would thwart the evil designs of any external force which tries to disturb the peace of the country.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">In a separate resolution, the FMSA expressed serious concern on a recent report that a Muslim member of the Indian Army - Subedar Ishrat Ali of Rajputana Rifles was allegedly penalised by his superior for calling out "Jai Hind".</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">According to a report, his superior insisted that Ishrat Ali should instead adopt the salutation of Ram Ram or Jai Mata Di while addressing his colleagues and superiors and refrain from saying Jai Hind.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The FMSA has urged the Defence Minister to enquire into the incident and take necessary action against the guilty officer.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The signatories to the above resolutions include Prof Shahabudin Quershi, Prof Razaullah Khan, both former senior faculty members at AMU, Dr G F Sabri, Dr Nasim Ashraf and Dr Fatima Zehra.</span></p>]]></description>
			<dc:creator>Edited by Kirti Dwivedi | Updated: 6:05 IST</dc:creator>
			<pubDate>Sun, 21 Sep 2014 13:23:19 -0600</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.newsx.com/national/nation/item/26968-muslim-intellectuals-welcomes-pm-modis-statement-on-community</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Don't hit below the belt, rake up old issue: Ajit Pawar says</title>
			<link>http://www.newsx.com/national/nation/item/26967-dont-hit-below-the-belt-rake-up-old-issue-ajit-pawar-says</link>
			<description><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/c93103d86eaf92d9e5e531d1eaf60127_Generic.jpg"><img align="right" border="0" src="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/c93103d86eaf92d9e5e531d1eaf60127_S.jpg" alt="dont-hit-below-the-belt-rake-up-old-issue-ajit-pawar-says" /></a><font color="#ff3300"><b>Featured</b></font><p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Mumbai: Ahead of the next month's Maharashtra Assembly elections, Deputy Chief Minister and NCP leader Ajit Pawar on Sunday took to the Facebook to make an appeal that his political rivals and media should not hit "below the belt" and rake up old issues.</span></p>

<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Pawar, who came in for intensive flak for his comment on the drought situation last year, said he had apologised for it. "If there is no water in the dam, what can be done? Am I supposed to urinate in the dam or what," Pawar had said, which kicked off a storm of protest, after which he apologised.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Pawar, in a statement circulated on Facebook by his followers today, said he should not have made the comment, but all efforts to persuade Bhaiyya Deshmukh, a Solapur-based farmer, to end his fast had failed. "Political rivals were using him to target the government which was making every effort to provide relief to the farmers," Pawar said.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">He later sat on a fast for ten hours at the memorial of the Y B Chavan, the first Chief Minister of the state, as a penance over his mistake, he said.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"The coming days will see hectic electoral politics. Please don't hit below the belt and don't rake up an issue which is a closed chapter," he said.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Pawar also said that the media was not as aggressive 25 years ago as it is now. "If a politician made a slip of tongue, the media would be forgiving back then," he said.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">He said recently he aired some personal views in an informal gathering for journalists at his bungalow, but the statements made "breaking news" even before the interaction ended. "Was it right to publicise something said in informal chat?" he asked.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">He was referring to his reported statement that he would not agree to become the Deputy Chief Minister if Prithviraj Chavan became the Chief Minister again.</span></p>]]></description>
			<dc:creator>Edited by Kirti Dwivedi | Updated: 5:45 IST</dc:creator>
			<pubDate>Sun, 21 Sep 2014 13:11:42 -0600</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.newsx.com/national/nation/item/26967-dont-hit-below-the-belt-rake-up-old-issue-ajit-pawar-says</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Massive rallies planned in front of UN, White House to welcome PM Modi</title>
			<link>http://www.newsx.com/national/nation/item/26966-massive-rallies-planned-in-front-of-un-white-house-to-welcome-pm-modi</link>
			<description><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/d1e0d93fd697745a775855fe6fc4b2a0_Generic.jpg"><img align="right" border="0" src="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/d1e0d93fd697745a775855fe6fc4b2a0_S.jpg" alt="massive-rallies-planned-in-front-of-un-white-house-to-welcome-pm-modi" /></a><font color="#ff3300"><b>Featured</b></font><p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Washington: Ahead of Prime Minister Narendra Modi's three-day visit to the US, hundreds of Indian-Americans from across the country have joined hands to give him a rousing welcome in front of the United Nations headquarters and the White House.</span></p>

<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">'America Welcomes Modi' rallies are being planned in front of the United Nations headquarters in New York on September 27, when Modi is to deliver his maiden address to the UN General Assembly.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The organisers are also preparing huge banners, posters and specially made T-shirts with slogans 'America Welcomes Modi', to be distributed among the participants.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Similarly in Washington DC, scores of Indian-Americans from the national Capital and from its suburbs in nearby Maryland and Virginia are preparing to hold welcome rallies in front of the White House on September 30, when Modi is scheduled to hold meeting with the US President Barack Obama, in his Oval Office.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">While the New York event is being organised by Indian American Intellectual Forum in association with several other organisations, the White House Rally has been planned by US India Democracy Forum.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"There is an unprecedented level of support for Modi in the US... Indian-Americans from as far as Chicago and Houston are flying to New York to welcome the Prime Minister in front of the United Nations when he delivers his address to the General Assembly," said Narain Kataria of the Indian American Intellectual Forum.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Kataria said Modi's supporters in Chicago have printed 'America Welcomes Modi' t-shirts, which would be distributed to the participants. A number of large posters and banners are also being printed for the participants to display it prominently during the event, expected to be attended by some 900 people.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Many of the participants would be wearing Modi masks, while two life-size cut outs of Modi would be put in display in front of the United Nations for people to take picture with their popular leader, Kataria said. Not everybody has been able to get a ticket for the public reception being hosted in honour of Modi, because of space constraints.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"This is our way of taking picture with Modi," he said.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Three days later a similar welcome rally is being planned in the Washington in front of the White House coinciding with the Modi-Obama meeting.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"Come celebrate the official 'US-India Partnership Day' on September 30. Join us for the festivities for recognition of this day by the US government," a flier of the event said.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Earlier this week, the US Senate had unanimously passed a resolution designating September 30 as 'US-India Partnership Day'.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">However, parallel to these welcome rallies, some groups have announced to hold protest rallies against Modi both outside the United Nations and in front of the White House.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">At both the places New York-based 'Sikhs For Justice' plans to hold protest rallies against the alleged violation of human rights in Punjab and Gujarat.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The Kashmir American Council (KAC) announced on Saturday to hold a candle light vigil in front of the White House on September 29 to remind Obama to fulfil his 2008 pledge to try and facilitate a better understanding between Pakistan and India, to resolve the Kashmir issue.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Meanwhile, in a letter to local authorities, the US India Democracy Forum have alleged that 'Sikhs for Justice' is trying to scuttle their welcome rally by stating that its anti-Modi rally would be attended by some 1300 people.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Since, the Lafayette Square Park has a capacity to accommodate only a certain number of people, if its application of a rally by 1300 people is granted permission, other groups would not be allowed to hold any rallies.</span></p>]]></description>
			<dc:creator>Edited by Kirti Dwivedi | Updated: 5:55 IST</dc:creator>
			<pubDate>Sun, 21 Sep 2014 12:54:29 -0600</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.newsx.com/national/nation/item/26966-massive-rallies-planned-in-front-of-un-white-house-to-welcome-pm-modi</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>PPA criticises BJP for excluding NE states during Xi Jinping’s visit</title>
			<link>http://www.newsx.com/national/nation/item/26965-ppa-criticises-bjp-for-excluding-ne-states-during-xi-jinpings-visit</link>
			<description><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/84c005a1f47a9e2676c761f92dc1fc4b_Generic.jpg"><img align="right" border="0" src="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/84c005a1f47a9e2676c761f92dc1fc4b_S.jpg" alt="ppa-criticises-bjp-for-excluding-ne-states-during-xi-jinpings-visit" /></a><font color="#ff3300"><b>Featured</b></font><p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Itanagar: The People's Party of Arunachal (PPA) on Sunday criticised the BJP-led NDA government at the Centre for "exclusion of people from the northeastern states during the visit of Chinese President Xi Jinping".</span></p>

<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The PPA, in a statement, said that the decision of the party in power had again proved its "racial attitude and segregation of the people" from the region.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"It is reported that Union MoS for Home Kiren Rijiju who, represents Arunachal Pradesh in Parliament, was also excluded from entire proceedings of talk and other programs," party president Nikh Kamin alleged.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Instead of segregation, during the visit of Chinese President, the focal point of dialogue should have been on border intrusions and Look East policy, opening of Stillwell Roads and Rijiju should have been allowed to play active role in entire discussion," he said.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The PPA while condemning the attitude of the Centre towards the people of the region, besides recent racial attack on a nurse from the state, demanded apology from the party in power, the statement said.</span></p>]]></description>
			<dc:creator>Edited by Kirti Dwivedi | Updated: 5:45 IST</dc:creator>
			<pubDate>Sun, 21 Sep 2014 12:15:50 -0600</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.newsx.com/national/nation/item/26965-ppa-criticises-bjp-for-excluding-ne-states-during-xi-jinpings-visit</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>BJP hopes seat-sharing with Shiv Sena can be mutually sorted out</title>
			<link>http://www.newsx.com/national/nation/item/26964-bjp-hopes-seat-sharing-with-shiv-sena-can-be-mutually-sorted-out</link>
			<description><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/559abb6dc799b6e1dce3148920162b6d_Generic.jpg"><img align="right" border="0" src="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/559abb6dc799b6e1dce3148920162b6d_S.jpg" alt="bjp-hopes-seat-sharing-with-shiv-sena-can-be-mutually-sorted-out" /></a><font color="#ff3300"><b>Featured</b></font><p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Mumbai: Squabbling over seat-sharing showed no signs of resolution today with the BJP saying there was "nothing new" in Shiv Sena's final offer to give it 119 seats for upcoming Maharashtra assembly polls and hoped it can be mutually settled.</span></p>

<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Hours after Uddhav Thackeray's tough talk in Mumbai on seat-sharing and that Sena cannot give beyond 119 seats, BJP told its old alliance partner that it was the duty of both the parties to continue the tie-up and sort out issues instead of going through the media, in remarks directed at the Sena chief.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The party also termed Thackeray's final offer to it as being "nothing new" as the BJP has been contesting on 119 seats eversince the alliance came into being.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Reacting cautiously, leaders of opposition in Maharashtra Assembly and Legislative Council Eknath Khadse and Vinod Tawde said here the party wants Sena to re-negotiate on such seats that they never won in the last 25 years, so that they are not given to the NCP-Congress alliance on a platter in the upcoming polls.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"There is nothing new in the latest Shiv Sena offer as BJP has been contesting 119 seats ever since the alliance came into being. We want the alliance to continue. It is the duty of both Shiv Sena and BJP to maintain the alliance.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"We have 25 year-old ties and seat-sharing issue can be sorted out mutually through face to face talks and not through media (TV)," Tawde told reporters in a hurriedly convened press conference.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Khadse said, "Shiv Sena has been losing on 35 seats while we have been losing on 19, if these were to be re allocated then we would all benefit instead of these seats going automatically to Congress-NCP alliance."</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"Many such seats had been lost by narrow margin in the previous elections. That was the thought and mindset behind the proposal for the 135 seats," he said.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">However, the BJP leaders also said they were ready to accept 130 seats—five seats down from its earlier demand.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Shiv Sena today made it clear that it won't make any more concession for BJP, offering to cede it only 119 out of the total 288 seats in Maharashtra Assembly for next month's polls, and said this was "the final attempt" to break the logjam over seat-sharing.</span></p>]]></description>
			<dc:creator>Edited by Kirti Dwivedi | Updated: 5:35 IST</dc:creator>
			<pubDate>Sun, 21 Sep 2014 11:55:23 -0600</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.newsx.com/national/nation/item/26964-bjp-hopes-seat-sharing-with-shiv-sena-can-be-mutually-sorted-out</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Maoist camp busted in Odisha and weapons seized</title>
			<link>http://www.newsx.com/regional/other-states/item/26963-maoist-camp-busted-in-odisha-and-weapons-seized</link>
			<description><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/44f437eb02653a00f4fdad5bed9e7d5d_Generic.jpg"><img align="right" border="0" src="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/44f437eb02653a00f4fdad5bed9e7d5d_S.jpg" alt="maoist-camp-busted-in-odisha-and-weapons-seized" /></a><font color="#ff3300"><b>Featured</b></font><p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">A Maoist camp was neutralised and some weapons as well as naxal literature were seized after a gun-battle with security forces in a forest in Odisha's Kandhamal district today, police said.</span></p>

<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The encounter took place during a joint combing operation by the Special Operation Group (SOG) and armed police in Bodasingha forest near Balandapada, said Kandhamal Superintendent of Police Kanwar Vishal Singh.</span></p>]]></description>
			<dc:creator>Edited by Kirti Dwivedi | Updated: 5:15 IST</dc:creator>
			<pubDate>Sun, 21 Sep 2014 11:42:37 -0600</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.newsx.com/regional/other-states/item/26963-maoist-camp-busted-in-odisha-and-weapons-seized</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>AAP's leader Mayank Gandhi booked for playing down molestation incident</title>
			<link>http://www.newsx.com/national/nation/item/26962-aaps-leader-mayank-gandhi-booked-for-playing-down-molestation-incident</link>
			<description><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/b7fca815ed8734995584a9f48947a0b3_Generic.jpg"><img align="right" border="0" src="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/b7fca815ed8734995584a9f48947a0b3_S.jpg" alt="aaps-leader-mayank-gandhi-booked-for-playing-down-molestation-incident" /></a><font color="#ff3300"><b>Featured</b></font><p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">MUMBAI: Aam Aadmi Party (AAP) leader Mayank Gandhi is among the six people booked here after a 21-year-old female party volunteer filed a criminal complaint against them, police said on Saturday.</span></p>

<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">While AAP activist Tarun Singh has been booked under section 354 (a) (sexual harassment), 506 (punishment for criminal intimidation), 509 (word, gesture or act intended to insult the modesty of a woman) of IPC, Gandhi and four others have been booked for abetting the crime, a police officer at Oshiwara police station said.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"The offence had occurred in April this year in suburban Oshiwara, ahead of Lok Sabha elections," said additional police commissioner Milind Bharambe.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"Based on the allegations levelled by the victim, an FIR was registered yesterday. The victim alleged that she brought to Gandhi's notice the sexual advancements of some party workers, but he did pay heed to them. And hence, she approached the local police who registered the FIR yesterday," Bharambe said.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Refuting the charge of abetting the crime, Gandhi described the complaint as "politically motivated".</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"When the female volunteer had complained to me against Tarun Singh saying he was harassing her, I pulled him up and immediately suspended him from the party. I asked the victim if she wanted to lodge an FIR against Tarun, but she refused," Gandhi told PTI.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">An internal committee of the party had been enquiring into the matter after it was reported to it, Gandhi said.</span></p>]]></description>
			<dc:creator>Edited by Kirti Dwivedi | Updated: 5:15 IST</dc:creator>
			<pubDate>Sun, 21 Sep 2014 11:26:57 -0600</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.newsx.com/national/nation/item/26962-aaps-leader-mayank-gandhi-booked-for-playing-down-molestation-incident</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>France asks India to finalize missile project soon</title>
			<link>http://www.newsx.com/national/defence/item/26961-france-asks-india-to-finalize-missile-project-soon</link>
			<description><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/baa78156802e633857d8ab8b26ef4249_Generic.jpg"><img align="right" border="0" src="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/baa78156802e633857d8ab8b26ef4249_S.jpg" alt="france-asks-india-to-finalize-missile-project-soon" /></a><font color="#ff3300"><b>Featured</b></font><p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">NEW DELHI: France has asked India for early finalisation of the long-pending Rs 30,000-crore project for joint production of short-range surface-to-air missile (SR-SAM) systems.</span></p>

<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">In a letter, the French defence ministry has told its Indian counterpart that "it will carry out substantial transfer of technology and know-how, especially in the field of missile guidance".</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The French side has proposed that the project "would enable India to get in a few years in areas of strategic missile, the maximum autonomy you have called for".</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">SR-SAM is proposed to be a joint venture between India and France and they have nominated the DRDO (Defence Research and Development Organisation) and a French multinational firm for the programme.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The deal has been under negotiations for over five years and has been awaiting final clearance after French President Francois Hollande and then Prime Minister Manmohan Singh in 2013 announced that talks have been concluded between both the sides on the missile development project.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The IAF had raised certain objections over the programme but the defence ministry has to take a final call on the programme after holding discussions with all stakeholders.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The French defence ministry said it wants to actively participate in new Indian government's plans to achieve autonomy in field of military hardware production.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">It has said that the missile programme would help in meeting India's domestic market and can also be supplied to future export markets.</span></p>]]></description>
			<dc:creator>Edited by Kirti Dwivedi | Updated: 4:45 IST</dc:creator>
			<pubDate>Sun, 21 Sep 2014 11:06:25 -0600</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.newsx.com/national/defence/item/26961-france-asks-india-to-finalize-missile-project-soon</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>PM Modi working on VoA facility on the anvil for US tourists</title>
			<link>http://www.newsx.com/national/nation/item/26960-pm-modi-working-on-voa-facility-on-the-anvil-for-us-tourists</link>
			<description><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/acf7b7c55b46fa3918347241eaedd0b2_Generic.jpg"><img align="right" border="0" src="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/acf7b7c55b46fa3918347241eaedd0b2_S.jpg" alt="pm-modi-working-on-voa-facility-on-the-anvil-for-us-tourists" /></a><font color="#ff3300"><b>Featured</b></font><p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">New Delhi: India is working on a proposal for Visa on Arrival (VoA) facility for US tourists, one of the big-ticket announcements expected to be made during Prime Minister Narendra Modi's high-profile visit to the US beginning September 26.</span></p>

<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The Ministry of Home Affairs is working overtime to finish the work on the VoA proposal to finalise it in time for the Prime Minister's visit, according to government sources.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">MHA in consultation with the Tourism ministry is working on the Tourist VoA under which visa can be granted to US citizens who do not have a residence or occupation in India and whose sole objective of visiting India would be recreation, sightseeing, casual visit to meet friends and relatives, etc, the sources said.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Under the new proposal, which is still being worked out, the stay limit is expected to be 30 days.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Initially, in January 2010 TvoA scheme was introduced for citizens of five countries and now, the facility is available for citizens of 11 countries -Finland, Japan, Luxembourg, New Zealand, Singapore, Cambodia, Vietnam, Philippines, Laos, Myanmar, Indonesia and South Korea.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">However, even despite being strategic partners, there is no TVoA facility for the citizens of India and the US in each other's country. As per some estimates, the annual flow of US tourists stand around 10 lakh, currently.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The Prime Minister will be on a five-day visit to the US during which he will address the UN General Assembly in New York and then travel to Washington where he would hold bilateral talks with US President Barack Obama, who invited Modi for a meeting during a call to wish him on his victory in the Lok Sabha polls nearly four months ago.</span></p>]]></description>
			<dc:creator>Edited by Kirti Dwivedi | Updated: 4:35 IST</dc:creator>
			<pubDate>Sun, 21 Sep 2014 10:59:59 -0600</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.newsx.com/national/nation/item/26960-pm-modi-working-on-voa-facility-on-the-anvil-for-us-tourists</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Bilawal one of the 'daydreamers' in Pakistan, Muslim League says</title>
			<link>http://www.newsx.com/national/nation/item/26959-bilawal-one-of-the-daydreamers-in-pakistan-muslim-league-says</link>
			<description><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/fb0fd5f5c47879af077374cf1cf2a6db_Generic.jpg"><img align="right" border="0" src="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/fb0fd5f5c47879af077374cf1cf2a6db_S.jpg" alt="bilawal-one-of-the-daydreamers-in-pakistan-muslim-league-says" /></a><font color="#ff3300"><b>Featured</b></font><p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">New Delhi: Indian Union Muslim League on Sunday dubbed Bilawal Bhutto Zardari as one of the "daydreamers" in Pakistan for his Kashmir remarks and said that every inch of Indian territory will be protected to the last minute.</span></p>

<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"The utterances of Pakistan's Opposition leader Bilawal Bhutto is nothing but to show he is also one of the daydreamers in Pakistan when he spoke that he will take every inch of Kashmir," E Ahamed, the Member of Parliament and the IUML chief, said in a statement.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Asserting that Jammu and Kashmir is an integral and inalienable part of India, Ahamed said: "entire India</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">especially 170 million Muslims will defend the integrity of the country for which last drop of blood will also be shed." He suggested Bilawal and others in Pakistan to do something for their own nation instead of living in daydreams.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"Muslims of India will never allow anybody to reduce the numerical strength of Muslim Population in India, and every inch of Indian Union will be protected to the last minute defending integrity, sovereignty and independence of our mother land," the former minister added.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Bilawal, who has announced plans to contest next general elections in 2018, heads the secular Pakistan People's Party which officially wants good ties with India.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Bilawal, considered the 'Gen-Next' politician of Pakistan, had told his party workers in Multan in Pakistan'sPunjab on Friday that PPP would get Kashmir back from India.</span></p>]]></description>
			<dc:creator>Edited by Kirti Dwivedi | Updated: 4:05 IST</dc:creator>
			<pubDate>Sun, 21 Sep 2014 10:18:47 -0600</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.newsx.com/national/nation/item/26959-bilawal-one-of-the-daydreamers-in-pakistan-muslim-league-says</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Diplomacy is not a take-away joint, Congress tells PM Modi</title>
			<link>http://www.newsx.com/national/nation/item/26958-diplomacy-is-not-a-take-away-joint-congress-tells-pm-modi</link>
			<description><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/719d9c68792122abf05f094b2e3c7c9e_Generic.jpg"><img align="right" border="0" src="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/719d9c68792122abf05f094b2e3c7c9e_S.jpg" alt="diplomacy-is-not-a-take-away-joint-congress-tells-pm-modi" /></a><font color="#ff3300"><b>Featured</b></font><p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">New Delhi: Criticising the Narendra Modi government's policy towards Pakistan and China, Congress on Sunday said diplomacy is not a "take away joint" and asked the Prime Minister to take the country into confidence before working on any "strategic alliance" with the US.</span></p>

<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Talking about Modi's foreign policy, Congress spokesperson and former External Affairs Minister Salman Khurshid said it is too early to pass a judgement one way or the other but "won't give high marks right away".</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"If you take handling of Pakistan, I think it is very clear that his impression was he would just say something and Pakistan would do it. That is not how diplomacy works. Pakistan is a difficult country. And Pakistan has given us lot of troubles and to expect that Pakistan will just click its heels and say... is not something you should have expected. You should have taken far greater care, far greater sense of planning," Khurshid said in a television interview.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">India had called off the Foreign Secretary level meeting with Pakistan after their High Commissioner to New Delhi Abdul Basit met with Kashmiri separatist leaders even though the Modi government had warned him against it.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Khurshid said he was amazed that the government did not think it would work out in this manner. "Should they have not anticipated? Should they not have considered that this is the likely move that Pakistan will make? We can't be caught off guard and then pretend that we are brave," he said.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The former minister said Modi thinks it is like going to a "take away joint and think that if you just put the cash there, you will get what you want". "It does not happen like that in diplomacy. Diplomacy is a far more complicated thing. Diplomacy is a far more strenuous thing and just to think that I can win an election in India and can win everybody across the globe... not so easy," Khurshid said.</span></p>]]></description>
			<dc:creator>Edited by Kirti Dwivedi | Updated: 3:45 IST</dc:creator>
			<pubDate>Sun, 21 Sep 2014 10:06:28 -0600</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.newsx.com/national/nation/item/26958-diplomacy-is-not-a-take-away-joint-congress-tells-pm-modi</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Floods damage 50 kms three-tier border fencing along LoC, IB in J&amp;K</title>
			<link>http://www.newsx.com/regional/j-k/item/26957-floods-damage-50-kms-three-tier-border-fencing-along-loc-ib-in-jk</link>
			<description><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/271a700d83eb8ce758a0a870eb6ef613_Generic.jpg"><img align="right" border="0" src="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/271a700d83eb8ce758a0a870eb6ef613_S.jpg" alt="floods-damage-50-kms-three-tier-border-fencing-along-loc-ib-in-jk" /></a><font color="#ff3300"><b>Featured</b></font><p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Udhampur: Over 50 km of the three-tier border fencing and flood-lighting have been damaged by the recent floods along the LoC and IB in Jammu and Kashmir and security forces are racing against time to repair it to prevent cross-border infiltration ahead of winters.</span></p>

<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">With the Army expressing apprehension that militants might take advantage of the situation and infiltrate, work is going on round-the-clock to plug in the gaps on the fencing.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"As many as 20 to 25 kms of border fencing has been damaged in various patches along the Line of Control in?Kashmir and Jammu regions during floods", a senior Army officer told PTI.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Similarly, a BSF officer put the damage caused to fencing along the IB in Jammu frontier to 14 to 15 km along with flood-lighting.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Jammu and Kashmir has 734 Kms of LoC running through Jammu, Kashmir and Ladakh regions from Kargil to Malu (Akhnoor) in Jammu district, while it has 190 Kms of International Border from Malu to Punjab belt running through Jammu, Samba and Kathua districts.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Anti-infiltration obstacle system (AIOS) has been deployed along 740 Kms along Indo-Pak border in Jammu and Kashmir.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Of these, 550 Kms of LoC has been fenced with flood-lighting along with 190 Kms of fenced IB.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">As Security forces battle floods to reach out to people for rescue and relief, the BSF and the Army are also racing against time to repair the damaged AIOS along LoC and IB to prevent cross-border infiltration from Pakistan ahead of winters.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Army Engineers with their men and machines are working round-the-clock to complete the task in the shortest possible time and they have been able to plug the critical gaps in AIOS.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"We are racing against time to repair and reconstruct the damage fencing. The fencing has been damaged in patches. Where ever it was critical we put it up within two to three days", the officer said.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"The balance work is going on a war-footing", the officer said.</span></p>]]></description>
			<dc:creator>Edited by Kirti Dwivedi | Updated: 3:25 IST</dc:creator>
			<pubDate>Sun, 21 Sep 2014 09:46:15 -0600</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.newsx.com/regional/j-k/item/26957-floods-damage-50-kms-three-tier-border-fencing-along-loc-ib-in-jk</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Saradha chitfund scam: CBI questions Chidambaram's wife</title>
			<link>http://www.newsx.com/national/nation/item/26956-saradha-chitfund-scam-cbi-questions-chidambarams-wife</link>
			<description><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/fb26cdf8e264b88b4fd2d311f4fd2813_Generic.jpg"><img align="right" border="0" src="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/fb26cdf8e264b88b4fd2d311f4fd2813_S.jpg" alt="saradha-chitfund-scam-cbi-questions-chidambarams-wife" /></a><font color="#ff3300"><b>Featured</b></font><p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">New Delhi: The CBI officials quizzed Nalini Chidambaram, wife of former union minister P Chidambaram in connection with the multi-crore Saradha chitfund scam, as per reports on Sunday.</span></p>

<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Nalini is the latest to join the list of prominent names which have been questioned by the CBI in the scam.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The CBI had earlier arrested a leader of West Bengal's ruling Trinamool Congress and former director general of the state armed police Rajat Majumdar in connection with the case.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">TMC's Raja Sabha MP, Srinjoy Bose, was also summoned and questioned by the CBI.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Majumdar had worked as a security advisor for the tainted Saradha Group after his retirement as a police officer in 2008.</span></p>]]></description>
			<dc:creator>Edited by Kirti Dwivedi | Updated: 3:15 IST</dc:creator>
			<pubDate>Sun, 21 Sep 2014 09:29:21 -0600</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.newsx.com/national/nation/item/26956-saradha-chitfund-scam-cbi-questions-chidambarams-wife</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Airlines oppose govt policy on connectivity to remote areas</title>
			<link>http://www.newsx.com/national/others-news/item/26955-airlines-oppose-govt-policy-on-connectivity-to-remote-areas</link>
			<description><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/fc82243b12b09ee30babb01d4567e75c_Generic.jpg"><img align="right" border="0" src="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/fc82243b12b09ee30babb01d4567e75c_S.jpg" alt="airlines-oppose-govt-policy-on-connectivity-to-remote-areas" /></a><font color="#ff3300"><b>Featured</b></font><p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Airlines and private charter operators have opposed the government's draft policy on air connectivity to regional and remote areas, saying it will have severe impact on their financial strength.</span></p>

<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Almost all major airlines, including the proposed Tata-SIA carrier Vistara, and business jet operators have submitted their opinions to the Civil Aviation Ministry over the past few days opposing various provisions of the draft policy, and called for further deliberations.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">To discuss the policy and other issues like high taxation on jet fuel with top airline officials, Civil Aviation Minister Ashok Gajapathi Raju has convened a meeting here next week, official sources said.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The revised draft policy on air connectivity to regional and remote areas was made public last month by the Ministry, which proposed a major shift in the route dispersal guidelines and promised several incentives and exemption from various charges to airlines which fly to such unconnected places.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Terming the state governments as major stakeholders in improving air connectivity in the hinterland, the policy asks them to take financial measures like slashing VAT on jet fuel and underwriting of some seats to encourage aviation growth.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">It also suggests that the state governments should waive electricity and municipal charges like house and property taxes for five years for airport infrastructure.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The draft proposes increase in the number of trunk routes from present 12 to 30 and identifies 87 regional "incentive destinations". It makes it mandatory for scheduled airlines to mount capacity "which is at least equal to the capacity deployed on trunk routes" by October 2015.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">In its submission, private airline Jet Airways said the policy requirement to deploy 100% of trunk route capacity on regional routes could cause overcapacity and hence this should be should be reduced to 50%.</span></p>]]></description>
			<dc:creator>Edited by Priyanka Kukreja || Updated: 14:50 IST</dc:creator>
			<pubDate>Sun, 21 Sep 2014 09:07:05 -0600</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.newsx.com/national/others-news/item/26955-airlines-oppose-govt-policy-on-connectivity-to-remote-areas</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Padmanabhaswamy temple audit to take 5-6 months: Vinod Rai</title>
			<link>http://www.newsx.com/national/nation/item/26954-padmanabhaswamy-temple-audit-to-take-5-6-months-vinod-rai</link>
			<description><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/59d3647a3f8272190f23ecb96b7b2ee4_Generic.jpg"><img align="right" border="0" src="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/59d3647a3f8272190f23ecb96b7b2ee4_S.jpg" alt="padmanabhaswamy-temple-audit-to-take-5-6-months-vinod-rai" /></a><font color="#ff3300"><b>Featured</b></font><p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">New Delhi: The special audit of the properties of Kerala's famous Sree Padmanabhaswamy temple, which is facing allegations of financial irregularities, is expected to be completed in the next five to six months.</span></p>

<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Former CAG Vinod Rai, who has been tasked with a special audit of the temple's properties, also said that the team is getting a lot of co-operation from the temple's trust as well as the administration.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"It will go on for about five or six months more at least," Rai in response to a query on when the final audit report is expected to be completed.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The Supreme Court, in April this year, had asked Rai to supervise this special audit.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"... One thing that is good is happening is that we are getting a lot of co-operation. Audit is not difficult to the extent that records are available," Rai, who had served as Comptroller and Auditor General (CAG) from 2008-13, said.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Rai, a retired IAS officer from Kerala cadre, also noted that people have full faith in the temple and its deity.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"Anything that is said connected to the deity, people tend to believe. That is why there is lot of faith about one particular vault (Kallara B) and there is lot of superstition about it.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"We don't have any direction from the Supreme Court on whether it should be opened or not as yet. But to a large extent there is a certain degree of strength in people's superstitions, people's beliefs and that is the belief which has built up the image of that deity, that it is a very powerful deity," Rai said.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">In his report, submitted to the Supreme Court earlier this year, senior advocate Gopal Subramaniam had highlighted several serious irregularities in the management of the temple and its wealth.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The temple has six vaults, most of which are underground and are filled with priceless articles. During preparation of its inventory by the apex court-appointed panel, five of these vaults were opened, leaving out one chamber, called 'vault (Kallara) B'.</span></p>]]></description>
			<dc:creator>Edited by Priyanka Kukreja || Updated: 14:40 IST</dc:creator>
			<pubDate>Sun, 21 Sep 2014 08:58:11 -0600</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.newsx.com/national/nation/item/26954-padmanabhaswamy-temple-audit-to-take-5-6-months-vinod-rai</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>PM Modi greets Japanese counterpart on his birthday</title>
			<link>http://www.newsx.com/national/nation/item/26953-pm-modi-greets-japanese-counterpart-on-his-birthday</link>
			<description><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/297cacee8d2f7847cf1bdcf5906f5bac_Generic.jpg"><img align="right" border="0" src="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/297cacee8d2f7847cf1bdcf5906f5bac_S.jpg" alt="pm-modi-greets-japanese-counterpart-on-his-birthday" /></a><font color="#ff3300"><b>Featured</b></font><p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">New Delhi: Prime Minister Narendra Modi on Sunday wished his Japanese counterpart Shinzo Abe on his birthday and said that both of them are committed to taking India-Japan ties to the next level.</span></p>

<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"Wishing @AbeShinzo a Happy Birthday! I pray for his long life, good health &amp; wish him the best in leading Japan to new heights of progress," the Prime Minister tweeted.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Recalling his interactions with the Japanese Prime Minister, Modi said, "Whenever I interact with @AbeShinzo, I cannot but marvel at his insight &amp; expertise on a wide range of issues, both local &amp; international."</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"Both PM @AbeShinzo &amp; I are committed to taking India- Japan relations to the next level &amp; contributing to global peace &amp; development," he said.</span><br /><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Modi, who turned 64 on September 17, had received a call from Abe who wished him on his birthday, in a reflection of the special bonding the two Prime Ministers enjoy.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The Prime Minister visited Japan only in the beginning of this month and the warmth between the two leaders was at display during that time.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Separately, Modi also congratulated New Zealand Prime Minister John Key and his National Party for winning the general election held yesterday.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"Congratulations to @johnkeypm &amp; the NZ National Party for the victory in the General Election," Modi tweeted.</span></p>]]></description>
			<dc:creator>Edited by Priyanka Kukreja || Updated: 14:20 IST</dc:creator>
			<pubDate>Sun, 21 Sep 2014 08:45:47 -0600</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.newsx.com/national/nation/item/26953-pm-modi-greets-japanese-counterpart-on-his-birthday</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Big rallies planned in front of UN, White House to welcome PM Modi</title>
			<link>http://www.newsx.com/world/us/item/26952-big-rallies-planned-in-front-of-un-white-house-to-welcome-pm-modi</link>
			<description><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/0f853930c6361607b829759511c585f5_Generic.jpg"><img align="right" border="0" src="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/0f853930c6361607b829759511c585f5_S.jpg" alt="big-rallies-planned-in-front-of-un-white-house-to-welcome-pm-modi" /></a><font color="#ff3300"><b>Featured</b></font><p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Washington: Ahead of Prime Minister Narendra Modi's three-day visit to the US, hundreds of Indian-Americans from across the country have joined hands to give him a rousing welcome in front of the United Nations headquarters and the White House.</span></p>

<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">'America Welcomes Modi' rallies are being planned in front of the United Nations headquarters in New York on September 27, when Modi is to deliver his maiden address to the UN General Assembly.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The organisers are also preparing huge banners, posters and specially made T-shirts with slogans 'America Welcomes Modi', to be distributed among the participants.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Similarly in Washington DC, scores of Indian-Americans from the national Capital and from its suburbs in nearby Maryland and Virginia are preparing to hold welcome rallies in front of the White House on September 30, when Modi is scheduled to hold meeting with the US President Barack Obama, in his Oval Office.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">While the New York event is being organised by Indian American Intellectual Forum in association with several other organisations, the White House Rally has been planned by US India Democracy Forum.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"There is an unprecedented level of support for Modi in the US... Indian-Americans from as far as Chicago and Houston are flying to New York to welcome the Prime Minister in front of the United Nations when he delivers his address to the General Assembly," said Narain Kataria of the Indian American Intellectual Forum.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Kataria said Modi's supporters in Chicago have printed 'America Welcomes Modi' t-shirts, which would be distributed to the participants. A number of large posters and banners are also being printed for the participants to display it prominently during the event, expected to be attended by some 900 people.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Many of the participants would be wearing Modi masks, while two life-size cut outs of Modi would be put in display in front of the United Nations for people to take picture with their popular leader, Kataria said. Not everybody has been able to get a ticket for the public reception being hosted in honour of Modi, because of space constraints.</span></p>]]></description>
			<dc:creator>Edited by Priyanka Kukreja || Updated: 13:30 IST</dc:creator>
			<pubDate>Sun, 21 Sep 2014 07:54:40 -0600</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.newsx.com/world/us/item/26952-big-rallies-planned-in-front-of-un-white-house-to-welcome-pm-modi</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>#BJPSenaMahaWar Live: Shiv Sena Chief Uddhav Thackeray addresses party workers in Mumbai</title>
			<link>http://www.newsx.com/component/k2/item/26951-#bjpsenamahawar-live-shiv-sena-chief-uddhav-thackeray-addresses-party-workers-in-mumbai&amp;Itemid=916</link>
			<description><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/12fb72d9c34220658319954a594fa4e6_Generic.jpg"><img align="right" border="0" src="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/12fb72d9c34220658319954a594fa4e6_S.jpg" alt="#bjpsenamahawar-live-shiv-sena-chief-uddhav-thackeray-addresses-party-workers-in-mumbai" /></a><font color="#ff3300"><b>Featured</b></font><p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Sena Chief Uddhav Thackeray made a final offer to BJP of 151-119 seats in a public address in Mumbai even as he served an ultimatum and said, "We are making last effort to save the alliance."</span></p>

<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">According to the final formula, Shiv Sena will contest 151 seats, BJP 119 while 18 seats will be left for others.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Here are the live updates:</span></strong></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">• If alliance breaks, it will hurt me. Our list of cadidates is ready and give declare it anytime, says Sena Chief</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">• The idea behind alliance was not to be in power but to give a justice to people, says Thackeray in the party meeting</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">• After Godhra riots, LK Advani had called on Balasaheb Thackreray to seek his advise after public demand to remove Narendra Modi. It was Balasaheb Thackeray, who stood by Modi and said he should not be removed.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">• "This is the only unique alliance in the world that has happened for the sake of the Hindutva philosophy," Uddhav Thackeray said.</span></p>
<p><iframe src="//www.youtube.com/embed/EIEdAoTDjeM" frameborder="0" width="684" height="415" allowfullscreen="true" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"></iframe></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">• “We have to come back to power; the dream of Balasaheb Thackeray cannot be left unfullfilled. I don't just speak; I act on what I say”, says Sena Chief</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">• We are making last effort to save the alliance, says Uddhav Thackeray</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">• Many faces have been unmasked during polls time, have taken a decision, will announce it soon, says Uddhav Thackeray</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">• Party workers have given me authority to take a decision and I'll do it with responsibility, keeping everything in mind, says Shiv Sena Chief Uddhav Thackeray</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">• I will take the decision with responsibility, keeping everything in mind, says ShivSena Chief Uddhav Thackeray</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">• Next month, it will be a saffron Diwali in Maharashtra, says Sena Chief Uddhav Thackeray in the meeting</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">• It's time to fight alone, not ride on any 'Wave', says Shiv Sena in the meeting on seat sharing.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">• Shiv Sena leaders declare intent to fight polls alone.</span></p>]]></description>
			<dc:creator>NewsX Bureau</dc:creator>
			<pubDate>Sun, 21 Sep 2014 07:28:59 -0600</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.newsx.com/component/k2/item/26951-#bjpsenamahawar-live-shiv-sena-chief-uddhav-thackeray-addresses-party-workers-in-mumbai&amp;Itemid=916</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>#BJPSenaMahaWar: BJP rejects Shiv Sena’s offer of 125 seats on Maharashtra seat sharing</title>
			<link>http://www.newsx.com/component/k2/item/26950-#bjpsenamahawar-bjp-rejects-shiv-sena’s-final-offer-of-125-seats-on-maharashtra-seat-sharing&amp;Itemid=916</link>
			<description><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/2746aed5b4d0552cceb1dbdf2249b79a_Generic.jpg"><img align="right" border="0" src="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/2746aed5b4d0552cceb1dbdf2249b79a_S.jpg" alt="#bjpsenamahawar-bjp-rejects-shiv-sena’s-final-offer-of-125-seats-on-maharashtra-seat-sharing" /></a><font color="#ff3300"><b>Featured</b></font><p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The BJP-Shiv Sena alliance of over 25 years is on the verge of a collapse after the BJP has rejected the fresh offer made by the Sena over allocation of seats for the Assembly Polls. Rejecting the Sena's seat-sharing formula, BJP said that it leaves less number of seats in its kitty.</span></p>

<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The BJP and the Sena have seen a flurry of talks between its top leaders over seat-sharing but none of it has resulted in anything concrete. However, both the parties have reiterated that the alliance is important to them but it will not come at the cost of self-respect. But the latest is the BJP terming the Sena's offer as unacceptable.</span></p>
<p><iframe src="//www.youtube.com/embed/B4OiRkvmHoA" frameborder="0" width="684" height="415" allowfullscreen="true" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"></iframe></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">After the BJP’s public refusal of the Shiv Sena’s final offer of 125 seats including the smaller allies, the Shiv Sena has now gone into a huddle. Sena Chief Uddhav Thackeray and son Aditya Thackeray present at the meeting attended by Subhash Desai, Sanjay Raut, Anil Desai and Diwakar Raote.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Sources had said that Sena wants to contest 155 of the 288 seats in the assembly and suggested that the BJP contest 125, ten less than it has reportedly demanded.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">BJP leaders meet once again over the Maharashtra seat sharing at the party headquarters at 24, Akbar Road. BJP president Amit Shah is meeting senior leaders Ram Lal and JP Nadda, Senior Maharashtra BJP leaders also present.</span></p>]]></description>
			<dc:creator>NewsX Bureau</dc:creator>
			<pubDate>Sun, 21 Sep 2014 07:09:11 -0600</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.newsx.com/component/k2/item/26950-#bjpsenamahawar-bjp-rejects-shiv-sena’s-final-offer-of-125-seats-on-maharashtra-seat-sharing&amp;Itemid=916</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>NewsX Exclusive Interview with former Maharashtra Chief Minister Ashok Chavan</title>
			<link>http://www.newsx.com/interviews/item/26949-newsx-exclusive-interview-with-former-maharashtra-chief-minister-ashok-chavan</link>
			<description><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/caaef367f0d2d23f5f25c58a3094ebcb_Generic.jpg"><img align="right" border="0" src="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/caaef367f0d2d23f5f25c58a3094ebcb_S.jpg" alt="newsx-exclusive-interview-with-former-maharashtra-chief-minister-ashok-chavan" /></a><font color="#ff3300"><b>Featured</b></font><p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The Congress is ready to contest alone in the assembly polls in an exclusive interview to NewsX former Maharashtra Chief Minister Ashok Chavan says the party is not afraid to go solo</span></p>

<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><iframe src="//www.youtube.com/embed/OFGwZmFvv5M" frameborder="0" width="684" height="415" allowfullscreen="true" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"></iframe></p>]]></description>
			<dc:creator>NewsX Bureau</dc:creator>
			<pubDate>Sun, 21 Sep 2014 06:54:24 -0600</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.newsx.com/interviews/item/26949-newsx-exclusive-interview-with-former-maharashtra-chief-minister-ashok-chavan</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>UPSC shifts NDA &amp; NA exam centre from Srinagar to Jammu</title>
			<link>http://www.newsx.com/regional/j-k/item/26948-upsc-shifts-nda--na-exam-centre-from-srinagar-to-jammu</link>
			<description><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/bf5ffaae3156bd858f444a647575f188_Generic.jpg"><img align="right" border="0" src="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/bf5ffaae3156bd858f444a647575f188_S.jpg" alt="upsc-shifts-nda--na-exam-centre-from-srinagar-to-jammu" /></a><font color="#ff3300"><b>Featured</b></font><p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">New Delhi: All candidates who had opted for Srinagar centre to appear in the National Defence Academy (NDA) and Naval Academy (NA) examination will now have to take the test from Jammu, Union Public Service Commission (UPSC) has said.</span></p>

<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The NDA and NA Examination (II) is scheduled to be held on September 28.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"The candidates of NDA &amp; NA Examination(II), 2014 who have opted for Srinagar as their examination centre are informed that the Government of Jammu and Kashmir has intimated that almost all the educational institutions in the city are submerged or marooned," UPSC said.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Based on the considered advice of the state government, the Commission has decided to cancel the Srinagar Centre and accommodate all the candidates at Jammu centre, it said.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Heavy rains has led to floods in Jammu and Kashmir which has so far claimed lives of at least 277 people and rendered thousands homeless.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The candidates who were allotted Government S P Higher Secondary School, Maulana Azad Road, Srinagar, are advised to reach Government M A M College, University Road, Jammu to appear in the NDA and NA (II) examination, it said.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The candidates, who have not been able to download their e-admit cards due to disruption in Internet facilities in Srinagar, may collect it from the venue supervisor preferably on September 27 from 10 AM to 5 PM or on September 28 during 8 AM to 9 AM to get entry into examination premises.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The candidates may also take note of the fact that the examination is scheduled from 10 AM to 12.30 PM (Paper I mathematics) and from 2 PM to 4.30 PM (Paper II General Ability Test) on September 28, UPSC said.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The NDA and NA exam is conducted to select officers for Army and Navy.</span></p>]]></description>
			<dc:creator>Edited by Priyanka Kukreja || Updated: 12:20 IST</dc:creator>
			<pubDate>Sun, 21 Sep 2014 06:44:30 -0600</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.newsx.com/regional/j-k/item/26948-upsc-shifts-nda--na-exam-centre-from-srinagar-to-jammu</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Ishrat case: court allows 2 accused cops to go outside Gujarat</title>
			<link>http://www.newsx.com/regional/gujarat/item/26947-ishrat-case-court-allows-2-accused-cops-to-go-outside-gujarat</link>
			<description><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/591b5ddca40e0c029eea8e04a8bad82b_Generic.jpg"><img align="right" border="0" src="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/591b5ddca40e0c029eea8e04a8bad82b_S.jpg" alt="ishrat-case-court-allows-2-accused-cops-to-go-outside-gujarat" /></a><font color="#ff3300"><b>Featured</b></font><p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Ahmedabad: The special CBI court here today allowed the applications of two police officers, who are accused in the Ishrat Jahan fake encounter case, seeking modification of their bail conditions which bar them from leaving Gujarat.</span></p>

<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Judge Geeta Gopi allowed the pleas of IPS officers G L Singhal and Anaju Chaudhary, though CBI opposed it saying they may abscond if allowed go outside Gujarat or tamper with evidence.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">But advocate Brijrajsinh Jhala, the accused officers' lawyer, submitted that they were not seeking to leave the country and most witnesses in the case are police officers who live in Gujarat.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Ishrat Jahan, Javed Sheikh, Zeeshan Johar and Amjad Ali Rana were killed by a team of the city crime branch on Ahmedabad-Gandhinagar road on June 15, 2004. According to CBI, it was a fake encounter.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Singhal was reinstated in service in May this year as a group commandant in the State Reserve Police.</span></p>]]></description>
			<dc:creator>Edited by Priyanka Kukreja || Updated: 12:00 IST</dc:creator>
			<pubDate>Sun, 21 Sep 2014 06:23:15 -0600</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.newsx.com/regional/gujarat/item/26947-ishrat-case-court-allows-2-accused-cops-to-go-outside-gujarat</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Replacement of Planning Commission still under consideration</title>
			<link>http://www.newsx.com/national/nation/item/26946-replacement-of-planning-commission-still-under-consideration</link>
			<description><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/d29f389d48f49462ce3a3df2a72de319_Generic.jpg"><img align="right" border="0" src="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/d29f389d48f49462ce3a3df2a72de319_S.jpg" alt="replacement-of-planning-commission-still-under-consideration" /></a><font color="#ff3300"><b>Featured</b></font><p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">New Delhi: The proposal to replace Planning Commission with a new body, as announced by Prime Minister Narendra Modi, is "still under consideration" of the central government.</span></p>

<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">In reply to an RTI query, the Planning Commission said the final decision, as and when it is taken, on its replacement will be put in public domain.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The Planning Commission was asked to provide detail of its meetings with officials of the Prime Minister's Office (PMO) in this regard, copy of minutes of such meetings, and name, structure, address and mandate of the proposed body.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"The proposal (to replace Planning Commission with a new body) is still under consideration with the government... As and when the final decision is taken by the government of India, the same will be placed in the public domain," the plan panel said in its reply to the RTI application filed.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The Prime Minister is the Chairman of the Planning Commission, which works under the overall guidance of the National Development Council, according to its present mandate. The Deputy Chairman and the full-time members of the Commission, as a composite body, provide advice and guidance for the formulation of Five Year Plans, annual plans, state plans and monitoring plan programmes among others.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">In his Independence Day speech, Modi had announced that a new institution with a new soul will replace the Planning Commission.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The new body will lead the country based on creative thinking, public-private partnership, optimum utilisation of resources, utilisation of youth power of the nation, to promote the aspirations of state governments seeking development, to empower the state governments and to empower the federal structure, he had said.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"Very shortly, we are about to move in a direction when this institute would be functioning in place of Planning Commission," Modi had said.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The Congress had opposed the government's move, terming it a "knee-jerk and half-baked decision" and favoured a "restructuring instead of dismantling" of the panel.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Later on his Twitter posts, Modi had invited suggestions from people on the proposed body to replace the plan panel.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"Inviting you to share your ideas on what shape the new institution to replace the Planning Commission can take," he had tweeted.</span></p>]]></description>
			<dc:creator>Edited by Priyanka Kukreja || Updated: 11:35 IST</dc:creator>
			<pubDate>Sun, 21 Sep 2014 05:56:20 -0600</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.newsx.com/national/nation/item/26946-replacement-of-planning-commission-still-under-consideration</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Those under preventive detention have right to vote: EC</title>
			<link>http://www.newsx.com/national/nation/item/26945-those-under-preventive-detention-have-right-to-vote-ec</link>
			<description><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/ab747942ef5d6c3f38181f04a96d3f68_Generic.jpg"><img align="right" border="0" src="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/ab747942ef5d6c3f38181f04a96d3f68_S.jpg" alt="those-under-preventive-detention-have-right-to-vote-ec" /></a><font color="#ff3300"><b>Featured</b></font><p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">New Delhi: People under preventive detention have the right to vote, the Election Commission has said ahead of Assembly elections in Maharashtra and Haryana, and warned that there should be "no ground" for any grievance due to non-compliance of the directive.</span></p>

<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Against the backdrop of allegations that political activists and leaders are being detained by police ahead of elections, the EC has written to the Chief Secretaries of Maharashtra and Haryana, reminding them of Section 62 (5) of the Representation of the People Act and the Conduct of Election Rules that specify that those in preventive detention are entitled to cast their votes by post.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The letter referred to the provisions in the Conduct of Election Rules under which the administration has to intimate the Returning Officer of each constituency the names of electors under preventive detention, along with their addresses, electoral roll numbers so that postal ballots can be sent to them to facilitate them exercise their franchise in the elections.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"... Instructions may kindly be issued to the concerned authorities to ensure that provisions...Are strictly complied with at the general elections and there is no ground for any grievance on account of non-compliance of the provision of the said (Conduct of Election) rule," the EC has said.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Seeking to remove any ambiguity, it said in case the authorities are not aware of the address of the Returning Officer of a detainee's constituency, they should send the details to the Chief Electoral Officer (CEO).</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">In another letter issued to all CEOs, the EC has asked all state police chiefs to ensure that junior level police officials are not allowed to misuse power to deter a political activist to campaign for his or her leader or political party during elections.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">It referred to a recent order of the Patna High Court which said that an official attached to a police station misused his powers to deter a person from campaigning in polls by threatening him with legal action.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">It asked all DGPs and CEOs to ensure that no "indirect restrictions" are placed on campaigning during electioneering.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Assembly elections will be held in Maharashtra and Haryana in a single phase on October 15 and counting of votes will take place on October 19.</span></p>]]></description>
			<dc:creator>Edited by Priyanka Kukreja || Updated: 11:25 IST</dc:creator>
			<pubDate>Sun, 21 Sep 2014 05:44:12 -0600</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.newsx.com/national/nation/item/26945-those-under-preventive-detention-have-right-to-vote-ec</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Soon order food of your choice through SMS onboard train</title>
			<link>http://www.newsx.com/national/nation/item/26944-soon-order-food-of-your-choice-through-sms-onboard-train</link>
			<description><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/c7229d688824719a1933caf8d2dabe94_Generic.jpg"><img align="right" border="0" src="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/c7229d688824719a1933caf8d2dabe94_S.jpg" alt="soon-order-food-of-your-choice-through-sms-onboard-train" /></a><font color="#ff3300"><b>Featured</b></font><p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">New Delhi: Soon you can order meals of your taste through SMS while travelling on a train as Railways is launching a mobile phone-based service in a move to offer multiple catering options to passengers.</span></p>

<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The SMS-based service, part of the e-catering service, will be launched on September 25 in a few selected trains on on a pilot basis, said a senior Railway Ministry official.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">IRCTC, which is coordinating the e-catering service, is finalising a new designated number to be used for SMS service for ordering food on a train.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Plagued with complaints, Railways has stepped up efforts to improve catering services on trains.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"Our aim is to provide multiple choices to passengers. While the existing service of getting food from pantry cars will continue, the SMS-based service is also being offered to passengers," the official said.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">According to the plan, a passenger will get response from a dedicated team after sending the SMS mentioning his PNR number.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"The passenger will get call after the due online verification of the PNR status and berth position in the particular train seeking details of food order. Payments will be made after the delivery," he said.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">While SMS-based service is being launched, Railways is also finalising a plan to start online order system where a passenger can also book his food online.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Arrangements have been made with some reputed food chains and eating joints for providing food through SMS-based orders on trains, the official said, adding "the online order system will also be launched shortly".</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Recently, Railways had started providing ready-to-eat packaged food in certain trains on a trial basis offering variety of choices to passengers.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The ready-to-eat food service got a good response and now we are planning to formulate a policy on it by roping in more players, the official said.</span></p>]]></description>
			<dc:creator>Edited by Priyanka Kukreja || Updated: 1:15 IST</dc:creator>
			<pubDate>Sun, 21 Sep 2014 05:30:26 -0600</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.newsx.com/national/nation/item/26944-soon-order-food-of-your-choice-through-sms-onboard-train</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Childhood abuse leads to obesity in adult women</title>
			<link>http://www.newsx.com/life-style/health/item/26943-childhood-abuse-leads-to-obesity-in-adult-women</link>
			<description><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/94ac37efb44914a0182a5a20e346cfe2_Generic.jpg"><img align="right" border="0" src="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/94ac37efb44914a0182a5a20e346cfe2_S.jpg" alt="childhood-abuse-leads-to-obesity-in-adult-women" /></a><font color="#ff3300"><b>Featured</b></font><p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Women who were physically abused during childhood are more likely to be obese, a new study has revealed.</span></p>

<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">University of Toronto researchers indicated that women who were physically abused in childhood were more likely to be obese than women from non-abusive homes.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"After adjusting for age and race, childhood physical abuse was associated with 47% higher odds of obesity for women" lead author Esme Fuller-Thomson, Professor and Sandra Rotman Endowed Chair in the University of Toronto's Factor-Inwentash Faculty of Social Work, said.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"Among men, obesity wasn't associated with childhood physical abuse," the researcher said.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"We had anticipated that the association between childhood physical abuse and obesity among women would be explained by factors including depression and anxiety, adult socio-economic position, alcohol abuse, and other childhood adversities, such as having a parent addicted to drugs or alcohol," study co-author and doctoral student Deborah Sinclair, said.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"However, even after taking into account all these factors, women from physically abusive families still had 35 per cent higher odds of obesity," she said.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The study could not determine the reason for the relationship between childhood physical abuse and women's obesity.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"It is unclear why childhood physical abuse is associated with adult obesity among women but not men; it may reflect gender differences in coping mechanisms," study co-author and doctoral candidate Sarah Brennenstuhl, said.</span></p>]]></description>
			<dc:creator>Edited by Priyanka Kukreja || Updated: 10:55 IST</dc:creator>
			<pubDate>Sun, 21 Sep 2014 05:20:12 -0600</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.newsx.com/life-style/health/item/26943-childhood-abuse-leads-to-obesity-in-adult-women</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>DDA allows conversion of property through GPA, registered agreement</title>
			<link>http://www.newsx.com/cities/item/26942-dda-allows-conversion-of-property-through-gpa-registered-agreement</link>
			<description><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/651755849344d24c93eb506e14737955_Generic.jpg"><img align="right" border="0" src="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/651755849344d24c93eb506e14737955_S.jpg" alt="dda-allows-conversion-of-property-through-gpa-registered-agreement" /></a><font color="#ff3300"><b>Featured</b></font><p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">New Delhi: The DDA has decided to allow the conversion of property from leasehold to freehold on the basis of registered agreement to sell and general power of attorney, which was earlier suspended by a Supreme Court judgement.</span></p>

<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"The Competent Authority in Delhi Development Authority (DDA) after taking the opinion of Solicitor General, has decided to allow such conversions subject to producing documents authenticating that the transaction is genuine," the DDA said in a statement.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The conversion had been suspended in the wake of a Supreme Court judgement in a case in 2011, it said.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The genuineness would be verified at the time of processing of conversion application and subject to production of related documents such as agreement to sell registered with sub-registrar of Delhi.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">On verification of these documents the lease administrating agencies of DDA i.E. Land Disposal Wing and Housing Wing would process the conversion applications subject to completion of all other codal formalities as laid in conversion brochure, the urban housing body said.</span></p>]]></description>
			<dc:creator>Edited by Priyanka Kukreja || Updated: 10:35 IST</dc:creator>
			<pubDate>Sun, 21 Sep 2014 04:59:22 -0600</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.newsx.com/cities/item/26942-dda-allows-conversion-of-property-through-gpa-registered-agreement</guid>
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
