<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet href="http://www.newsx.com/components/com_obrss/assets/xsl/atom-to-html.xsl" type="text/xsl"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
	<channel>
		<title>rss</title>
		<description><![CDATA[RSS Feed]]></description>
		<link>http://www.newsx.com/</link>
		<lastBuildDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2014 04:57:30 -0600</lastBuildDate>
		<generator>FeedCreator 1.8.3 (obRSS 1.9)</generator>
		<atom:link href="http://www.newsx.com/component/obrss/rss?format=" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
		<image>
			<url>http://www.newsx.com/images/</url>
			<title>rss</title>
			<link>http://www.newsx.com/</link>
			<description>RSS Feed</description>
		</image>
		<item>
			<title>#PMTurns64: Prime Minister Narendra Modi seeks blessings of his mother as he turns 64 today</title>
			<link>http://www.newsx.com/national/top-stories/item/26769-modi-turns-64-meets-mother-to-seek-blessings</link>
			<description><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/efbe03e411653d08b72f25f3babce6ef_Generic.jpg"><img align="right" border="0" src="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/efbe03e411653d08b72f25f3babce6ef_S.jpg" alt="modi-turns-64-meets-mother-to-seek-blessings" /></a><font color="#ff3300"><b>Featured</b></font><p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Prime Minister of India Narendra Modi turns 64 today and he met his mother Heeraben in Gandhinagar to seek her blessings. This is the first birthday of Narendra Modi after taking over the position of Prime Minister of India.</span></p>

<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">On the special day of her son’s birthday, the proud mother according to the sources donated Rs. 5, 000 for the Prime Minister’s Relief Fund for Jammu and Kashmir.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">According to the sources, PM Modi went to Gandhinagar, 23 km ahead from Ahmedabad alone in his normal sense without taking any support of his security guards to accompany him.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">&nbsp;</span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 10pt;"><iframe src="//www.youtube.com/embed/q4S-jmBHKfA" frameborder="0" width="684" height="415" allowfullscreen="true" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"></iframe></span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">His Japanese counterpart Shinzo Abe and President Pranab Mukherjee as well called the Indian PM to extend their good wishes to him on the special day.</span></span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">PM Modi had paid a visit to Japan only a fortnight back and the warmness between the two leaders was put on show at that time.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Apart from President Mukherjee, Vice President Hamid Ansari also wished him.</span></p>]]></description>
			<dc:creator>Written by Charnamrit Sachdeva</dc:creator>
			<pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2014 03:22:01 -0600</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.newsx.com/national/top-stories/item/26769-modi-turns-64-meets-mother-to-seek-blessings</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Iran's current uranium enrichment not acceptable: US</title>
			<link>http://www.newsx.com/world/us/item/26768-irans-current-uranium-enrichment-not-acceptable-us</link>
			<description><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/913cb88730ec007ec60bba635b128854_Generic.jpg"><img align="right" border="0" src="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/913cb88730ec007ec60bba635b128854_S.jpg" alt="irans-current-uranium-enrichment-not-acceptable-us" /></a><font color="#ff3300"><b>Featured</b></font><p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Washington: Iran cannot convince the world that its current ability to enrich uranium is acceptable, the top US negotiator said Tuesday ahead of new nuclear talks with global powers.</span></p>

<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">After months of intense negotiations the two sides have "identified potential answers to some key questions," Under Secretary of State Wendy Sherman said in a speech at an award-giving ceremony at Georgetown University.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">But she warned "we remain far apart on other core issues, including the size and scope of Iran`s uranium enrichment capacity."</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">As Iran and world powers prepare for new talks starting on Thursday in New York, Sherman said she expected the Islamic Republic "will try to convince the world that on this pivotal matter, the status quo ... should be acceptable."</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"It is not," Sherman stressed, as she was given a top award for distinction in the conduct of diplomacy.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"If it were, we wouldn`t be involved in this difficult and very painstaking negotiation."</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The five permanent members of the UN Security Council plus Germany (the P5+1) want Iran to scale down its nuclear activities to make any breakout move to manufacture a bomb extremely difficult.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">In return Tehran, which denies wanting nuclear weapons and says a peaceful atomic program is its right, wants the lifting of tough UN and Western sanctions.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">But Sherman stressed: "The world will agree to suspend and lift sanctions only if Iran takes convincing and verifiable steps to show that its nuclear program is and will remain entirely peaceful.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"We must be confident that any effort by Tehran to break out of its obligations will be so visible and time-consuming that the attempt would have no chance of success."</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Sherman insisted the ideas that the US and its allies have put forward in the hopes of reaching a deal by a November 24 deadline were "fair, flexible and consistent with Iran`s civilian nuclear needs and scientific knowhow."</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The talks in New York will be at the level of political directors. But foreign ministers from Iran and the six powers, present in New York for the UN General Assembly will likely also meet some time next week.</span></p>]]></description>
			<dc:creator>Edited by Priyanka Kukreja || Updated  8:40 IST</dc:creator>
			<pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2014 03:05:27 -0600</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.newsx.com/world/us/item/26768-irans-current-uranium-enrichment-not-acceptable-us</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>'Achhe din' myth exposed, BJP will be rejected in Haryana as well: Congress</title>
			<link>http://www.newsx.com/haryana-news/item/26767-achhe-din-myth-exposed-bjp-will-be-rejected-in-haryana-as-well-congress</link>
			<description><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/1160d90ff310b7a591caa3c09d3c08df_Generic.jpg"><img align="right" border="0" src="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/1160d90ff310b7a591caa3c09d3c08df_S.jpg" alt="achhe-din-myth-exposed-bjp-will-be-rejected-in-haryana-as-well-congress" /></a><font color="#ff3300"><b>Featured</b></font><p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Chandigarh: Congress on Tuesday termed the assembly bypolls results as a "mini referendum" saying the "achhe din" myth stands exposed as the people have rejected the "authoritarian" mode of governance, and asserted that the electorate of Haryana will also reject BJP in the October 15 elections.</span></p>

<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"The 'achhe din' myth stands exposed and the artificially created bubble has burst. The People of India have spoken once again in this mini-referendum - from Gujarat to UP - rejecting the governance style, lack of vision and authoritarian mode of governance," Congress national spokesman and Haryana Cabinet Minister Randeep Singh Surjewala said.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">He said the inclusive style of governance as shown by the Congress is the only way to run a country as diverse as India.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"We thank the people of India for showing the mirror to BJP and the Prime Minister," Surjewala said on the bypoll results today.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Asked what impact the bypoll results could have on the next month's assembly polls in Haryana, Surjewala said the people will reject the saffron party.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"BJP suffers from a phobia of arrogance in Haryana and has become an accumulating point for defectors, opportunists and rejected leaders," the senior Congress leader said.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">With Haryana Janhit Congress separating from BJP accusing it of "repeated betrayals", Surjewala said "with their own alliance having been shamelessly breached by BJP leadership, their now found love for INLD whom their own (BJP) President (Amit Shah) calls a goonda party is indeed intriguing and strange".</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"They (BJP) must answer clearly to the people of Haryana ans clarify this opportunistic brand of politics that they seem to be playing out," he said.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">BJP was dealt a major blow in the Assembly by-elections in Uttar Pradesh, Rajasthan and Gujarat, the states it had swept in the Lok Sabha polls four months ago, as it lost 13 of the 23 seats held by it.</span></p>]]></description>
			<dc:creator>Edited by Priyanka Kukreja || Updated: 8:20 IST</dc:creator>
			<pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2014 02:42:13 -0600</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.newsx.com/haryana-news/item/26767-achhe-din-myth-exposed-bjp-will-be-rejected-in-haryana-as-well-congress</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Writers, historians, scribes show solidarity with Kashmir's flood-hit people</title>
			<link>http://www.newsx.com/cities/item/26766-writers-historians-scribes-show-solidarity-with-kashmirs-flood-hit-people</link>
			<description><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/da6e404ffe4f564e03d1f5edcae6a158_Generic.jpg"><img align="right" border="0" src="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/da6e404ffe4f564e03d1f5edcae6a158_S.jpg" alt="writers-historians-scribes-show-solidarity-with-kashmirs-flood-hit-people" /></a><font color="#ff3300"><b>Featured</b></font><p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">New Delhi: Eminent writers, historians, scientists, journalists and civil society workers on Tuesday came forward to show their solidarity with the people Jammu and Kashmir battling the worst floods in the state's history.</span></p>

<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">At a discussion here, they called for prompt rehabilitation of the affected people and asked the authorities to speed up the relief and rescue work.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"We could not stop the floods but we could have certainly mitigated the damage to a very large extent. They were not flash floods. With modern technology, we could have predicted the water levels and gave concrete alerts to people," said Saleem Baig, Convener, INTACH (Indian National Trust for Art and Cultural Heritage), J&amp;K chapter.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Baig rejected reports of selective rescue operations and said "it is not the time to look at such developments. We should not converge long-standing political problems with something that is immediate and requires prompt action."</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Iftikar Gilani, senior journalist who had reported extensively about the state, pointed to loopholes in rescue operations and suggested a few solutions to streamline the operations in the valley.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"There is a dire need for more water pumps, water purification units and a team of pediatricians in the valley. Many Air India flights are unable to lift relief materials from major airports. The material is lying unclaimed at airports in Pune, Bangalore and Calcutta.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"Just 80 boats have been allotted for the rescue operations, against the requirement of 650. We need to also look at the kind of relief materials that the victims are in need of," said the journalist at the event at the Press Club of India here.</span></p>]]></description>
			<dc:creator>Edited by Priyanka Kukreja || Updated:  8:00 IST</dc:creator>
			<pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2014 02:23:56 -0600</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.newsx.com/cities/item/26766-writers-historians-scribes-show-solidarity-with-kashmirs-flood-hit-people</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>China's Xi visit to India sets tone for future relations</title>
			<link>http://www.newsx.com/national/nation/item/26765-chinas-xi-visit-to-india-sets-tone-for-future-relations</link>
			<description><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/2588ba9d8579390782250bb334029344_Generic.jpg"><img align="right" border="0" src="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/2588ba9d8579390782250bb334029344_S.jpg" alt="chinas-xi-visit-to-india-sets-tone-for-future-relations" /></a><font color="#ff3300"><b>Featured</b></font><p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Indian Prime Minister Narendra Modi will spend his 64th birthday Wednesday at a private dinner with Xi Jinping in his home state of Gujarat, as the Chinese president begins a visit that will set the tone for relations between Asia`s rival superpowers.</span></p>

<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Despite his hardline nationalist reputation, Narendra Modi moved quickly to engage with traditional rival China after taking office in May, and has pulled out all the stops for Xi`s first state visit to India.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The Chinese president will fly into Gujarat`s main city Ahmedabad, where giant billboards in Mandarin, Gujarati and English have been put up to welcome him.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">But Modi has also made clear he sees China as a competitor and intends to pursue a more muscular foreign policy than the previous centre-left Congress party government.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The nuclear-armed neighbours fought a brief but bloody war in 1962 over the Indian state of Arunachal Pradesh in the eastern Himalayas, and are still embroiled in a bitter dispute over the territory.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">India`s new government recently eased restrictions on construction in the areas up to 100 kilometres of its disputed border, allowing the Indian military to build roads and other infrastructure in an area that China claims as its own.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">But both sides say they want to focus on economic cooperation, with India seeking Chinese funding for a planned overhaul of its dilapidated railways and cooperation in nuclear energy.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">China is India`s biggest trading partner, with annual two-way commerce of more than $65 billion. But Indian data shows the trade deficit with China has soared to more than $40 billion from just $1 billion in 2001-02.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Modi, who ran for election promising to revive India`s flagging economy, called for more Chinese investment when he met Xi in Brazil in July.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">China meanwhile is eager to cement its relationship with its western neighbour at a time of heightened tensions with Japan and several Southeast Asian nations over disputed territory.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Rajrishi Singhal, senior fellow at New Delhi think tank Gateway House, said Xi would be eager to allay India`s fears over the widening trade deficit during his visit.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"The tenor and purpose of President Xi Jinping`s visit to India... can be gauged from the large size of the delegation accompanying him, comprising of senior ministers, leading business barons and bankers," said Singhal.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"Apart from the scheduled talks on political, security and border issues, the Chinese president`s visit is likely to primarily focus on allaying the Indian government`s growing discomfort over the widening trade deficit between the two countries."Modi has spoken of his admiration for China`s economic growth in the last decade.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">But he also enjoys a close relationship with Japan`s President Shinzo Abe, and analysts have said he may be able to leverage Beijing`s rivalry with Tokyo to secure Chinese investment.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">China`s consul-general in Mumbai Liu Youfa told the Times of India daily ahead of the visit that Xi would "commit investments of over $100 billion", pointing out that this was three times the amount pledged by Japan during a visit by Modi earlier this month.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Xi heads to India after visiting the Maldives and Sri Lanka as China increasingly asserts its influence in a region that has traditionally come under India`s sphere of influence.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Colombo has sought to allay Indian fears by insisting its relations with Beijing are based on commercial rather than security considerations.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">But some in New Delhi still fear China`s growing engagement in the region is a deliberate strategy to encircle India.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The presence of the Dalai Lama, Tibet`s exiled spiritual leader, is another source of tension between India and China, and New Delhi is on alert for any protests during Xi`s visit.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Xi will visit Gandhi`s former hermitage, now a museum, and have dinner with Modi in a tent on the riverbank in Ahmedabad, where he is expected to announce plans to build a Chinese-funded industrial park.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">On Thursday he will hold formal talks with Modi and India`s President Pranab Mukherjee in New Delhi and sign a series of agreements with the prime minister, before departing for China on Friday.</span></p>]]></description>
			<dc:creator>Edited by Priyanka Kukreja || Updated: 7:40 IST</dc:creator>
			<pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2014 02:10:27 -0600</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.newsx.com/national/nation/item/26765-chinas-xi-visit-to-india-sets-tone-for-future-relations</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>India Debates: Why India wedded to #VIPPerk culture? </title>
			<link>http://www.newsx.com/component/k2/item/26764-india-debates-why-india-wedded-to-#vipperk-culture?&amp;Itemid=919</link>
			<description><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/cbb0ee3903881e244661bd6d5ee15241_Generic.jpg"><img align="right" border="0" src="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/cbb0ee3903881e244661bd6d5ee15241_S.jpg" alt="india-debates-why-india-wedded-to-#vipperk-culture?" /></a><font color="#ff3300"><b>Featured</b></font><p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">A shocking mobile video, which has been uploaded on YouTube, has gone viral.</span></p>

<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The video shows that former Interior Minister of Pakistan -- Rehman Malik has been thrown off of a plane.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">According to reports, the PK 370 of Pakistan International Airlines (PIA) was delayed by 2 hours before leaving for Islamabad from Karachi.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">While angry passengers blamed Malik for the delay, airline officials have not confirmed the reason yet.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Many suspected that the flight was delayed for some technical glitch which is reportedly very common with PIA. Pakistani website posted a video series which showed the incident inside the plane.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The video has gone viral on YouTube and on other sites. Video has been viewed more than 53,000 times.</span></p>
<p><iframe src="//www.youtube.com/embed/4UATOj2sD9E" frameborder="0" width="684" height="415" allowfullscreen="true" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"></iframe></p>]]></description>
			<dc:creator>NewsX Bureau</dc:creator>
			<pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2014 17:32:27 -0600</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.newsx.com/component/k2/item/26764-india-debates-why-india-wedded-to-#vipperk-culture?&amp;Itemid=919</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Nation at 9: Hate ranter Yogi makes excuses </title>
			<link>http://www.newsx.com/shows/specials/item/26763-nation-at-9-hate-ranter-yogi-makes-excuses</link>
			<description><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/3342db3751cce7047d499d802c3efba1_Generic.jpg"><img align="right" border="0" src="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/3342db3751cce7047d499d802c3efba1_S.jpg" alt="nation-at-9-hate-ranter-yogi-makes-excuses" /></a><font color="#ff3300"><b>Featured</b></font><p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Blaming all but himself, BJP leader Yogi Adityanath on Tuesday said a big factor for party's poor performance in Uttar Pradesh was that he was not allowed to campaign everywhere in the state.</span></p>

<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The Gorakhpur MP also blamed candidate selection and the party's strategy in the state for the BJP's failure in the bypolls.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"Party's UP campaign strategy was flawed," Yogi Adityanath said.</span></p>
<p><iframe src="//www.youtube.com/embed/dR4P8Aa_9PQ" frameborder="0" width="684" height="415" allowfullscreen="true" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"></iframe></p>]]></description>
			<dc:creator>NewsX Bureau</dc:creator>
			<pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2014 17:20:30 -0600</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.newsx.com/shows/specials/item/26763-nation-at-9-hate-ranter-yogi-makes-excuses</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>J&amp;K: Government releases additional Rs 100 crore each to Kashmir, Jammu</title>
			<link>http://www.newsx.com/regional/j-k/item/26762-jk-government-releases-additional-rs-100-crore-each-to-kashmir-jammu</link>
			<description><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/f455114419340a11950f29efd7fc2c7f_Generic.jpg"><img align="right" border="0" src="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/f455114419340a11950f29efd7fc2c7f_S.jpg" alt="jk-government-releases-additional-rs-100-crore-each-to-kashmir-jammu" /></a><font color="#ff3300"><b>Featured</b></font><p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Jammu: The Omar Abdullah government on Tuesday placed Rs 100 crore each at the disposal of the Divisional Commissioners of Kashmir and Jammu for temporary restoration of infrastructure.</span></p>

<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">According to an official spokesman, the fresh grant is in addition to the already released Rs 100 crore each for Jammu and Kashmir divisions. The multi-disciplinary teams constituted to assess losses due to the flood are working actively and pumps have been put up at various places to drain out stagnant water from the Srinagar city.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Chief Minister Omar Abdullah, who is monitoring relief and rehabilitation operations, directed for close coordination among critical departments of SMC, Flood Control, UEED, ERA and Fire and Emergency Services for ensuring speedy relief and rehabilitation of the flood victims.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">He also directed to go for even controlled cuts to drain out the stagnant water, besides deploying maximum dewatering pumps. Omar asked the Chief Secretary to streamline the mechanism of loss assessment. He appealed to the insurance companies to depute their teams immediately to flood affected areas to settle the claims.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">It was informed that 100 tonnes of food grains have been supplied to Srinagar and Budgam districts during the past two days by the CAPD, besides 400 tonnes and 150 tonnes food grains have been distributed in Anantnag, Pulwama and adjoining areas respectively.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">About 162 LPG trucks have also been made available in Srinagar and adjacent areas in the last two days and work is on to replenish petrol supply in the valley.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Nearly, 40 lakh chlorine tablets have reached the Valley and the Chief Minister directed that these tablets should be distributed along with the relief material through CAPD, NDRF and other teams to all places. Likewise, nine lakh chlorine tablets have already been distributed in the flood affected</span><br /><span style="font-size: 10pt;">areas, the spokesman said.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The meeting was apprised that Bone and Joint Hospital in Barzulla, Rainwara Hospital and SKIMS, Soura have resumed services. The SKIMS, Bermina which has been inundated will be made partially functional in a couple of days after water is drained out.</span></p>]]></description>
			<dc:creator>Edited by Kirti Dwivedi | Updated: 6:45 IST</dc:creator>
			<pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2014 13:52:46 -0600</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.newsx.com/regional/j-k/item/26762-jk-government-releases-additional-rs-100-crore-each-to-kashmir-jammu</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Top senior Maoist leader arrested in Gadchiroli</title>
			<link>http://www.newsx.com/regional/maharashtra/item/26761-top-senior-maoist-leader-arrested-in-gadchiroli</link>
			<description><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/73686d93531b50d7c1f42247aecf87be_Generic.jpg"><img align="right" border="0" src="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/73686d93531b50d7c1f42247aecf87be_S.jpg" alt="top-senior-maoist-leader-arrested-in-gadchiroli" /></a><font color="#ff3300"><b>Featured</b></font><p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Gadchiroli: A senior Maoist was arrested by the Gadchiroli police Tuesday, Superintendent of Police Sandip Patil said during a press conference here today.</span></p>

<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The arrested Maoist cadre, identified as Raju alias Jethuram Dhurwa (41) who is a resident of Khedgaon village in Rajnandgaon district of Chhattisgarh, is allegedly a member of the Manpur Division and Commander of Aundhi Local Operation Squad.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The Gadchiroli police succeeded in arresting such a senior Maoist cadre for the first time after 2007, the SP said, adding, Maoists have suffered a major setback with the arrest.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Earlier, a deputy commander of this Maoist squad was killed in an encounter at Gahangatta after which this squad had almost ceased to exist, he said.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Allegedly, Raju was actively involved in several serious offences in Chhattisgarh and Maharashtra.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Before joining the Maoist movement, he worked as militia member in his native place. He used to allegedly transport explosives and other material sent by Maoist Gudsa Usendi and Manpur Division Special Zonal Committee to various Maoist squads.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Raju joined the Pallemadi Maoist squad in 2007 and was transferred to Mohalla Local Operation Squad in 2008, where he continued till 2012.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">In 2012, he was transferred to the Pallemadi Maoist squad and worked as in-charge of the Aundhi squad, the police official said.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Allegedly, Raju was involved in several crimes including vehicle burning at Pallemadi mines in 2006, looting gelatin sticks in Mahamaya, the Sorpar murder in 2007, Sambalpur encounter, Padi murder in 2009, Kandali murder in 2011, Bukmarka hill and Mungner encounters in 2012, Lekepar ambush in 2012, as well as Mudeli and Mardgutta encounters in 2014, the police official said.</span></p>]]></description>
			<dc:creator>Edited by Kirti Dwivedi | Updated: 6:05 IST</dc:creator>
			<pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2014 12:53:19 -0600</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.newsx.com/regional/maharashtra/item/26761-top-senior-maoist-leader-arrested-in-gadchiroli</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Bypoll results no barometer for things to come, says Sushil Modi</title>
			<link>http://www.newsx.com/regional/other-states/item/26760-bypoll-results-no-barometer-for-things-to-come-says-sushil-modi</link>
			<description><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/ebff3531fe0668baf1a9b098f3660d4c_Generic.jpg"><img align="right" border="0" src="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/ebff3531fe0668baf1a9b098f3660d4c_S.jpg" alt="bypoll-results-no-barometer-for-things-to-come-says-sushil-modi" /></a><font color="#ff3300"><b>Featured</b></font><p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Patna: Former Bihar Deputy Chief Minister Sushil Kumar Modi Tuesday sought to downplay the results/trends in three Parliamentary and 33 Assembly seats, the counting for which was underway.</span></p>

<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"The results/trends during counting of votes for three Parliamentary and 33 Assembly seats across several states are not a barometer for things to come in future nor does it have anything to do with the past results," Modi told reporters in reply to a question.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The results/trends must be seen as isolated cases reflecting local issues and equations, Modi said, adding it has nothing to do with the general elections or performance of the NDA government headed by Prime Minister Narendra Modi.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The bypoll results will also have no bearing on assembly polls to be held in Maharashtra, Haryana and other states later this year or next year, the senior BJP leader, under whose leadership the party put up a rather unimpressive show winning four of 10 Assembly seats in bypolls recently, claimed.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Modi argued the bypoll results should not be seen in the context of approval of the NDA government's performance or lack of it saying that neither the prime minister nor top BJP leaders had campaigned in the poll-bound Parliamentary and Assembly constituencies as was the case with the Congress leaders like Sonia Gandhi and Rahul Gandhi, who too had refrained from canvassing for their party candidates.</span></p>]]></description>
			<dc:creator>Edited by Kirti Dwivedi | Updated:  5:45 IST</dc:creator>
			<pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2014 12:49:27 -0600</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.newsx.com/regional/other-states/item/26760-bypoll-results-no-barometer-for-things-to-come-says-sushil-modi</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>No need to use &quot;His Excellency&quot;, says Kerala Governor</title>
			<link>http://www.newsx.com/regional/other-states/item/26759-no-need-to-use-his-excellency-says-kerala-governor</link>
			<description><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/7f4c90e4ede24e7c7dcfb1e40fae43a1_Generic.jpg"><img align="right" border="0" src="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/7f4c90e4ede24e7c7dcfb1e40fae43a1_S.jpg" alt="no-need-to-use-his-excellency-says-kerala-governor" /></a><font color="#ff3300"><b>Featured</b></font><p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Thiruvananthapuram, Kerala Governor and former Chief Justice of India Justice P Sathasivam Tuesday suggested avoiding epithets like "His Excellency" while addressing him.</span></p>

<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"Honourable Governor of Kerala desires that he may be addressed as Honourable Governor in all correspondence and not along with any other epithet such as His Excellency," a Raj Bhavan release said here.</span></p>]]></description>
			<dc:creator>Edited by Kirti Dwivedi | Updated: 5:25 IST</dc:creator>
			<pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2014 12:41:58 -0600</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.newsx.com/regional/other-states/item/26759-no-need-to-use-his-excellency-says-kerala-governor</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>#VVIPPerk: Angry passengers bar PPP leader Rehman Malik for causing delay in the flight schedule</title>
			<link>http://www.newsx.com/component/k2/item/26758-#vvipperk-angry-passengers-bar-ppp-leader-rehman-malik-for-causing-delay-in-the-flight-schedule&amp;Itemid=714</link>
			<description><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/ec61a09ba20dda328604d7afb1ac78d5_Generic.jpg"><img align="right" border="0" src="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/ec61a09ba20dda328604d7afb1ac78d5_S.jpg" alt="#vvipperk-angry-passengers-bar-ppp-leader-rehman-malik-for-causing-delay-in-the-flight-schedule" /></a><font color="#ff3300"><b>Featured</b></font><p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Karachi: What came as a major embarrassment for the top leaders in Pakistan was when the leader of Pakistan People’s Party (PPP) Rehman Malik and Pakistan Muslim League - Nawaz (PML-N) Member of National Assembly Dr. Ramesh Kumar Wakwani were expelled from boarding Islamabad-bound PIA flight from Karachi as they delayed it by more than two hours.</span></p>

<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">A video clipping has gone viral on the internet which shows that the passengers of the flight in n extremely angry mood held the two prominent leaders responsible for the delay and even questioned them.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">“We have taken it for too long... 68 years... are we going to take it for another 68 years?” passengers can be heard saying in the video.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The PPP leader was asked to apologize by the passengers as he approached the jet-way that connects the terminal to the aircraft.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">“Malik sahab, sorry. You should go back. You should apologize to these passengers. You should be ashamed of yourself... 250 passengers have suffered because of you. It is your fault, sir,” was one of the passenger’s statements.</span></p>
<p><iframe src="//www.youtube.com/embed/Emst2VM4gR0" frameborder="0" width="684" height="415" allowfullscreen="true" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"></iframe></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">&nbsp;</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">As the agitation against the leaders echoed, another passenger could be heard saying, “Malik sahab, you are not a minister any more. And even if you are, we don’t care... anymore.”</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">PIA’s flight PK-370 was scheduled to depart from Karachi’s Jinnah International Airport at 7 PM but was delayed by almost three hours.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Dr. Ramesh Kumar Wakwani appeared to be accompanying Rehman Malik was as well taken off the aircraft allegedly for their VIP treatment of coming in late and delaying the scheduling of the aircraft and eventually the flight departed for its destination without the two lawmakers.</span></p>]]></description>
			<dc:creator>Written by Charnamrit Sachdeva</dc:creator>
			<pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2014 12:19:58 -0600</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.newsx.com/component/k2/item/26758-#vvipperk-angry-passengers-bar-ppp-leader-rehman-malik-for-causing-delay-in-the-flight-schedule&amp;Itemid=714</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Want to do films that scare me: Emraan Hashmi says</title>
			<link>http://www.newsx.com/showbiz/celebrities/item/26757-want-to-do-films-that-scare-me-emraan-hashmi-says</link>
			<description><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/bfb6e0312258c5f38b3a04b2146f3618_Generic.jpg"><img align="right" border="0" src="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/bfb6e0312258c5f38b3a04b2146f3618_S.jpg" alt="want-to-do-films-that-scare-me-emraan-hashmi-says" /></a><font color="#ff3300"><b>Featured</b></font><p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Commercial Bollywood films may be his "bread and butter" but Emraan Hashmi says he is keen to take risks and do projects that scare him as a performer post his "creatively satisfying" turns in 'Shanghai' and Danis Tanovic's upcoming movie 'Tigers'.</span></p>

<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Hashmi's performance in the Oscar-winning director's real-life inspired drama has earned him a lot of praise in the international media following its world premiere at the recently concluded Toronto International Film Festival.</span></p>]]></description>
			<dc:creator>Edited by Kirti Dwivedi | Updated: 5:15 IST</dc:creator>
			<pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2014 12:13:59 -0600</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.newsx.com/showbiz/celebrities/item/26757-want-to-do-films-that-scare-me-emraan-hashmi-says</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>People have rejected BJP's politics of polarisation, Congress says</title>
			<link>http://www.newsx.com/national/nation/item/26756-people-have-rejected-bjps-politics-of-polarisation-congress-says</link>
			<description><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/b8b3919020649cc8e0b35f890cc0decc_Generic.jpg"><img align="right" border="0" src="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/b8b3919020649cc8e0b35f890cc0decc_S.jpg" alt="people-have-rejected-bjps-politics-of-polarisation-congress-says" /></a><font color="#ff3300"><b>Featured</b></font><p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">As BJP suffered reverses in the assembly bypolls, Congress today said the results should ring alarm bells for the saffron party as people have rejected its "politics of polarisation" and claimed anti-incumbency factor has set in within 100 days of Modi government coming to power.</span></p>

<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"People did not like the attitude of BJP and Modi government. While the Prime Minister himself kept silent, BJP leaders and ministers in the Modi government played the politics of polarisation through their statements," Congress general secretary Shakeel Ahmed said.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">He noted that Congress' gains in Gujarat and Rajasthan were significant as in the Lok Sabha polls it had drawn a blank in both states.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"Now we will try to improve our performance," said Ahmed, who is is AICC general secretary in-charge for poll bound Haryana.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Turning to Uttar Pradesh, the Congress spokesman alleged that "full authority" had been given to people who were responsible for inciting riots in the state.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"Leave aside caste, creed and religion, these communal forces were acting as triggers to incite fight between husband and wife," he said in an obvious reference to BJP raking up the issue of "Love Jihad", the alleged forcible conversion of Hindu girls through marriage.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">He said that the bypoll verdict shows that "this is the first government whose anti-incumbency factor has started working within 100 days of coming to power. Alarm bells are ringing for the BJP".</span></p>]]></description>
			<dc:creator>Edited by Kirti Dwivedi | Updated:  4:55 IST</dc:creator>
			<pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2014 11:55:58 -0600</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.newsx.com/national/nation/item/26756-people-have-rejected-bjps-politics-of-polarisation-congress-says</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Indian masterpieces up for sale in NY</title>
			<link>http://www.newsx.com/world/us/item/26755-indian-masterpieces-up-for-sale-in-ny</link>
			<description><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/fc8fcdcfe694313b95a45e8203f36a50_Generic.jpg"><img align="right" border="0" src="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/fc8fcdcfe694313b95a45e8203f36a50_S.jpg" alt="indian-masterpieces-up-for-sale-in-ny" /></a><font color="#ff3300"><b>Featured</b></font><p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">New York: Paintings by one of India's most important modern artists go under the hammer in New York on Wednesday, highlights in a booming market for Asian art featured this week. Three oils on canvas by pioneering Indian abstract artist Vasudeo Santu Gaitonde, who in 1964 based himself in New York, are being offered for auction by Christie's and Bonham's.</span></p>

<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Bonham's canvases, signed and dated 1961 and 1963, come from the artist's "non-objective" series and were acquired by US artist Morris Graves, who described him as "fine -- or superb -- as Mark Rothko at his best."</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The auction house values the oil paintings, which</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">have spent 45 years with a San Francisco collector, at $300-500,000 and $600-800,000 respectively. Christie's is offering a 1971 publicly known painting "Untitled" in moss green for $750,000 to $900,000, which it says showcases the "painter, philosopher and alchemist at the zenith of his career."</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Gaitonde's prices don't yet compare to the stratospheric ones fetched for Western art, but experts say he is poised to join the international modern art canon, and that there is a robust, emerging market in modern Indian art.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The Guggenheim in New York on October 24 opens the first museum exhibition dedicated to the famously reclusive artist, and Gaitonde work has recently set records in the Asian art world.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">In 2012 Christie's set a world record for a modern Indian painting by selling a canvas for $3.79 million. In March, Sotheby's sold another Gaitonde for $2.5 million.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Bonham's three-year-old department of Indian, Himalayan and South Asian art, a minnow compared to powerhouses Christie's and Sotheby's, has billed Wednesday's sale as a real coup. "It couldn't be a better time to offer these," Mark Rasmussen, Bonham's junior specialist, told AFP.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">He regards Gaitonde as the most sought-after modern Indian painter, and said he expected bids from collectors as well as international institutions.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong><span style="font-size: 10pt;">'Poetry on canvas'</span></strong></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Born in Nagpur, India in 1924, Gaitonde was inspired early on by Swiss artist Paul Klee, then turned towards abstraction and cultivated a lifelong interest in Zen Buddhism.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">He studied in Bombay and in 1964 lived at New York's Chelsea Hotel, then a cultural hub that housed Bob Dylan, Arthur Miller and Leonard Cohen.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Deepanjana Klein, head of South Asian modern and contemporary art at Christie's, called Gaitonde's work "poetry on canvas."</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"There is only a finite body of great work and collectors know that. When they see something great they will come and get it," she told AFP</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The last decade has seen an astonishing explosion in the global market for Asian art, fueled by new, cash-rich wealth in China but in which European and US collectors have kept pace.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Catching up with Western prices</span></strong></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Jonathan Stone, head of Asian art at Christie's and based in Hong Kong, told AFP that the growth was so fast that Asian art prices are starting to catch up with Western art.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"Chinese art has taken a lot of the headlines, but the interest in Southeast Asian art has grown considerably, and I know there has been a significant growth in the Indian contemporary and modern market," he said.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Christie's had an inaugural sale in Mumbai last year and is setting up in Shanghai to capitalize on new clients, but Stone says none of that detracts from Asian sales week in New York.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"New York remains almost unique in the way we're able to offer such a range of Asian art across all cultures and all epochs," he said.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Christie's hopes to make $26 million from Asian art this week, and Sotheby's a whopping $42.5 to $58 million, bolstered by Chinese ceramics and classical painting and calligraphy.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Bonhams' upper estimate for its Chinese, Indian and Japanese art sales is $10 million.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Bruce MacLaren, a Chinese art specialist at Bonhams, said some artists are selling for at least 10 times what they were selling for 10 years ago.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Chinese imperial, 18th, 19th and 20th century art does well, and buyers from mainland China really command the market, he said.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"They're absolutely transforming the way the market is behaving," he told AFP.</span></p>]]></description>
			<dc:creator>Edited by Kirti Dwivedi | Updated: 4:45 IST</dc:creator>
			<pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2014 11:35:14 -0600</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.newsx.com/world/us/item/26755-indian-masterpieces-up-for-sale-in-ny</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Narendra Modi's magic has faded: TMC</title>
			<link>http://www.newsx.com/regional/west-bengal/item/26754-narendra-modis-magic-has-faded-tmc</link>
			<description><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/5054252360e1858b1691f28299a767d7_Generic.jpg"><img align="right" border="0" src="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/5054252360e1858b1691f28299a767d7_S.jpg" alt="narendra-modis-magic-has-faded-tmc" /></a><font color="#ff3300"><b>Featured</b></font><p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Kolkata: Even as the BJP made inroads in West Bengal winning the Basirhat South Assembly seat in a by-election, the ruling Trinamool Congress, which retained the Chowringhee seat, on Tuesday claimed the magic surrounding Narendra Modi has faded within 100 days of coming to power at the Centre.</span></p>

<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Expressing happiness over the poll result, Trinamool national general secretary Mukul Roy asserted his party will bag more than two-thirds seats in the 2016 Assembly polls.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"The bypoll results across the country have now proved that within 100 days of its coming to power, the BJP has been losing people's faith in it. The Modi magic has faded and people have voted against this government which has been using central agencies with political motive," Roy told media persons here.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">While Trinamool's Nayana Bandyopadhyay won the Chowringhee seat, party candidate and former India football skipper Dipendu Biswas lost out to the BJP's Samik Bhattacharya by over 1,000 votes in Basirhat South.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"Despite the smear campaign by the media and our rivals, people continue to repose faith in Mamata Banerjee and the Trinamool. During the Lok Sabha polls, BJP led by over 30,000 votes in the Basirhat (South) segment, but we recovered more than 28,000 of that," Roy said.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"We are confident of not only winning Basirhat (South), but also more than two-thirds seats in the 2016 Assembly polls," he added.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">With the Congress and CPI-M candidates faring poorly in both constituencies, Roy said both the parties have become "irrelevant".</span></p>]]></description>
			<dc:creator>Edited by Kirti Dwivedi | Updated: 4:45 IST</dc:creator>
			<pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2014 11:26:51 -0600</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.newsx.com/regional/west-bengal/item/26754-narendra-modis-magic-has-faded-tmc</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Minor allegedly raped by neighbour in UP</title>
			<link>http://www.newsx.com/regional/up/item/26753-minor-allegedly-raped-by-neighbour-in-up</link>
			<description><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/6a4f457a6990dd74c63e187696a28fd0_Generic.jpg"><img align="right" border="0" src="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/6a4f457a6990dd74c63e187696a28fd0_S.jpg" alt="minor-allegedly-raped-by-neighbour-in-up" /></a><font color="#ff3300"><b>Featured</b></font><p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Muzaffarnagar: A 10-year-old girl was allegedly raped by her neighbour when she was alone at home, police said Tuesday.</span></p>

<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The incident took last week when the 14-year-old accused entered the girl's house as she was alone and raped her, SHO Arun Kumar said.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The accused then threatened her against revealing the incident to anyone.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The incident came to light when the girl started feeling unwell and she narrated the whole episode to her mother, police said.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">A complaint was registered by her parents at New Mandi police station.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The girl has been sent for medical examination, police said, adding that the accused is still absconding.</span></p>]]></description>
			<dc:creator>Edited by Kirti Dwivedi | Updated: 4:35 IST</dc:creator>
			<pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2014 11:16:56 -0600</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.newsx.com/regional/up/item/26753-minor-allegedly-raped-by-neighbour-in-up</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>NCP's election campaign begins from Kolhapur</title>
			<link>http://www.newsx.com/regional/maharashtra/item/26752-ncps-election-campaign-begins-from-kolhapur</link>
			<description><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/2c6470ae12cb81d0baa9ee2de8b40bbe_Generic.jpg"><img align="right" border="0" src="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/2c6470ae12cb81d0baa9ee2de8b40bbe_S.jpg" alt="ncps-election-campaign-begins-from-kolhapur" /></a><font color="#ff3300"><b>Featured</b></font><p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Kolhapur: A day after the NCP inducted eight sitting independent legislators into its partyfold ahead of the state Assembly elections, the party is set to kickstart its first leg of campaign by holding a public rally at Kolhapur in Western Maharashtra Tuesday.</span></p>

<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"We have decided to start our campaigning from Kolhapur as this was the very place our party was born. Inspite of the Modi wave across the country, people elected an NCP MP from Kolhapur," Dhananjay Mahadik, NCP MP from Kolhapur constituency said today.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Mocking the BJP-led government at the Centre, Mahadik said that the bypoll results in various states declared today are only showing that Modi's prominence in the mind's of people is decreasing by the day.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"People chose Modi to be the PM as they believed he would live up to the tall promises he made. But see the results of bypolls even in states like UP. It only shows people are losing their patience with him. It won't be long before people start showing their anger to him," he said.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The Additional SP of Kolhapur said that elaborate security arrangements have been made ahead of today's rally, which is expected to be attended by NCP Chief Sharad Pawar, deputy Maharashtra CM Ajit Pawar and state NCP President Sunil Tatkare.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"We have deployed a 400 strong police force for the rally, which, according to NCP leaders will be attended by around 70,000 people. We have made arrangements according to the IB inputs that we have received," DSP Kolhapur Ankit Goyal said.</span></p>]]></description>
			<dc:creator>Edited by Kirti Dwivedi | Updated: 4:15 IST</dc:creator>
			<pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2014 10:43:33 -0600</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.newsx.com/regional/maharashtra/item/26752-ncps-election-campaign-begins-from-kolhapur</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Four killed in lightning incident in Odisha</title>
			<link>http://www.newsx.com/regional/other-states/item/26751-four-killed-in-lightning-incident-in-odisha</link>
			<description><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/1010314588ddb6ebee19312886cee06d_Generic.jpg"><img align="right" border="0" src="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/1010314588ddb6ebee19312886cee06d_S.jpg" alt="four-killed-in-lightning-incident-in-odisha" /></a><font color="#ff3300"><b>Featured</b></font><p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Jajpur: At least four persons died and nineteen others injured, eight of them seriously, after lightning struck them in different places in Odisha's Jajpur district Tuesday, police said.</span></p>

<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The injured persons were admitted to different hospitals in the district, while five of them were shifted to SCB Medical College and Hospital in Cuttack after their condition deteriorated, Jajpur District Chief Medical Officer Debabrata Jena said.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Two labourers, engaged in repair of the river embankment of the Baitarani, died on the spot and 11 others injured when lightning struck at Patapur.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">One person died on the spot while he was returning home from Arabal village on a bi-cycle as lightning struck.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Another person died and eight others were injured while they were working in different paddy fields at Dharmasala block, police said.</span></p>]]></description>
			<dc:creator>Edited by Kirti Dwivedi | Updated: 3:45 IST</dc:creator>
			<pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2014 10:36:32 -0600</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.newsx.com/regional/other-states/item/26751-four-killed-in-lightning-incident-in-odisha</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>West Bengal: Somnath Chatterjee wants new leadership in Left Front</title>
			<link>http://www.newsx.com/regional/west-bengal/item/26750-west-bengal-somnath-chatterjee-wants-new-leadership-in-left-front</link>
			<description><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/7c617d329022e24ea07a52a1daa2de32_Generic.jpg"><img align="right" border="0" src="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/7c617d329022e24ea07a52a1daa2de32_S.jpg" alt="west-bengal-somnath-chatterjee-wants-new-leadership-in-left-front" /></a><font color="#ff3300"><b>Featured</b></font><p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Kolkata: Expressing sadness over the dismal performance of CPI-M in the two Assembly bypolls in West Bengal, former Lok Sabha speaker and expelled party leader Somnath Chatterjee on Tuesday said the signs for the Left Front were ominous unless new faces come to the fore.</span></p>

<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">He also expressed "grave" concern over the Bharatiya Janata Party's victory in Basrihat (South).</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"There is no doubt that the signs are ominous. It's a sad state of affairs that the Left has not been able to get closer to masses. It's indicative of their organisational deficiency and as I have been advocating for some time now, it's high time there is a change in the leadership," Chatterjee told a news agency.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Opening its account in the state Assembly, BJP's Samik Bhattacharya wrested the Basirhat South constituency, while ruling Trinamool Congress retained the Chowringhee seat with Nayna Bandyopadhyay coming up trumps.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Chatterjee also expressed his concern over the rise of BJP in Bengal.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"It's a matter of great anguish and grave concern that Left is conceding ground to BJP and right wing forces are rising in Bengal. It's very painful to see the BJP reaping benefits of the Saradha issue and the not Left. I hope, those at helm are taking serious note of it and they must undertake immediate steps to arrest the decline," added Chatterjee.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Echoing similar views Udayan Guha of the Left constituent Forward Bloc, too advocated a change in leadership.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"Nothing can be more alarming than BJP winning the Basirhat South which has long been a CPI-M stronghold. Since the 2011 Assembly polls, Left has been steadily eroding making it evident that we have not been able to reach out to the voters. It is now apparent that people are not liking few of the leaders and it's high time new faces and young legs take up the mantle," Guha, a MLA from Dinhata in the state, told a news agency.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Guha also dubbed as "humiliating" CPI-M's Faiyaz Ahmed Khan losing his deposit from Chowringhee.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"What can be more humiliating? It's alarming to see BJP now asserting itself as the chief opposition in Bengal. Time has come for taking drastic steps to revive out fortunes," added Guha.</span></p>]]></description>
			<dc:creator>Edited by Kirti Dwivedi | Updated: 3:25 IST</dc:creator>
			<pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2014 09:58:22 -0600</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.newsx.com/regional/west-bengal/item/26750-west-bengal-somnath-chatterjee-wants-new-leadership-in-left-front</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Rajasthan: Congress wrests three Assembly seats from BJP</title>
			<link>http://www.newsx.com/regional/other-states/item/26749-rajasthan-congress-wrests-three-assembly-seats-from-bjp</link>
			<description><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/a1ecd100e0e2ff55d7f30c8d4a650575_Generic.jpg"><img align="right" border="0" src="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/a1ecd100e0e2ff55d7f30c8d4a650575_S.jpg" alt="rajasthan-congress-wrests-three-assembly-seats-from-bjp" /></a><font color="#ff3300"><b>Featured</b></font><p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Jaipur: In a jolt to the Vasundhara Raje government, the opposition Congress on Tuesday wrested three Assembly seats of Weir, Nasirabad and Surajgarh from the ruling BJP which could retain only the Kota seat.</span></p>

<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Out of four Assembly seats which went to polls on September 13, BJP managed to win only one, bringing down its strength in the 200-member Rajastahn Assembly to 160 from 163.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">In Nasirabad Assembly constituency, Congress candidate Ramnarayan Gujjar defeated BJP's Sarita Gena by a margin of 386 votes. Ramnarayan got 66,648 votes while BJP's Sarita got 66,262 votes.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Congress regained its old Scheduled caste seat of Weir with its candidate Bhajanlal defeating BJP veteran Gangaram Koli by 25108 votes.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">In Surajgarh Assembly constituency, BJP's former minister Digamber Singh, who shifted from Bharatpur and is said to be Raje loyalist, lost to the Congress candidate.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Congress' Shravan Kumar secured 70527 votes while Singh secured 67257 votes. With the victory in three seats, Congress tally in the Assembly is now 24.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">BJP retained Kota city with party candidate Sandeep Sharma winning the Kota-South Assembly constituency by defeating Congress candidate Shivkant Nandwana by a margin of 25,707 votes. Sharma got 84,233 votes while Shivkant got 58,526 votes.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Twenty-three candidates were in the fray including four each of BJP, and Congress, and one CPI-ML.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The bypolls were necessitated after sitting MLAs Sanwar Lal Jat (Nasirabad), Om Birla (Kota-South), Santosh Ahlawat (Surajgarh) and Bahadur Singh Koli (Weir) resigned from the Assembly following their election to Lok Sabha.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Immediately after the Assembly polls in November last year in Rajasthan, BJP had won all 25 Lok Sabha seats in the state in May this year.</span></p>]]></description>
			<dc:creator>Edited by Kirti Dwivedi | Updated: 3:15 IST</dc:creator>
			<pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2014 09:40:12 -0600</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.newsx.com/regional/other-states/item/26749-rajasthan-congress-wrests-three-assembly-seats-from-bjp</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Court sentences man to 10 years for murder</title>
			<link>http://www.newsx.com/cities/item/26748-court-sentences-man-to-10-years-for-murder</link>
			<description><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/106b7a3bc322be06c21fae08dfda7cf5_Generic.jpg"><img align="right" border="0" src="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/106b7a3bc322be06c21fae08dfda7cf5_S.jpg" alt="court-sentences-man-to-10-years-for-murder" /></a><font color="#ff3300"><b>Featured</b></font><p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">NEW DELHI: A Delhi court has sentenced a 23-year-old youth to 10 years in jail for beating a man, who was in relationship with his mother, to death.</span></p>

<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Additional Sessions Judge Rajesh Kumar Goel held Naveen guilty of killing one Anil Kumar in 2009 and convicted him for the offence of culpable homicide not amounting to murder under section 304 (part 1) of IPC.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The court also convicted his mother, Sunita, for helping him get rid of Kumar's body and sentenced her to three years rigorous imprisonment under section 201 (destruction of evidence) of IPC.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The court made a recommendation to the North District Service Legal Authority to award appropriate compensation to the family members Kumar under the Delhi Victim Compensation Scheme.</span></p>]]></description>
			<dc:creator>Edited by Kirti Dwivedi | Updated: 2:45 IST</dc:creator>
			<pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2014 09:31:07 -0600</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.newsx.com/cities/item/26748-court-sentences-man-to-10-years-for-murder</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>India, China relations go beyond plain arithmetic, says PM Narendra Modi</title>
			<link>http://www.newsx.com/national/nation/item/26747-india-china-relations-go-beyond-plain-arithmetic-says-pm-narendra-modi</link>
			<description><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/a7a32cf2b2b052b8f53e94b16d483955_Generic.jpg"><img align="right" border="0" src="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/a7a32cf2b2b052b8f53e94b16d483955_S.jpg" alt="india-china-relations-go-beyond-plain-arithmetic-says-pm-narendra-modi" /></a><font color="#ff3300"><b>Featured</b></font><p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">New Delhi: A day ahead of Chinese President Xi Jinping's arrival in Gujarat, Prime Minister Narendra Modi on Tuesday hailed the ties shared between India and China.</span></p>

<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">In a conversation with Chinese journalists based in New Delhi, the PM said, “India and China are bound by history, connected by culture, and inspired by rich traditions. Together they can create a bright future for the entire mankind.”</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Modi further summarised the future of possibilities of bilateral ties shared by India and China by saying “Inch (India and China) towards Miles (Millennium of Exceptional Synergy)”.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">He said that every inch we cover can rewrite history of humanity and every mile we cross will go a long way in making this planet a better place.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The PM further hoped that together India and China cover several miles. Several miles that take not only the two nations forward but also all of Asia and humankind towards the path of progress and harmony, Modi added.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Further referring to the large population base of India and China, Modi said that when the two Asian countries gain, almost 35 percent of the world’s population benefits; when India and China strengthen ties, almost 35 percent of the world’s people come closer; when economic cooperation between India and China increases, the lives of almost 35 percent of the world’s population undergoes qualitative changes.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Responding to a question on how he foresees India and China relations developing, the Prime Minister explained that our relations go beyond plain arithmetic.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">“The arithmetic and chemistry of our relations convince me that together we can script history and create a better tomorrow for all of mankind.”</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Prime Minister Narendra Modi will set aside protocol and himself receive Chinese President Xi Jinping when he arrives in Ahmedabad on Wednesday.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Xi will become the first world leader to begin an India visit from Gujarat.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Modi will himself receive Xi on his arrival from Colombo on Wednesday afternoon.</span></p>]]></description>
			<dc:creator>Edited by Kirti Dwivedi | Updated: 2:45 IST</dc:creator>
			<pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2014 09:23:40 -0600</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.newsx.com/national/nation/item/26747-india-china-relations-go-beyond-plain-arithmetic-says-pm-narendra-modi</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Ranbir Kapoor refused to comment on Deepika Padukone’s cleavage controversy?</title>
			<link>http://www.newsx.com/showbiz/most-popular/item/26746-ranbir-kapoor-refused-to-comment-on-deepika-padukones-cleavage-controversy</link>
			<description><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/78671aa50a5bb123af3252f5eb631e57_Generic.jpg"><img align="right" border="0" src="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/78671aa50a5bb123af3252f5eb631e57_S.jpg" alt="ranbir-kapoor-refused-to-comment-on-deepika-padukones-cleavage-controversy" /></a><font color="#ff3300"><b>Featured</b></font><p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">On one hand where maximum people from the tinsel town have come forward to the recent ‘cleavage controversy’ of Deepika Padukone, her former beau actor Ranbir Kapoor has chosen to stay mum on the matter.</span></p>

<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The entire Bollywood fraternity has chosen to stand next to the ‘Finding Fanny’ actress and has rallied against the inappropriate picture of Padukone being used but the ‘Besharam’ actor has opted to stay quiet on the same.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">While most of the people have chosen the micro-blogging site Twitter to express the anger on the controversy and offered massive reactions, a source close to Ranbir Kapoor who is not present on Twitter unlike many other Bollywood celebs has stated that the Kapoor lad does not wish to be a part of the row for now.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">As the source informed, “Ranbir is certain of media questioning him on the matter the next time he steps out and they would not let him off without taking his reaction. But at the same time, he does not wish to comment on the matter for now.”</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Well, it is also to be noted that Ranbir is apparently dating the ‘Boom’ actress Katrina Kaif who is supposedly very much possessive about him. In that case, it is sure that Ranbir should actually keep a distance from making any comment on her former girl’s controversy to keep his present partner at ease.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">“RK is not among those who would want to get involved in anything for publicity or just to get his name out in the papers. He has wisely chosen to distance himself from this,” the source added.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">But yes, at least we are sure that Ranbir will be at one point of time being quizzed on the matter, sooner or later!</span></p>]]></description>
			<dc:creator>Written by Charnamrit Sachdeva</dc:creator>
			<pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2014 09:09:09 -0600</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.newsx.com/showbiz/most-popular/item/26746-ranbir-kapoor-refused-to-comment-on-deepika-padukones-cleavage-controversy</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Narendra Modi wave is over: Arvind Kejriwal on By-poll results</title>
			<link>http://www.newsx.com/national/nation/item/26745-narendra-modi-wave-is-over-arvind-kejriwal-on-by-poll-results</link>
			<description><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/aa8b27dab2239d588bd7dc67b52ea2a0_Generic.jpg"><img align="right" border="0" src="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/aa8b27dab2239d588bd7dc67b52ea2a0_S.jpg" alt="narendra-modi-wave-is-over-arvind-kejriwal-on-by-poll-results" /></a><font color="#ff3300"><b>Featured</b></font><p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">New Delhi: A day ahead of Chinese President Xi Jinping's arrival in Gujarat, Prime Minister Narendra Modi on Tuesday hailed the ties shared between India and China.</span></p>

<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">In a conversation with Chinese journalists based in New Delhi, the PM said, “India and China are bound by history, connected by culture, and inspired by rich traditions. Together they can create a bright future for the entire mankind.”</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Modi further summarised the future of possibilities of bilateral ties shared by India and China by saying “Inch (India and China) towards Miles (Millennium of Exceptional Synergy)”.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">He said that every inch we cover can rewrite history of humanity and every mile we cross will go a long way in making this planet a better place.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The PM further hoped that together India and China cover several miles. Several miles that take not only the two nations forward but also all of Asia and humankind towards the path of progress and harmony, Modi added.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Further referring to the large population base of India and China, Modi said that when the two Asian countries gain, almost 35 percent of the world’s population benefits; when India and China strengthen ties, almost 35 percent of the world’s people come closer; when economic cooperation between India and China increases, the lives of almost 35 percent of the world’s population undergoes qualitative changes.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Responding to a question on how he foresees India and China relations developing, the Prime Minister explained that our relations go beyond plain arithmetic.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">“The arithmetic and chemistry of our relations convince me that together we can script history and create a better tomorrow for all of mankind.”</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Prime Minister Narendra Modi will set aside protocol and himself receive Chinese President Xi Jinping when he arrives in Ahmedabad on Wednesday.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Xi will become the first world leader to begin an India visit from Gujarat.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Modi will himself receive Xi on his arrival from Colombo on Wednesday afternoon.</span></p>]]></description>
			<dc:creator>Edited by Kirti Dwivedi | Updated: 2:25 IST</dc:creator>
			<pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2014 09:03:14 -0600</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.newsx.com/national/nation/item/26745-narendra-modi-wave-is-over-arvind-kejriwal-on-by-poll-results</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>How to become a dexterous driver: Tips for new drivers</title>
			<link>http://www.newsx.com/auto/cars/item/26744-how-to-become-a-dexterous-driver-tips-for-new-drivers</link>
			<description><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/fe8189c76e2d97d6ceca3983b62a08d5_Generic.jpg"><img align="right" border="0" src="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/fe8189c76e2d97d6ceca3983b62a08d5_S.jpg" alt="how-to-become-a-dexterous-driver-tips-for-new-drivers" /></a><font color="#ff3300"><b>Featured</b></font><p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Being a new driver in the city where the streets don’t stop is surely not a piece of an easy cake walk. And why would it be, after all it has a string of aligned responsibilities attached to it, one of which is widely recognized as ‘Parking’!</span></p>

<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Henceforth, we bring all the new drivers out there with some of the very useful day-to-day parking tips.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Let’s talk about <strong>Parallel Parking</strong>.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">• Uncomfortable with your angle of approach? Don’t force it, just pull back out and start over.</span><br /><span style="font-size: 10pt;">• Leave the car in front of you with space to get out of their spot while parking.</span><br /><span style="font-size: 10pt;">• Make sure that your foot is always near the brake pedal.</span><br /><span style="font-size: 10pt;">• When you are behind a car which is signalling to Parallel Parking, either pass right away or give them enough space to move.</span><br /><span style="font-size: 10pt;">• Strive to find a space which is at least six feet longer than your car.</span><br /><span style="font-size: 10pt;">• Even before you pull in, make sure to flash the brake rights and put on the turn signal.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Follow the steps to master the <strong>‘S’ Method</strong>.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">• If you want to park behind another car, pull up three feet away and turn on your indicator.</span><br /><span style="font-size: 10pt;">• Put your car into reverse and turn your wheels all the way to the right.</span><br /><span style="font-size: 10pt;">• Back up until you make a 45-degree angle very slowly and stop. Turn the wheels to the left.</span><br /><span style="font-size: 10pt;">• Back up until you are parallel with the curb.</span><br /><span style="font-size: 10pt;">• Make sure that you are less then twelve inches from the curb.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Exiting a Parallel Parking Space</span></strong></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">• Back up straight, as far as possible.</span><br /><span style="font-size: 10pt;">• Turn the wheels to the left.</span><br /><span style="font-size: 10pt;">• Turn on the indicator.</span><br /><span style="font-size: 10pt;">• Keep a check on the traffic.</span><br /><span style="font-size: 10pt;">• Give the vehicle on your right enough space to maintain a distance from the car in front of you.</span><br /><span style="font-size: 10pt;">• Turn the wheels slowly to the right.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Why should Parking Lots and Garages be left behind?</span></strong></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Are you new in the game of driving? Do you go for shopping, work, movies or college? Too bad because you need to park in a lot!</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">• Park your car in the centre.</span><br /><span style="font-size: 10pt;">• Be aware of ‘one way’ instructions on the ground or on signs.</span><br /><span style="font-size: 10pt;">• Watch out for speed and people especially small children in the parking lot.</span><br /><span style="font-size: 10pt;">• Try not to park at the end of an aisle, where other cars are making lots of turns.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Parking on a Hill</span></strong></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">As they wisely say that troubles are never foretold. Injuries can happen anywhere, especially when the emergency brakes fail. That is why it is important to know how to park on a hill.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">• Make sure to park close to the, and always use your emergency brake.</span><br /><span style="font-size: 10pt;">• When parking UPWARDS on a hill, turn your front wheels to the LEFT.</span><br /><span style="font-size: 10pt;">• When parking DOWNWARDS on a hill, turn your front wheels to the RIGHT.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong><span style="font-size: 10pt;">“Rewind the story between the two of us...oops, I mean REVERSE!”</span></strong></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Parking in Reverse is one of the safest ways to avoid accidents caused by backing out of spaces into blind traffic and chances of the cars to break.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Flash those lights on these steps.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">• Turn on the indicator. Pull over at the nearest space and wait for the cars behind you to pass.</span><br /><span style="font-size: 10pt;">• Pull your car in the centre of both the lanes and keep your indicators on.</span><br /><span style="font-size: 10pt;">• Put the car in reverse and turn the wheel towards the side that the parking space is on. Remember to look back while driving backwards.</span><br /><span style="font-size: 10pt;">• Straighten the wheel out as you go back.</span><br /><span style="font-size: 10pt;">• Don’t forget to check the mirrors.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Good Luck, beginners!</span></p>]]></description>
			<dc:creator>Written by Ayushree Nandan</dc:creator>
			<pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2014 08:31:10 -0600</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.newsx.com/auto/cars/item/26744-how-to-become-a-dexterous-driver-tips-for-new-drivers</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Grateful to people of UP for rejecting BJP, voting for SP: Akhilesh Yadav</title>
			<link>http://www.newsx.com/regional/up/item/26743-grateful-to-people-of-up-for-rejecting-bjp-voting-for-sp-akhilesh-yadav</link>
			<description><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/123babc225f04f797bf02454be3fb70d_Generic.jpg"><img align="right" border="0" src="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/123babc225f04f797bf02454be3fb70d_S.jpg" alt="grateful-to-people-of-up-for-rejecting-bjp-voting-for-sp-akhilesh-yadav" /></a><font color="#ff3300"><b>Featured</b></font><p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Lucknow: Uttar Pradesh Chief Minister Akhilesh Yadav on Tuesday said that he was thankful to the people of his state for rejecting Bharatiya Janata Party's (BJP) communal policies and for voting in favour of the ideology of the Samajwadi Party.</span></p>

<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"The complete results aren't out yet, but after looking at the bypoll trends, I would like to thank the people of Uttar Pradesh for voting for Samajwadi Party's ideology and policies. I am happy that communal elements have been rejected by them," said Yadav.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"I am grateful to them for not voting in favour of people who tried to divide the state and generate communal tensions. The people have voted thoughtfully against such powers who were trying to divide the society. Since the beginning, our party has tried to take the state on the path of development and harmony and I assure you that if we win, we will try our best to bring optimal development in UP," he added.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Expressing gratitude towards people of Uttar Pradesh, Samajwadi Party leader Gaurav Bhatia said that the bypoll trends reflect the acceptance of the party's policies.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"I would like to thank the people of Uttar Pradesh, who have helped us win. It is a win for both Mulayam Singh and Akhilesh Yadav. I would also like to thank the workers of SP, who have worked really hard for the party. The results show that the policies of SP have been well-accepted by the public," said Bhatia.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">In Uttar Pradesh, the ruling Samajwadi Party is leading at six out of 11 Assembly seats as well as the Mainpuri Lok Sabha seat.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The results of bypolls for three Lok Sabha and 33 Assembly constituencies spread across ten states, where the bypolls were held on September 13, were announced earlier today.</span></p>]]></description>
			<dc:creator>Edited by Kirti Dwivedi | Updated: 1:45 IST</dc:creator>
			<pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2014 08:04:04 -0600</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.newsx.com/regional/up/item/26743-grateful-to-people-of-up-for-rejecting-bjp-voting-for-sp-akhilesh-yadav</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Google to make YouTube videos available offline soon in India</title>
			<link>http://www.newsx.com/gadgets/others/item/26742-google-to-make-youtube-videos-available-offline-soon-in-india</link>
			<description><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/3a2178c0624d9aec3d0adf2c9238fd4b_Generic.jpg"><img align="right" border="0" src="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/3a2178c0624d9aec3d0adf2c9238fd4b_S.jpg" alt="google-to-make-youtube-videos-available-offline-soon-in-india" /></a><font color="#ff3300"><b>Featured</b></font><p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">New Delhi: After Android One, India will have another first from Google as the tech giant plans to make YouTube available offline, allowing people to save on download charges for watching their favourite videos.</span></p>

<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">In the coming weeks, once the service is available offline, viewers can download the video, save it and watch it later without downloading it again and in turn, save on recurring data download charges.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"YouTube is popular here. You watch some videos again and again. How awesome would it be if you could keep watching them again and again without having to pay for data, and take the videos with you wherever you go?" Google Vice President Product Management Ceasar Sengupta said.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">He added that in the next few weeks, YouTube will be available offline in India.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">As of now, the service is not available in any other country.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"You can download a video once, save it to your phone, and watch it again and again," he said.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">According to industry reports, the online video consumption is pegged at over 3.7 billion videos per month in the country.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">According to comscore, the total online video audience in India saw growth of over 70 per cent in 2013 with the average viewer watching 18 per cent more videos and spending 28 per cent more time viewing.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Video consumption on mobile phones has also been growing steadily in the country.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">YouTube alone gets over 60 million unique users a month and about one-third of the traffic coming from mobile phones.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">India is the first country where Google has launched its Android One smartphones, in partnership with handset makers Micromax, Karbonn and Spice. Other countries like Indonesia, Bangladesh and Philippines will follow in the coming months.</span></p>]]></description>
			<dc:creator>Edited by Priyanka Kukreja || Updated: 12:10 IST</dc:creator>
			<pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2014 06:35:34 -0600</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.newsx.com/gadgets/others/item/26742-google-to-make-youtube-videos-available-offline-soon-in-india</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Ruling TDP wins Nandigama Assembly bypoll in AP</title>
			<link>http://www.newsx.com/regional/andhra-pradesh/item/26741-ruling-tdp-wins-nandigama-assembly-bypoll-in-ap</link>
			<description><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/aadc8bf91c198e677af7232f6592c8ba_Generic.jpg"><img align="right" border="0" src="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/aadc8bf91c198e677af7232f6592c8ba_S.jpg" alt="ruling-tdp-wins-nandigama-assembly-bypoll-in-ap" /></a><font color="#ff3300"><b>Featured</b></font><p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Giving the ruling party a boost, Telugu Desam Party's Tangirala Sowmya today won the Nandigama Assembly bypoll in Andhra Pradesh by 74,827 votes.</span></p>

<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Riding on the sympathy wave, Sowmya, a software engineer, got 99,748 votes, pushing her Congress rival Bodapati Babu Rao to a distant second with 24,921 votes in a straight contest in Krishna district.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The main opposition YSR Congress Party had not fielded candidate after TDP requested other parties to make the election unanimous.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">The by-election was necessitated following the vacancy caused by the death of Sowmya's father due to a cardiac arrest days after he was elected in the May polls.</span></p>]]></description>
			<dc:creator>Edited by Priyanka Kukreja || Updated: 12:00 IST</dc:creator>
			<pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2014 06:21:54 -0600</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.newsx.com/regional/andhra-pradesh/item/26741-ruling-tdp-wins-nandigama-assembly-bypoll-in-ap</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>E-rickshaw ban: Arvind Kejriwal to meet Nitin Gadkari on Tuesday</title>
			<link>http://www.newsx.com/cities/item/26740-e-rickshaw-ban-arvind-kejriwal-to-meet-nitin-gadkari-on-tuesday</link>
			<description><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/496eb3aef1bc673162317e90aaa87a81_Generic.jpg"><img align="right" border="0" src="http://www.newsx.com/media/k2/items/cache/496eb3aef1bc673162317e90aaa87a81_S.jpg" alt="e-rickshaw-ban-arvind-kejriwal-to-meet-nitin-gadkari-on-tuesday" /></a><font color="#ff3300"><b>Featured</b></font><p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">New Delhi: Aam Aadmi Party (AAP) leader Arvind Kejriwal will meet Union Transport Minister Nitin Gadkari on Tuesday on the issue of the ban on e-rickshaws in the national capital.</span></p>

<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"Kejriwal will tomorrow meet Gadkari along with a delegation of e-rickshaw drivers and raise the issue of the ban," said an AAP spokesperson.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"E-rickshaws were banned in Delhi due to the government's inaction. Gadkari misled the e-rickshaw drivers on June 17 at Ramlila Maidan by saying he would come up with a policy on it in a month, but nothing has been done.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;">"I have sought an appointment with Gadkari, who is the minister in charge," Kejriwal said.</span></p>]]></description>
			<dc:creator>Edited by Priyanka Kukreja || Updated: 11:10 IST</dc:creator>
			<pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2014 05:43:47 -0600</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.newsx.com/cities/item/26740-e-rickshaw-ban-arvind-kejriwal-to-meet-nitin-gadkari-on-tuesday</guid>
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
